<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Greybard's Corner]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Greybard's Corner</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:44:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:44:06 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Determine Equipment Category]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>GM chooses a modifier from 0-7 based on a range of desired outcomes. This modifier is added to the d6 result to determine the final material.<br><br><br>GM chooses a modifier from 0-4 based on a range of desired outcomes. This modifier is added to the d6 result to determine the final material.<br>]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/my-homebrew/randomized-equipment/1-generate-base-equipment.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/My Homebrew/Randomized Equipment/1 - Generate Base Equipment.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:05:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Determine Enchantment Type]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Weapons<br><br><br><br><br><br>Alteration<br><br>Conjuration<br><br>Destruction<br>
Illusion<br>
Mysticism<br>
Necromancy<br>
Restoration]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/my-homebrew/randomized-equipment/2-generate-enchantment.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/My Homebrew/Randomized Equipment/2 - Generate Enchantment.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 04:53:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Project Collaboration]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>I'm in the process of moving some things around to try some things out.<br><br><a data-href="UESRPG 3e v4" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/uesrpg-3e-v4.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG 3e v4</a>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:42:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 - v2 Errata Merge Changelog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Added Drain [Type] Spell

<br>Stormrider57 wrote flavor text


<br>Added Drain (*) Spell Effect
<br>Added Cure Disease (Self) Spell

<br>Stormrider57 wrote flavor text


<br>Added Curing Touch spell

<br>Stormrider57 wrote flavor text


<br>Added Cure Disease Spell Effect
<br>Added Bleeding Condition
<br>Added the Magic Damage Type

<br>Added an entry for the "Magic" Sub-type to the Magic Damage Types.
<br>Changed the sentence which reads

if the wound is from frost or poison damage, the character also loses a Stamina point.

  to read:

If the wound is from magic, frost, or poison damage, the character also loses a Stamina point.




<br>Added “Follow-up strike” Talent
<br>Added "Resolving opposing spell effects" to pg. 82
<br>Changed bound trait on pg.58. Reworded the errata's text from:

This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together by magic.&nbsp;It must obey the commands of their master unless it is to defend themselves. Items with this trait use their creators willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test, and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.

  to:

This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together, by magic. They obey the commands of their master except if they must defend themselves. Items with this trait use their creator’s willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test, and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.


<br>Changed to the errata Summoned trait on pg. 59
<br>Changed the flavor text for master alchemist
<br>Added rules for Holding Breath to pg 69
<br>Added rules for item durability (pending removal) to page 70

<br>We should be looking at the v3 advantage for applying damage to items as a potential substitute for this. If it’s used, take away the crushing weapon qualifier


<br>Added additional commerce rules to pg. 110 (everything from “Location Modifiers” to “Appraising an Item” from the errata)
<br>Added the Monster Hunter talent to the Weaponry Talents section

<br>Stormrider57 wrote flavor text


<br>Changed Power Attack stamina usage to use the errata rules
<br>Changed Killing Blow Talent to use the errata rules
<br>Corrected the soul gem pricing in the enchanting section to match that of the Equipment chapter
<br>Granted the parrying dagger the Slashing(3) quality
<br>Added the underlined sentence below to the Moonshadow power:

The character possesses a simple form of innate shadow magic. This power may be activated once a day with the use of the Cast Magic action. The character becomes Invisible for 18 seconds (3 rounds). The character may spend a Luck point, or burn one Luck, to extend this duration by one round (this may be done as many times as the character desires). This invisibility is broken if the character makes an attack, after which it reforms at the beginning of the next round as long as there is 1 round of duration left. This power may only be used once until after the character’s next long rest.


<br>Added the underlined verbiage below to the paragraph that introduces the concept of Target Numbers in Chapter 1:

You make tests by making a percentile roll and comparing the result to a Target Number; often referred to as TN, and typically a value between 1 and 99. If the roll is less than or equal to the target number, the character succeeds. If the roll is higher than the target number, they fail.


<br>Added the underlined verbiage below to the “Learning Effects and Forms” text in chapter 6:

A character may attempt to create a constant enchantment using any effect from any school as long as that effect has the Upkeep Attribute and a listed duration. It is not dependent on their knowledge of any spells.


<br>Specified that using cast enchantments uses a Primary Action in “The Basics” portion of the Cast Enchantments section.
<br>Changed Executioner Talent to read:

The character increases the bonus from All Out Attacks to +30, and adds 1d4 to his Strength bonus for the purpose of the Splitting/Slashing quality when All Out Attacking with great axes and scimitars. Additionally, this character’s foes suffer a -20 penalty to Shock tests made because of wounds inflicted by greataxes and scimitars.


<br>Removed the text “-20 to Evade ranged attacks” from the Unnaturally Agile talent
<br>Replaced the rules for “Red Legion Throw” with the following:

When a character throws a Javelin and successfully causes damage to the target (after mitigation), the target location (either a limb or the body) is Speared. A Speared hit location is treated as crippled until the Javelin is removed, either as a Free action inflicting the Bleeding (1d4 + javelin material modifier) condition, or as a Secondary action requiring a strength test, which if successful removes the spear without causing further harm.  
If the Javelin is blocked instead the shield is Speared. A speared shield requires the wielder spend one Stamina point in order to even attempt to block with the added weight of the javelin. Removing the javelin from the shield requires the character to make a Strength test as a secondary action.  


<br>Added the sentence underlined below to the Falling Section in chapter 5:

Falling even a relatively short distance can be quite dangerous if a character is unlucky. Falling inflicts 1d10+[meters fallen beyond 2] damage to the body. This damage ignores armor. If a character is in control of their body when falling (not tied / paralyzed / unconscious / surprised etc.), they ignore fall damage for any distance less than 3 meters.


<br>Replaced Massive size mention with Enormous
<br>Modified “Talent Levels” section to read as below:

Each talent has an associated Talent Level. Talents of higher levels have more powerful effects, as they represent more powerful abilities that are more difficult to acquire. The level of the talent determines the XP cost of that talent. The level also determines a talent’s characteristic requirements. A character must meet the base characteristic score requirement (unmodified by external effects) of at least one of the talent’s governing characteristics before he can purchase it. Some talents have additional requirements, which will be listed with those talents.


<br>Added a section to “Creating Poisons” called “Toxins”, with the following text:

Creating a poison with a non-damaging effects does not follow the rules for normal poisons, but are rather brewn like a normal potion; except only the spell-effects with the [Toxin] tag can be used when brewing the poison in question.<br>
However, these more complicated compounds lose their bite much quicker than their simpler counterparts when applied to weapons, lasting for 1 minute (10 rounds) or 3 successful hits with the weapon/ammo, whichever comes first.<br>
Characters that take damage from a poisoned weapon with a non-damaging effect must make a test as specified by the effect in question to resist, but replaces any listed characteristic with Endurance.  


<br>Added the toxin attribute to the following spell effects:

<br>Burden
<br>Drain Magicka
<br>Fatigue
<br>Blind
<br>Calm
<br>Frenzy
<br>Paralyze
<br>Silence


<br>Copied the rules for effect durations from the combat chapter to the spellcasting chapter (replacing the incorrect rules there)
<br>Changed the alchemical ingredient prices in the equipment chapter to that of the prices in the spellcasting chapter (potions section)
<br>To specify that Throwing Stars/Darts use melee weapon materials, added a section called “Thrown Ranged Weapons” to the ranged weapons section:

Ranged weapons with the Thrown quality count as melee weapons for the purposes of determining weapon material.


<br>Added the underlined statement below to the Quick Draw Talent:

Additionally, the character can choose to either reduce the AP cost of drinking a potion to 1 or drink a potion without provoking Attacks of Opportunity.


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/1-v2-errata-merge-changelog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/1 - v2 Errata Merge Changelog.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:52:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2 - Black Book Merge Changelog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Added the emphasized text below to the Beast Tongue racial trait:

Bosmer can speak to, and understand the speech of, animals. How exactly this functions is left to the GM’s discretion, though it is recommended the GM call for a Perception test when the Bosmer encounters the speech of an unfamiliar animal to determine if they can understand it and communicate back. Additionally, the character receives a +20 bonus to any Profession [Animal Trainer] skill tests they make.


<br>Changed the Bound Trait to read the following:

This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together by magic. They must obey the commands of their master, except they will always prioritize defending themselves. Additionally, if attacked by their master for any reason, they turn hostile and lose the bound trait. Items with this trait use their creators Willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test (Except Combat Style), and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.


<br>Changed the Stunted Magicka trait to read:

Characters with this trait do not regenerate magicka naturally, and halve the benefits gained from Spell Restraint.


<br>Changed the Summoned trait to read:

This creature or item has been conjured from another plane of existence. Upon its death or destruction, it returns to where it came from immediately.


<br>Damaged(X) changes:

<br>Changed the Damaged(X) weapon quality to the following, removing the struck out text for brevity, and adding the emphasized text from the BB:

Weapons with this quality are damaged. They deal X less damage. If this would ever render a character incapable of dealing damage with the weapon, even with the maximum possible roll, then the weapon is destroyed. Natural Weapons cannot receive this Quality. All instances of this quality stack.


<br>Changed the Damaged(X) Armor Quality to the following, removing the struck out text for brevity, and adding the emphasized text:

~~A piece of Armor or a shield with this quality has been damaged.<br>
Reduce its AR or BR by X.<br>
~~A piece of Armor or a shield with this quality has its AR or BR reduced by X. If this would reduce that value to 0, then the item is destroyed. Natural Armor cannot receive this Quality. All instances of this quality stack.


<br>Changed the Frenzied condition’s first bullet point to read:

Must attempt to attack the nearest person or creature in melee combat each turn if able, using only All Out Attacks.


<br>Changed the Berserker Talent to read:

The character may take a primary action to gain the Frenzied condition. They only attack enemies as long as the condition was entered voluntarily.


<br>Changed the Controlled Anger Talent to read:

The character may remove the Frenzied condition as a free action. They can also roll a +0 Willpower test to take control of any involuntarily applied Frenzied condition.




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/2-black-book-merge-changelog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/2 - Black Book Merge Changelog.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:52:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 - v3 Merge Changelog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Added a section to the end of the Critical Successes &amp; Failures section in chapter one that reads:

Creatures and NPCs do not have Luck like a Player Character does; however, they still have the capacity to critically succeed or fail.<br>
On a roll of 1-3, the roll is considered a Critical Failure.<br>
On a roll of 98-100, the roll is considered a Critical Success.  


<br>Alternate Wounds

<br>Added an optional rule blurb to the end of the Wounds section in Chapter 5:

Optional Rule: Alternate Wounds<br>
If your group prefers less bookkeeping and a more forgiving experience, you can use this rule instead of the standard rules for Wounds:<br>
Instead of a character taking a Wound when they take damage in excess of their WT, they take a wound if they ever take damage from a critical success on an attack or if an attack reduces them to 0 Hit Points.  


<br>Added an optional rule note to Step 4 in the Attacking &amp; Defending section in Chapter 5:

Optional Rule Note: Alternate Wounds<br>
If you’re using the rules for Alternate Wounds found in Physical Health later in this chapter, then the attack instead causes a Wound if it brings the target to 0 HP or if the attack is a Critical Success and causes the target to take Damage.  


<br>Added an optional rule note after the Wound Threshold Attribute in Chapter 1:

Optional Rule Note: Alternate Wounds<br>
If you’re using the rules for Alternate Wounds found in Physical Health later in Chapter 5, then your character will not have a Wound Threshold Attribute.  




<br>Added the Linguistics attribute to Chapter 1 &gt; Attributes and Chapter 2 &gt; Finishing Touches. Changed the v3 formula (IB / 2) to IB - 2 or 4, whichever is lower.

A character’s Linguistics is equal to their Intelligence bonus minus two to a maximum of four and reflects the maximum number languages that they can start with at character creation. Every character starts with Cyrodilic, which is the common tongue around Tamriel and doesn’t count as one of the languages known from this attribute. One Exotic language counts as 2 languages known. Players should check in with their GM if they choose from the list of Exotic Languages. Additionally, GMs may expand this list of languages to fit the setting.


<br>Added the Breton | Bretic race language
<br>Added the following Exotic Languages:

<br>Ehlnofey | Ehlnofex
<br>Akavir | Akaviri
<br>Reachfolk | Reach-tongue




<br>Changed Power Attack in the Spending Stamina Section of Ch 1 to read

Add an amount of damage to a melee or ranged attack equal to twice the stamina points spent, to a maximum of 3 for +6 damage.


<br>Added a Skill Level Maximum section to Spend CrP &amp; Purchase Items:

Depending on however much Crp or total Exp your character has, they can only purchase a certain amount of Ranks in any skill. These are the appropriate skill rank maximums that a character can have in relation to their Crp/ total Exp:


<br>Skill Rank Maximums to Total XP

<br>Apprentice - 1000
<br>Journey - 2500
<br>Adept - 4000
<br>Expert - 5500
<br>Master - 7000




<br>Added Learning a Ritual - 25 CrP to Spend CrP &amp; Purchase Items &gt; Character Advancement CrP Costs
<br>Modified Ancestor Guardian to persist “until 30 minutes passes, or until the end of a Combat Encounter that it participates in; whichever comes first”
<br>Moved the Combat Style section to the end of the Skill Chapter
<br>Changed the text of the Combat Senses talent to read:

The character can choose to calculate their Initiative Rating by taking twice their Perception Bonus and adding two instead of the usual formula.


<br>Added an optional rule for Turn-Based AP Refreshing:

Optional Rule: Turn-Based AP Refreshing<br>
For an alternative strategic experience, your group can choose to play with this variant AP Refreshing ruleset.<br>
As combat starts, all characters start the first round with Maximum AP. Then, in all subsequent rounds, characters replenish their AP at the start of their turn.  


<br>Added the Assassinate talent:

Assassinate<br>
The character takes advantage of stealth to set a deadly strike.<br>
Apprentice (Agility)<br>
Requires Sneak Attack<br>
The character can cause only the damage from Sneak Attack to ignore any AR of the hit location they are hitting if they are attacking with a one-handed weapon that has the Exploit Weakness Weapon Quality.  


<br>Changed the Rank for Sneak Attack to Apprentice
<br>Changed the Rank for Shadow Strike to Expert
<br>Changed the text for Shadow Strike:

If the character makes an attack while hidden (melee attacks<br>
made this way must kill the target in order to benefit)then they can attempt a Stealth test opposed by the Observe of any enemies who would reasonably be able to notice the attack. On success, or if they roll more degrees of success, they remain hidden from those enemies. If the attack is a melee attack, then the character must forgo the advantage gained from the hidden condition to benefit from this talent.


<br>Changed Perfect Hit talent from

Master (Perception): The character adds their Perception bonus to the damage dealt by Precision Strike attacks (either melee or ranged).”

  to:

Expert (Perception): The character can use their Perception Bonus for the purposes of determining Splitting, Slashing, or Crushing damage in place of their Strength bonus.


<br>Changed Master Alchemist to increase strength by 20% instead of 10% (which stacks to 30% with Alchemist [School]).
<br>Changed the text of the Grandmaster talent, adding benefits for spellcasting skills

The character may reroll failed skill tests for that skill (but only once for a given test). This talent can be purchased multiple times for different skills. Does not stack with other talents that would allow rerolls. If this talent is taken with a spellcasting skill, then it increases the +1 bonus to effective skill rank to a +2. Which allows for the casting of Grandmaster spells. without penalty.


<br>Reduced the Interrogator talent level from Journeyman to Apprentice
<br>Reduced the Unnaturally Agile talent from Master to Expert
<br>Added a restriction to the Stubborn talent to only allow rerolls once per test
<br>Added a restriction to the Fearless talent to only allow rerolls once per test
<br>Reduce Fearless talent level to Expert
<br>Changed the Wall of Steel talent

The Character increases the AR and BR of any armor and shields worn by +1. Additionally, the character ignores the speed penalty from any armor worn.


<br>Reduced the Depth of understanding talent level to Expert and modfied it to grant the Power Well (IB x 5) Trait.
<br>Removed Force of Will, and used it’s text to replace Magicka Cycling’s, but made it improve by 2
<br>Modified Master of Magicka’s Prerequisite talents to Include Depth of Understanding OR Magicka Cycling.
<br>Removed the restriction against taking Depth of Understanding if you’ve taken force of will.
<br>Modified Bearded Warrior talent - rather than moving 1m closer, they can yank the target 1m in any direction that doesn’t cause their distance from them to increase.
<br>Removed the +10 bonus to persuade granted by the Beast of Steel talent.
<br>Changed Bruiser talent to read:

The character increases their damage with thrown axes by their Strength bonus. This replaces the Agility bonus added by Dart Thrower, if chosen. Making throwing attacks with hand axes does not provoke attacks of opportunity, and thrown axes can be retrieved as a free action if the character is able to move to where the axe landed. Drawing hand axes does not provoke attacks of opportunity. Additionally, maces the character wields gain the Concussive quality and their All Out Attacks cause the target to lose one stamina if the target takes damage from the attack after mitigation.


<br>Changed the Firing Line to read:

Any ranged attack the character makes with a Crossbow or Arbalest adds the Splitting Quality with a value equal to twice the number of Aim Actions made before the shot.<br>
Additionally, if they have a tower shield, it can be set up as a secondary action and used as cover. While behind the shield, the character can take a single aim action as a free action if they do not move or reload during that turn.  


<br>Changed the Halberdier talent:
<br>

The character becomes more effective with their halberds, and can use them to knock opponents off of their mounts.<br>
Expert (Strength)<br>
The character can choose to replace their halberd’s Splitting quality with the Crushing quality. Halberds the character wields range becomes 3m. Additionally, The character can spend 1SP to force the rider of a mount to make and succeed a Ride test or fall off of their mount, landing prone.  


<br>Changed the Hammerblow talent to read:

When the character lands a hit with a warhammer or maul they can choose to either cause their target to lose one Stamina Point, or make an all-out-attack to force the target to make an Endurance (+0) test. If the target fails this test, they gain the Dazed condition. The target may attempt one Endurance (+10) test on his first turn each round to remove the condition.


<br>Added The following to the Knife Fighter talent:

When the character uses the Penetrate Armor Advantage, they can add 1d4 to their damage roll.


<br>Added support for Alternate Wounds with the Monster Hunter talent:

Optional Rule Note: Alternate Wounds<br>
If your group is using the alternate rules for Wounds defined in the Physical Health section in Chapter 5, simply disregard the interaction with Wound Threshold in the Monster Hunter talent.  


<br>Changed the Viper’s Eye talent to read:

Spears the character wields gain Slashing. Additionally, Precision Strikes with a spear replaces Slashing with Crushing, and are only made at a -10 penalty. When wielding a spear in two hands it loses Unwieldy and its range is simply 3m.


<br>Changed the Point Blank talent to read:

When using a shortbow, the character never provokes attacks of opportunity when using it to make attacks within melee range of an enemy, and can use the weapon to attempt to parry attacks. Shortbows the character wields gain Exploit Weakness. Additionally, the character can gain an advantage by normal means when using a shortbow against a target within the target’s melee range.


<br>Added “once per test” to the end of Simple, Yet Effective talent.
<br>Modified the Staff Mastery talent to not reduce the penalty for precision strikes.
<br>Added the Bleeding (X) trait
<br>Added the following to the Telekinesis trait:

The character can also throw an object ast an opponent. This is a Primary Action and a Ranged Attack, and uses Mysticism (Willpower) for the test. Any object used in this manner counts as an improvised weapon, and can only be thrown a distance of WpB * 2 meters.


<br>Removed the rules section for Item Durability which was added from the v2 errata. The idea is that forceful impact is a simpler way to implement item durability for armor and weapons
<br>Added “For unarmed Coup de Grâce, refer to the Grappling rules.” to the Coup de Grace rule under Primary Actions
<br>Added the ability to use the Aim secondary action for spellcasting, but only for spells with the “Bolt” form.
<br>Added “Any character may use a reaction to an Attack of Opportunity without interrupting their current action, but they must be able to see their target.” to the Attack of Opportunity description
<br>Combined Block, Parry, and Evade into a single section which reads: “The character tries to defend against an incoming ranged or melee attack. See the Attacking &amp; Defending section for details.”
<br>Merged the Disarm and Take Weapon actions, but just called it “Disarm”.

Character makes an Athletics or unarmed Combat Style test which his opponent may oppose with his unarmed Combat Style or Athletics skill. If the target of the disarm attempt loses, the character may choose to either take the target’s weapon or fling the target’s weapon 1d4 meters in a random direction. The character must have a free hand in order to take the target’s weapon. Target cannot be of larger size and must be within 2 meters. Cannot disarm natural weapons.


<br>Added the blinded condition as a removable condition with the Resist action.
<br>Added the Feint special action:

Primary Action<br>
A character attempts a Combat Style test against an opponent’s Observe or Combat Style within a 2m range. If successful, they treat their next melee attack against the target as if they were Hidden. This effect only applies if the attack occurs before the end of the character’s next turn.  


<br>Added the Cast Magic Attacks option to the Attack step under Attacking and Defending:

The attacking caster makes a skill test with the skill corresponding to the school of the spell.


<br>Added a clarification to the Counter-Attack option in Attacking and Defending Step 3: “If both characters achieve the same degrees of success, then neither the Attack nor the Counter-Attack resolve.”
<br>Added the Forceful Impact Advantage:

The character can apply the Damaged(1) quality to any armor on the hit location. This may only be done if the weapon the character is using has the Crushing quality.


<br>In the “Death” section, changed “pass an Endurance test each round” to “pass an Endurance test at the end of each of their turns”.
<br>Changed the section name “Shock Test” to “Shock Effects”, as the section deals with the effects of shock, and there are effects even if the test is succeeded.
<br>Added the following to the end of Treating Wounds: “Treating a wound related to the Crippled Condition can only be done once per long rest. If this test results in a dramatic failure, the limb immediately becomes Maimed.”
<br>Changed Fatigue to apply when a character goes below 1 level of fatigue, rather than when the reach zero.

<br>Changed the last sentence of the first paragraph of Spending Stamina (ch1) to read:

When characters goes below zero SP they gain a level of fatigue.


<br>Changed the “Fatigued” section’s first paragraphin ch. 5 to read:

When a chracter gains a level of fatigue, they acquire the Fatigued condition. If they gain additional levels of fatigue, the effects worsen. Fatigue is most typically gained when a character falls below 0 SP, or spends/loses SP when they are at 0.


<br>Stamina Points (Endurance Bonus) under “Attributes”:

When characters fall below zero SP they gain a level of the fatigue condition.




<br>Added an optional rule note for the Frenzied condition:

If you’re using the rules for Alternate Wounds, disregard the WT increase in this bullet point.


<br>Added an optional rule note for Alternate Wounds to Organ Damage:

If you’re using the rules for Alternate Wounds; instead of reducing WT by 1, increase the passive wound penalty to all tests to -30.


<br>Specified that ““Snapping out” of the fear always happens at the end of their turn.” in the Fear Effects section.
<br>Fixed Inspire Heroism to read:

Once per round as a free action, the character can make a command test to inspire an ally who can perceive them. When inspired, the ally gains +10 to their next combat test.


<br>Added Orcish to the racial languages
<br>In step 2: Casting Test in Casting Spells, added the concept of a character’s Spellcasting Level:

This test suffers a -10 penalty for each point by which the spell level exceeds the character’s Spellcasting Level in that skill. The Spellcasting Level is determined by taking the spell’s school skill level and adding one. If the character is untrained in that school’s skill, the Spellcasting Level in that school is considered zero and they cannot cast the spell.


<br>R/M Attack have been split into their own listings under Spell Attributes. Also specified that M Attacks don’t provoke attacks of opportunity.
<br>Added Mindlock (X): Reduces the caster’s max AP by X to a minimum of zero.
<br>Removed the Reaction Attribute
<br>Added the following Talents:

<br>Mage Guard<br>
The character is able to channel excess magicka to harden their defensive spells.<br>
Journeyman (Willpower)<br>
The character can add a +1 bonus to the effect of a spell they cast with the Defensive Overload attribute. They must not restrain the spell during casting to gain this benefit.<br>

<br>Arcane Defender<br>
The character has mastered their magical defensive abilities and is able to use excess magicka more effectively when on the defensive.<br>
Master (Willpower)<br>
Requires Arcane Defender<br>
The character increases the bonus gained from the Mage Guard Talent from 1 to WB/2 (round up).<br>



<br>Added the “Defensive Overload” spell attribute:

By default, spells with the Defensive Overload attribute have no extra effects. When a character takes the Mage Guard and later, the Arcane Defender talents, they benefit from a a bonus to the spell effect if not restraining the spell.


<br>Added the Defensive Overload Attribute to: Armor, Magic Armor, Magic Shield, Shield, [Type] Armor, [Type] Shield, and Ward
<br>Modified Costs for Burden, Feather, Jump, levitate, Lock, Magic Armor, Open, Repair, Shield, Slowfall, [Type] Armor, [Type] Shield, Water Breathing, Water Walking, Ward
<br>Changed both Ward spells to read

May be cast as a reaction to an attack in place of the character’s normal defense, and does not provoke Attacks of Opportunity. Caster generates a magical ward that acts as a shield for all damage, gaining [Spell Strength] Magical and Physical BR. Power Block is incompatible with this shield.


<br>Renamed the Shield family of spells and effects to better match the mechanics

<br>Shield/Physical Shield becomes Stoneflesh
<br>Magic Shield becomes Ebonyflesh
<br>[Type] Shield becomes [Type]flesh
<br>Elemental Shield spell effect becomes Elemental Flesh


<br>Modify base cost of the newly named flesh family of spells, and change the conventional Spell Form to “Target”:

<br>Stoneflesh and Ebonyflesh reduced to 2 x SL
<br>Elemental Flesh reduced to 1 x SL
<br>Modified the spells to read “Target character within 50m of caster” rather than “Caster”
<br>Modified costs of the conventional spells to match this formula and spell form


<br>Added all Conjuration spells from the Scroll of Oblivion
<br>Added all Conjuration talents from the Scroll of Oblivion
<br>Fixed Thought Caster by adding Spell Sword talent as a prerequisite
<br>Changed hunger spell strength in Summon Daedra spell from 2 to 1
<br>Added Direct tag to Sunder Binding spell
<br>Changed Sunder Binding description to read:

The caster picks a target within 50m that has the Summoned<br>
trait. Target must make an opposed Willpower Test vs the caster<br>
with a [Spell Strength] modifier or be sent back to the place<br>
from whence it came.  


<br>Change chain lighning from direct to R Attack (50m)
<br>Changed Drain [Type] to Direct Attack
<br>Updated various Destruction spells to match spell effect/form cost changes
<br>Changed Blind from Direct to Direct Attack
<br>Added a note to Calm: “Note: If a character while under this spell’s effect is struck by a Frenzy effect, than this spell effect is immediately nullified”
<br>Updated various Illusion spells to match spell effect/form cost changes
<br>Changed illusion spells to direct attack from direct

<br>Calm
<br>Charm
<br>Frenzy
<br>Horror
<br>Panic
<br>Paralyze
<br>Silence


<br>Updated various Mysticism spells to match spell effect/form cost changes
<br>Changed Absorb Magicka from Direct to Direct Attack
<br>Removed overload from Absorb Magicka
<br>Changed Mark spell from:

Places an invisible, magic mark at the caster’s current location. Use common sense when deciding how many different marks a character can keep track of at once.

  to:

Places an invisible, magic mark at the caster’s current location. The amount of marks a character can keep track of is equal to their Intelligence Bonus.


<br>Updated various Restoration spells to match spell effect/form cost changes
<br>Added the ritual section with the following rituals:

<br>Rite of Focus
<br>Rite of Textual Inscription
<br>Rite of Motion
<br>Rite of Sight
<br>Rite of Morpholithic Inscription


<br>Removed the examples from “The Big Three”. They are wordy and don’t add much in the way of clarification.
<br>Added “The weapon does not increase the range of any spell as a result of its reach” to the end of the entry for the Focus weapon trait
<br>Renamed Bodkin and Broadhead arrows to Slashing and Splitting Arrows.
<br>Added the Mindlock attribute to the spell Attributes
<br>Changed Direct Attack to read: “This spell has a target or targets, counts as an attack, and requires a Primary Action to cast. These kinds of spells cannot do damange, and cannot be defended against by normal means.”
<br>Decreased Self form cost to 1
<br>Increased Touch form cost to 1
<br>increased Target form cost to 4
<br>Changed Target description to “Affects a single target character within 50m of the caster. If this spell would alter the Target’s mind or harm them in any way, this form becomes a Direct Attack.”
<br>Changed Chain form to R Attack (50m)
<br>Changed Cloack form cost to 4
<br>Decreased Pulse spell form to 4 + Z
<br>Gave Elemental Armor, Magic Armor, and Armor the Defensive Overload attribute
<br>Increased Drain [Characteristic] spell effect to 8 x SL
<br>increased Fire, Frost, and Shock effects to 2 x SL
<br>increased sunlight to 3 x SL
<br>Introduced mutual exclusivity to the calm and frenzy spell effects
<br>Modified Cure Disease to read:

Affected target removes the Diseased SL Condition<br>
Spell Level 2 = Common<br>
Spell Level 4 = Magical  
Note: This effect always counts as being either Spell Level 2 or Spell Level 4


<br>Increased rejuvinate cost to 25
<br>In Step 5 of Cast Enchantments creation, modified Binding Strength to come from the DoS of the enchanting test.
<br>Created the “Enchantment Savant” talent:

Enchantment Savant<br>
The character is able to craft consistently strong enchantments.<br>
Journeyman (Intelligence)<br>
When the character crafts an enchantment, they can choose to use their Enchant skill level as the Binding Strength of the enchantment instead of the DoS of the Enchant test if the DoS would cause the Binding Strength to be below their Enchant skill level.  


<br>Capped number of upkeep refreshes to the BS of the enchantment
<br>Added “In addition, the Water Breathing and Water Walking effects can be chosen, but the Become Etheral effect cannot.” to the Choose Constant Effects step
<br>Added the following optional rule:

Optional Rule - Cursed Constant Enchantments<br>
Some groups may like the idea of Cursed Enchantments. If you’re using this optional rule, then the following Spell Effect can also be added to an enchantment:  
Name: Curse<br>
Rules: This enchantment cannot be disabled by its wearer. To remove the enchanted item, the wearer can test Willpower once per turn, successfully removing the item on a success.<br>
The penalty for the Willpower test is determined by the spell level of the Curse:<br>
1: +30 2: +20 3: +10 4: +0 5: -10 6: -20 7: -30<br>
Cost: 5 x SL  


<br>Removed Magic Quality from Adamantium armor and shields
<br>Changed the “Utilizing Untrained Weapons/Armor” section to read:

Characters who use Weapons, Armor, or other equipment that they are not trained to use suffer the usual -20 penalty for using an untrained skill on any associated combat tests, movement tests in the case of armor, or any other tests that the GM deems appropriate. The GM may choose to alter or ignore this penalty if they feel the circumstances do not apply.


<br>Changed replenish to read:

Target character within 1 meter regains [Spell Strength] MP which cannot exceed the final casting cost

  Made the same change to the spell effect.<br>

<br>Changed Critical Success/Failure to allow double advantage, and added specification for tie:

If one character critically succeeded, treat it as if they succeeded with more DoS than their opponent (if their opponent succeeded at all). They also gain an advantage. If one character rolls a critical failure, and their opponent passed, then their opponent counts as having critically succeeded. If one character critically succeeds and the other fails or one succeeds and one critically fails, then the character who succeeded gains two advantages, which can stack if applicable. If both sides roll a critical success or failure then no advantage is gained, and neither attack or defense resolves.


<br>Renamed Tempered Focus talent to Living Armory
<br>Added Weapon Echo talent with Bladecaller as a prerequisite:

Weapon Echo<br>
The character has mastered the art of weaving a conjured weapone in with their attacks.<br>
Expert (Willpower)<br>
Requires Bladecaller<br>
When the character casts a Conjure Weapon spell, they may choose to reduce the duration of the spell to 1 round, and allow the weapon to freely float above the ground in an unoccupied space they can see. When summoned in this way, the conjurer may make a single attack with the weapon on their turn (which still counts as one of the total number of attacks they can do each round) using Combat Style (Willpower) for its test. The first of these attacks can be made as a free action, but subsequent attacks with a weapon echo require 1 AP. Immediately before or after making this attack, the character can move the weapon their WpB meters in any direction.  


<br>Changed the rules for Seasoned Conjurer:

When the character succeeds on a Conjuration test, they can choose to take a number of degrees of success that they rolled, or take a number equal to their Conjuration skill rank instead.


<br>Made Taskmaster talent allow the character to choose to use it (required to make Master of the Hordes change work)
<br>Modified Master of the Hordes:

The character may reduce the (X) required by each Mindlock trait affecting them by 1 (to a minimum of 0). This can apply to a maximum number of creatures summoned in this way is equal to the summoners WpB. A character may use this talent or Taskmaster on a summoned creature, but not both at once.


<br>Changed Forceful Impact to no longer be limited to weapons with the crushing quality.
<br>Fixed “Both characters fail” in step 3 in attacking &amp; defending section. Was: “Nothing happens and the turn ends”. Changed to: “Neither attack nor defense resolves”
<br>Added an alternate rule for Luck Point refreshing:

Some groups may find refreshing Luck Points at the start of each session to be too frequent or stale. For such groups, this optional rule is recommended.<br>
Rather than refreshing to full LP at the start of each session, characters start out after character creation with 1 LP. Then, Luck Points are only gained by earning them through significant character moments. These moments might include the following: adhering to a character’s Bond(s), character flaws, character personality traits, good planning, significantly positive interactions with any associated deities, achieving a character goal, Character Traits, Negative Character Traits or any other moments or interactions that the GM deems appopriate. GMs new to the system or their group should reward their players with LP often until they have a good idea on how they’re used in the system and by the players.  


<br>Updated the Force Movement special action to give the opponent the option to use Athletics instead of just the Combat Style test to oppose it.
<br>Made a change so that LP cannot be spent to reroll Critical Failures. Luck Score, however, CAN be used to reroll Critical Failures.
<br>Modified Defensive Stance to read as follows:

Defensive Stance<br>
Using this action grants the character +10 on any defensive tests made until their next turn. If the character has made any attacks this round, this action cannot be taken. Additionally, taking this action reduces your Attack limit to 0 until your next turn.  


<br>Also moved the delay turn action out of the list of delays as it was just a list of one since Defensive Stance is no longer a delay action


<br>Specified that soul trap is seen as a hostile action
<br>Modified all instances of Counter Attack to read as “Counter-Attack” for consistency.
<br>Modified Unnaturally Agile Talent: changed rank to Adept, then modified “This movement counts towards their total movement for the round.” to “This movement does not count toward their total movement for the round.”
<br>Modified Thunder Charge from:

The character can make an All Out Attack without the usual +20 bonus whenever he takes the dash action if his movement would carry him into melee range with someone he did not begin his turn within melee range of, and as long as he moves at least half of his base Speed towards the target in that turn. This All Out Attack only costs 1 AP instead of the usual 2.

  to:

The character can make an All Out Attack using 1 AP, instead of the usual 2, whenever they take the Dash action. This is applicable only if their movement would bring them into melee range with someone they were not initially within melee range of at the start of their turn. Additionally, they must move at least half their base Speed toward the target during that turn.


<br>For crit success on Alchemy, changed from max target number as DoS to max target number plus one
<br>For crit success on enchanting tests, changed from max target number as DoS to max target number plus one
<br>Added ENC values to the food table
<br>Specified that soul gems have ENC 0
<br>Changed price of silver ammo from 20 to 26
<br>Got rid of the idea of CrP, instead specifying what things can only be purchased with XP during character creation
<br>Allowed a choice between XP and gold to the purchase of spells during character creation.
<br>Removed the concept of CrP, just specifying what can’t be purchased with XP after character creation (currently, only spells)
<br>Removed the optional elite advance step from the character creation process. Starting characters with EAs is generally a bad idea except for specialized high level adventures. This will be specified in the Elite Advancements chapter once it’s created during the Scroll Merge step.
<br>Modified short rest to grant a number of Magicka Points determined by dropping the ones place from their Maximum MP. So, if a character's Maximum Magicka is 56, they recover 5 Magicka, rather than just IB.
<br>Changed the Bleeding(X) Condition:

Bleeding(X)
Reduce Wound Threshold by X. At the end of the character’s next turn, they take X damage (bypass AR/resistance); then X is reduced by 1. If X would be 0, the Bleeding condition is removed.
X is capped at 10 minus the affected character’s Endurance Bonus. If the Bleeding(X) condition would be inflicted on a character that already has a Bleeding condition, the value of each is added together and replaces the current Bleeding condition.


<br>Changed the red legion throw to inflict the Bleeding(1) condition instead of Bleeding(1d4+Material Modifier)
<br>Changed Blood Lung to inflict Bleeding(1) instead of 1d4 damage.


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/3-v3-merge-changelog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/3 - v3 Merge Changelog.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:52:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[4 - Scroll Merge Changelog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Merged Core Racial Talents from the PhB with the following changes

<br>Changed Dunmer Ancestor’s Protection Talent due to not taking the changes in PhB to Ancestor Guardian:

The Dunmer increases their Resistance (Fire) trait by 1. Additionally, once per long rest, the dunmer can cast Sanctuary at level 2 as a free action. The spell lasts for three rounds, costs no Magicka Points, and requires no test to successfully cast.


<br>Changed Dunmer Ancestor’s Wrath Talent due to not taking the changes in PhB to Ancestor Wrath:

Increase the Sanctuary spell gained from the Ancestor’s Protection talent from level 2 to level 3. Additionally, once per long rest, the character can use a Secondary Cast Magic Action to cast the Fire Cloak spell at level 2. The spell lasts for three rounds, costs no Magicka Points, and requires no test to successfully cast.


<br>Changed Imperial Luck to read:

The Imperial increases their bonus Stamina Points from Star of the West to 3 SP. Additionally, any time the Imperial spends LP or burns luck to increase the DoS of a test, the first LP they spend or luck they burn on that test adds 2 DoS to the test instead of the usual 1.


<br>Changed the Woad talent to read:

The Nord can, as an action, apply a smear of ritually prepared Woad war paint, which grants a Physical and Magical shield that protects against 5 points of damage for 3 Rounds that refreshes for free each Round. After the third round, the shield is no longer refreshed and dissipates once the shield HP is reduced to 0 or the character takes a Long Rest.
The ritual necessary to prepare one dose of Woad paint requires the Nord have access to natural plants, an open sky, and must be performed over a Long Rest as they beseech Kyne for her blessings and protection in the battles to come. This dose of Woad paint must be applied before the character’s next Long Rest.




<br>Added advice for short rests
<br>Added the following paragraph to Spell Absorption trait:

A character can have multiple instances of this trait simultaneously. If a spell successfully hits a target with this trait, resolve each instance individually in any order rather than adding the values together. Once a spell is absorbed, no additional instances of this trait should be tested for the purposes of absorbing this spell.


<br>modified the Cloak Conventional Spell and the Cloak spell form to activate at the end of the caster’s turn instead of at the end of each round
<br>Added the Tough(1) Trait to the Orsimer to faciliate the racial talents merge
<br>Split the purchasing gear and items section out from the Spend XP section in Chapter two. Purchasing gear now happens after attributes are generated in character creation.
<br>Weak immune system trait should also counteract disease immunity.
<br>Increased spell XP purchase cost to 10 x SL from 5 x SL for character creation, based on feedback.
<br>Merged and modified the Unglamoured racial variant from the Player’s Handbook:

<br>One With The Wild now gives a +10 bonus to all survival tests and a +20 bonus to those related to their wild shape traits. This replaces the old rules completely.


<br>Merged the Climber trait from SoB
<br>Merged the Bite trait from SoB, renamed to “Strong Jaws”
<br>added the following to the Regeneration trait:

This does not count as magical healing unless applied by some magical source.


<br>Added the swimmer trait
<br>Added a weak bones trait which reduces WT by X
<br>Merged the Reachmen, ashlanders, and crowns and forebears racial variants as-is.
<br>Merged the Ayleids and maormer as-is
<br>Merged the Falmer with the addition of an additional talent:

<br>(Racial) Chillhearted Fury: Frost damage dealt by the Falmer using spells or enchantments is increased by 1.


<br>Merged the sload with the following changes

<br>Added a +20 bonus to persuade tests made to intimidate to the Foreigner trait
<br>renamed the Foreigner trait to “Abominable”


<br>Changed Bound Trait text that relates to hostility of the conjurer, changed “if attacked” to “if intentionally harmed”
<br>Reduced Conjuration summon creature spell costs to 1/2 of their previous costs instead of 1/3. This overrides the previous changelog entry which mention reducing these spells’ costs.
<br>Added the following rule to Conjuration Summoning Spells:

If this spell is restrained, the summoned creature’s Maximum AP is reduced by 1 while they have the Bound trait.


<br>Merged the Expanded Racial Talents from the Player’s Handbook
<br>Merged the “Fleshing Out A Character”, “Character Names”, and “Optimizing Characters” sections into Ch 2.
<br>Point buy - budget reduced to 80, can no longer be spent on luck. Luck must still be rolled for.
<br>Modified Telepathy trait to allow a broadcasting to up to WB characters
<br>Merged the following from PHB:

<br>Alfiq - Added the following under “Other”

<br>Alfiq can take the Thought Caster talent without meeting any talent or characteristic prerequisites.


<br>reduced cathay Int to 20 to account for better Nat weapons
<br>reduced Ohmes-Raht to 25 Ag, boost Prs to 27
<br>reduced Ohmes End by 1
<br>Reduced Dagi-Raht Prc and Prs by 1, gave them Powerwell(10)
<br>Fixed spelling of Pahmar (not Pahmer)
<br>Pahmar - change description to say "More primal dialect of ta'agra"
<br>Added to Pahmar and Senche "Other" section

<br>The Pahmar/Senche can understand any language in their languages list, but can only speak Ta'agra.
<br>Looted armor must be modified by a smith before the Pahmar/Senche can equip it.
<br>The Pahmar/Senche does not have opposable thumbs, and will suffer penalties to any tasks requiring fine motor skills or grip, such as using a weapon. This is left to GM arbitration.


<br>All instances of "Bite" in the natural weapons profiles are removed. Added as a description for these traits "Attacks made with this natural weapon do not require a free hand".
<br>Character Traits

<br>All CrP values are divided by 100 and replaced with the Trait Points currency.
<br>New Characters start CC with 1 Trait Point, and can purchase a maximum of 5 traits (total between pos. and neg.).

<br>Severe Negative Traits

<br>Amnesia, and Star Cursed = 5 TP
<br>Blind, Deaf, Lingering Injury = 4 TP


<br>All Trait Points after CC are lost






<br>Added the following to all Summon Creature spells

If the spell ends because the caster chooses not to upkeep this spell and the summoned creature has the Bound trait, the creature is unsummoned.


<br><br><br>
<br>Added Bonds
<br>Removed mention of Counter-Attacking from the Blademaster talent, as defensive stance precludes the player from Counter-Attacking.
<br>Modified “Strong Jaws” to read:

A Bite attack made by this character that deals damage automatically starts a Grapple. The test to contest this Grapple is made against the original test made by the attacker. If the target Counter Attacks a Bite attack, the Counter Attack ignores the creature’s AR and Natural Toughness trait.


<br>Merged Quadruped from the Scroll of Oblivion, changing it to read:

Characters with this trait move up to twice their speed when they use the Dash action and three times their speed when they use the Sprint stamina ability.


<br>Merged the Rite of Conjuring, but specified that the creature cannot be subjugated if the ritual fails.
<br>Merged the Rite of Princely summoning, removing the Elite keyword
<br>Merged the Rite of the Creation of Flesh, modifying the harvesting test to be a -20 Alchemy test limited by Lore,
<br>Changed the number of upkeeps maximum for a cast enchantment to 1 instead of BS.
<br>Specified that mindlock is still paid by caster in cast enchants
<br>From Scroll of Undeath:

<br>Added Necromancy Skill
<br>Added the Reanimation spell with the following changes

<br>Creatures are now reanimated with full HP, Full SP, Full MP, Full AP, and any uses of limited use abilities
<br>Added traits to the list of what they retain.
<br>Specified that they do not retain powers gained from their race
<br>Specified that creatures turn to a pile of ash and cannot be reanimated when they die after they are reanimated or the spell is not upkept.
<br>Reduced spell cost values by 1 to reflect uncon costs
<br>Added the spell effect


<br>Added the Summon Ghost spell with the following changes

<br>Added to spell effects
<br>reduced duration to 1 round and cost to 12
<br>added lvl 3 with an ancient ghost at 16 MP


<br>Added the Summon wraith spell with the following changes

<br>Added to spell effects
<br>reduced duration to 1 round and cost to 18
<br>added a lvl 5 version which summons a Gloom Wraith @22MP




<br>From Wonders of Ayleids

<br>We left the Colovian Ayleids behind
<br>Created the Elite Advances optional chapter
<br>Merged the White-Gold artificer EA

<br>Changed the non-ayleid cost to burn 10 luck instead of 500 XP
<br>Changed welkynd and varla armor to no longer require a test to absorb the magicka
<br>Merged rituals with the following changes

<br>Separated the create varla stone and welkynd stone rituals
<br>Welkynd stone ritual saw a reduction to the Power Well trait granted by sapphire
<br>Modified the base varla stone to be standard, and the flawless varla stone to recharge 3 enchanted items (with more difficult test)




<br>Various edits for clarity (storm was a poopy boi caveman)


<br>Modified mighty cleave to not require forgoing the +20 All-Out Attack bonus to strike the 2 targets
<br>Specified that the number of targets in telepathy was “up to” a number of characters, not equal to.
<br>From Scroll of Undeath

<br>Added the following rule to enchanting with black soul gems:

using a Black Soul Gem in an enchantment limits any associated Enchanting tests by the enchanter’s Necromancy Skill.


<br>Merged the rites of undead with the following changes

<br>Specified that the bonewalker requires a Spell Level 5 or higher paralyzing magic cast on it
<br>Specified that the bonelord can know up to six spells that the ritual caster knows
<br>bonelord Binding words must be to guard a specific location and cannot be issued additional commands not directly relevant to guarding that location


<br>Merged Rite of Necromantic Transcendance

<br>Specified that the second necromancy test is also +10


<br>Merged Rite of Soul Sight

<br>Added: “On failure, the ritual cannot be reattempted for 7 days.”


<br>Rite of Mortal Transference

<br>Specified +0 Necromancy skill test in 1st paragraph
<br>Replace “Dire Quality” with “Magic Quality”
<br>Specified that the required chalice must be worth at least 500 Drakes


<br>Merged Soulsnare


<br>Changed the XP cost of purchasing spells at character creation for x5 to x10
<br>Clarified that the Natural Toughness trait applies to all damage types, as defined in the Scroll of Beasts
<br>Removed the cost for the Cursed effect optional rule (constant enchantments don’t calculate cost like cast enchantments) and specified that the effect is only available for constant enchants.
<br>Changed [Fire, Frost, Shock, Poison] Strike enchant cost from 375 x SL to 300 x SL
<br>Specified that Wall form applies its effect when a character enters it
<br>Modified Area of Effect Attacks to only halve damage on successful block - evade only works for AoE if the target can evade 1m out of the affected area.|
<br>Took away the ability for the Weakness trait to stack, instead applying the highest value X for any given damage type.
<br>Reduced the Resilient trait advances in the Wrothgarian and berserker from 5 each to 2 each
<br>Reduced HP bonus for the Sload’s Baleful Bloating trait to +3 from +10
<br>Remove Upkeep from Fatigue Spell and Spell Effect
<br>Added toxin tag to charm
<br>removed upkeep attribute from the calm spell effect
<br>Added potion attribute to restoration
<br>Added toxin tag to Turn Undead
<br>Added potion tag to Stabilize
<br>Removed Unwieldy quality from greatsword
<br>Modified Axe costs to match their equivalents in the Slashing/Crushing categories
<br>Book of Circles

<br>Merged Dai-Katana, added Shield Splitter, increased price to 350
<br>Merged Tanto, increased price to 75
<br>Merged Katana, Wakizashi, Trident, Rapier, Scimitar, Bola
<br>Created a category in equipment called “Utility Weapons” which contains the Net, Bola, and Sling. Then, we merged the Materials chart for the Sling, allowing it to also apply to the Net and Bola.
<br>Merged Punch dagger and Cestus, reducing Punch Dagger cost to 45.
<br>Merged Hook Sword + Bill Hook
<br>Merged Targe + Buckler Shield Types.
<br>Merged


<br>Increased cost of uncommon alchemy ingredients to 35
<br>Reduced cost of rejuvenate spell effect to 16, cost of spell to 17
<br>Changed Feint Again:

<br>hidden lasts until end of current turn instead of end of next turn
<br>Added in the choice to use deceive (or combat style)


<br>Book of Ayleids

<br>Merged the Pain Sorcerer

<br>Modified the entry cost to 1000 for Ayleids/someone with a trainer, 1500XP for anyone else.
<br>Various minor balance tweaks (shit’s changed, yo)
<br>removed the Blood Harvest talent
<br>Added Trollblood to the exceptions list on the Rite of Transformation




<br>Specified that, on failure, the attempt to make Runed Weapons/Armor cannot be repeated.
<br>Merged the rules for crafting Daedric Weapons &amp; Armor from the Scroll of Oblivion
<br>Changed the Characteristic Advance to use the current bonus instead of the new bonus.
<br>Propagated conjuration costs to the appendix.
<br>Changed common potion/poison cost to match the formulae provided to the players. Assumed the alchemist would have the Alchemist talent applied
<br>Specified that Upkeep test rerolling does not include the casting test.
<br>Renamed Danger Sense character trait to “Threat Awareness”
<br>Specified that summoned creatures do not retest Wp on upkeep; instead, retesting once per minute.
<br>Specified that the Knife fighter talent only applies to daggers, tantos, and shortswords.
<br>Merged the following weapon talents from Book of Circles with changes where specified:

<br>‘Tis but a scratch, rules changed to:

The character can channel their frenzy to ignore debilitating wounds.<br>
Expert (Endurance), Requires Berserker<br>
While the character is frenzied, they ignore the Passive Effects of Wounds, and any Crippled or Lost Limb/Body Conditions that they gain during this frenzy. These effects are immediately applied as normal once the character loses the Frenzied condition.


<br>Kensai - as-is
<br>Daisho - as-is
<br>Retiarius, renamed to “From Oblivion’s Heart” (capt. ahab ref) with the rules changed as follows:

Expert (Strength)<br>
Should an attack made by the character with a trident inflict a wound, the enemy gains the Bleeding(1) condition regardless of the shock test. Additionally, any Trident the character wields gains the Thrown (5/10/20) quality. If a thrown attack with this weapon hits the target, the attack counts as having the Entangling quality, except it can be blocked, and inflicts damage as normal.  


<br>Riposte - as-is
<br>The Whirling School - as-is, minus the last paragraph (re: wrapping around neck)
<br>Rain of Steel - renamed to “Slinger’s Wail” with the following rules:

The character’s missile sings at it flies through the air; a note of imminent death inciting terror in your enemies.<br>
Expert (Agility)<br>
When the character attacks while Hidden, characters who are unaware of them within the weapon’s short range must make a +0 Panic test.  


<br>Pugilist - took it as-is, but removed agility from gov. char.
<br>Rip and Tear - rules reduced to:

Hook Swords wielded by this character replaces the Slashing (2) quality with the Slashing quality. Additionally, the penalties inflicted by the Hooked trait are increased to -20 while the weapon is wielded by the character.





<br><br>
<br>Merged Shehai Shen She Ru from book of circles with the following changes

<br>Changed all XP costs to match the talent level that shares a name with the skill requirement on the technique
<br>Zero-Sum Interrupt

<br>reduced difficulty penalty to -20
<br>removed the stipulation that the target cannot react in any way


<br>Changed Bone-Shaver to read:

The swordsinger selects a target in melee reach, and tests this technique, choosing the penalty of the test. If successful, the character can immediately make a melee attack against the target as a free action using Shehai Shen She Ru. The swordsinger can choose the hit location freely. The target's wound threshold is reduced by X for the purposes of resolving this attack.


<br>Increased the difficulty penalty for The Sword Tremor by -10 to -50
<br>Shehai talents:

<br>Added Aberrant Adept
<br>Added the three Ansei Talents
<br>Added the Shehai (Effect) talent with the following changes:

<br>Rename “Blinding” effect to “Radiant”

The character can, as a free action, change the composition of his Shehai. When he does this, the blade glows brightly and hits with the Shehai deal Sunlight damage.



<br>Remove “Cleaving”
<br>Rename “Proven” to “Tested”
<br>Change “Soul Rending” to simply reduce WT by 1
<br>Remove Stable (no swords have Unwieldy anymore)
<br>Change Tearing to read: Attacks that do damage apply the Bleeding(1) condition
<br>Thirsting: Change Savage to “Proven” quality, Have not has
<br>For the effects which change the damage type (incl sunlight), modify them to require a secondary cast magic action

<br>Add an expert talent, called “Prismatic Blade” which allows switching those effects as a free action.






<br>Merged the Shehai as-is, but increase the second level penalty to -30, and the third level to -60


<br>Nuked the Paired Quality
<br>Added the following to the bleeding condition:

Bleeding can also be reduced by making a Profession[Medicine] +0 skill test and using a Healer’s Kit. Reduce X by the DoS of the test. The Healer’s Kit is not consumed in the process.


<br>Merged Thu'um with the following changes:

<br>made a note that a Thu'um test is not required for characters who know Dovahzul as a language.
<br>Replaced the following text from Voice of the Ancients:<br>
"However, to those not initiated in the way of the voice, the Tongue’s normal speech inflicts 1d4+WpB damage to all within WpB meters of the Tongue as the ground shakes and blood-vessels burst. A +10 Thu’um test can be used to reduce the voice to a “whisper” temporarily, reducing his speech to the volume of “rolling thunder”, removing the threat of harm."

<br>With:<br>
"What the tongue can and cannot do with this talent is up to the GM, but the effect is generally small and innocuous, though it is still apparent to those nearby that the Tongue is using his Voice."
<br>Modified the 2nd and 3rd words of Cure Disease:

<br>2nd Word now cures magical diseases
<br>3rd word now removes all magically applied effects.


<br>Cyclone
<br>First Word<br>
Change range to to 1m. All ranged attacks that pass through the affected area, including the character’s, are made at -10.
<br>Second Word

<br>reduce damage 1d8 Crushing(1)
<br>increase affect area to 2m
<br>Increase Ranged Attack penalty to -20


<br>Third Word

<br>Reduce damage to 1d12 Crushing(2)
<br>Increase Ranged Attack penalty to -30




<br>Decoy

<br>Modified it to "Create an illusory representation of the character"


<br>Dismay

<br>First word<br>
- Reducing range to 15m.
<br>Third Word

<br>change to require that the character forfeit the bonuses from both the 2nd and 3rd word.




<br>Dragonrend

<br>Changed to do the following:

<br>Target Dragon that the character can see or that can hear the character is compelled to land as soon as possible using however much movement and/or AP required to do so. Then, they must stay grounded for one minute. Additionally, they lose 1 Stamina Point.


<br>Made it legendary


<br>Frost AND Fire Breath

<br>Damage steps from: 1 - 1d8, 2 - 2d8, 3 - 4d8
<br>Remove damage mitigation bypass rule
<br>Reduced range to 10m cone


<br>Fleshrend

<br>change damage dice to 1 - 1d8, 2 - 1d10, 3 - 1d12
<br>words 1, 2, and 3 deal bleeding 1, 2, and 3 respectively
<br>Modify base difficulty to +0


<br>Ice Form

<br>Ice form - modify "check" to "test"
<br>Change stun condition to paralyzed, remove the part about "effects that would allow them to..."
<br>Changed 3rd word to -30


<br>Lightning Blast

<br>modified damage as follows: 1 - 2d4, 2 - 3d4, 3 - 5d4
<br>had each word increase AR/MR ignorance by 1: 3, 2: 5, 3: 7


<br>Restore Life

<br>modify "the Blood Loss" to read "passive wound effects"
<br>modify base difficulty to +0, and stepped difficulty to -30
<br>word 1: 2d6, word 2: 4d6, word 3 as-is


<br>Restore Magicka

<br>Modify values to a flat 15, 30, 45
<br>make it also able to target others


<br>Slow Time

<br>Keep the amount of max AP and Attacks you get consistent (+1) through all 3 words
<br>1st word = until end of next turn, 2nd word = 4 rounds
<br>3rd word as-is


<br>Storm Call

<br>Damage steps: 1 - 1d8, 2 - 2d8, 3 - 4d8
<br>Give the storm a 200m radius
<br>Once per round the character may, as a free action, command the storm to strike a specific target within the storm radius. This command is resolved as a Direct Attack which counts toward the character's attacks per round limit. At the end of each round, if the character has not commanded the storm this round the storm will attack a random character within the storm's radius.


<br>Unrelenting Force

<br>Change to a 3m wide, 15m long beam.
<br>Remove stun, use dazed condition
<br>Damage becomes 3d6 (3rd)
<br>Base difficulty is -10


<br>Whirlwind Sprint

<br>+10 to the base difficulty
<br>Add to the first word that the movement does not provoke AoO.
<br>Other actions cannot be performed during this movement. 


<br>Added the following to the Shouts section:

All shouts are audible within a 50m radius or the affected radius, whichever is larger. If the shout is marked with the Whisper keyword, the Tongue may choose to make the shout only audible within 1m instead.


<br>Tagged Throw Voice, Aura Whisper, and Shadow Form as Whisper shouts.


<br>Bend will

<br>1 + 2nd words, addED the word "reasonable" to the first sentence.
<br>2nd word, make the Wp test a +10 test
<br>3rd word, make the Wp test a -10


<br>Call of Valor

<br>Heroes of Sovngarde

<br>Power Attack is still using old PA rules. Change to match current rules.
<br>Move the "Summoned" rules to the Shout.
<br>Remove Warrior-Spirit
<br>Variants

<br>Mage of Sovngarde

<br>Fix "Ward Bolt"
<br>Give it Power Well (20)


<br>Greater Hero of Sovngarde

<br>Rename "Tough" to "Hardy"
<br>"Uses either the Hero or the Mage of Sovngarde as a base"






<br>Specify in the first word "Hero or Mage of Sovngarde"
<br>2nd Word - Typo, "Greater  Hero"
<br>Change the difficulty. Keep base, change incremental to -20


<br>Dragon Aspect

<br>Add an asterisk that states that the shout can only be used successfully once per long rest.
<br>Add "Natural Toughness (3)" to the second word


<br>Form Change

<br>Make it a whisper shout
<br>Difficulty - 0 base, -20 incremental


<br>Earthen March

<br>Remove "at the cost of slowing them" in the flavor text and the penalty to the word
<br>Change difficulties to -20 base, -20 incremental


<br>Song of Destiny

<br>"Prophesy" &gt; "Prophecy"
<br>As we merge this one, pay close attention and edit for clarity, consistency, and readability
<br>Also reduced max AP by 1 while singing


<br>Soul Tear

<br>1st word - Choose targets equal to WpB. If target dies within 1m, fill soul gem (word like soul trap) 
<br>2nd word - Halve the targets' HP Maximum for 1 min. If a targets current hp is higher than this new max, reduce their current HP to their max. Once this effect wears off, the Current HP remains at the value.
<br>3rd word - If the character dies during the shout's duration, the corpse rises for 5 minutes


<br>Words of Surety

<br>Make it a Whisper




<br>Thu'um Rituals

<br>The Knotted Tongue

<br>Cannot be used for Legendary Shouts
<br>Remove from the flavor text "making it a tool to strengthen those already strong in the Voice"
<br>Regardless of the results of the test, the ritual ingredients are consumed except for the tongue itself.




<br>Conjure Weapon effect cost in the appendix becomes SL x 7
<br>Replaced Appendix Conjure weapon with the correct version of the effect text
<br>Modified the costs for Conventional Conjure Weapon
<br>Specified that conjure armor/weapon 
<br>Renamed Drain Characteristic to Absorb Characteristic to better represent what the spell does. As such, moved to Mysticism for consistency
<br>Reorganized the Appendix with regards to reassigning the responsibility for determining Attack effects to the effects table.
<br>Lichdom Elite Advance

<br>merged in Scroll of Undeath version along with the following from the Black Book

<br>Skeletal Claws




<br>Specified that Attacks of Opportunity from Retreat apply when an opponent "voluntarily" retreats.
<br>Specified that Damaged Quality affects all Armor Ratings, not just AR. Item still breaks when AR is reduced to 0
<br>Removed Resistance trait stacking

<br>(fight me)


<br>reduced Sunder Binding effect and casting costs and added it to the Mysticism school in addition to Conjuration
<br>Fixed all references to "Hit Points" - should be "Health Points"
<br>Added "Throughout the course of the game, Characters that wish to pursue learning languages can do so. Please discuss with your GM on ways to do this."  to Linguistics
<br>Removed the requirement that the character can not have attacked on their turn for defensive stance 
<br>Made the defensive stance bonus for Blademaster talent stack with the existing bonus from Defensive Stance
<br>Did not merge cannibalism from the BB. The rules don't add much to gameplay, and we figured that the subject was best left to a GM's supplement.
<br>Merged Warden Elite Advance with the following changes:

<br>Made all warden talents governed by both Wp and Prs
<br>Modified Fungal Growth to use Defensive Overload instead of Overload
<br>Modified Budding Seeds to use Defensive Overload instead of Overload and reduced cost to 10 for level 3 and 20 for level 6


<br>Added "This Form ignores the Attack attribute at GM discretion" to the Cloak and Rune forms in the Appendix.
<br>Made Rune form take up 1 square meter
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/4-scroll-merge-changelog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/4 - Scroll Merge Changelog.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:54:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[v4.b1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>
Added the Unfettered Conjuration talent

<br>
Changed learning spells from trainers - now it takes 1 less day than it does with a tome, to a minimum of 1 hour.

<br>
Removed the summoned daedra Willpower test which could make them become unbound 

<br>
Modified the bound trait

<br>Added the reference to being hostile found in soul trap to trigger removal of trait
<br>trait is removed if the master's ally is hostile or harmful as well.


<br>
Modified the Diseased trait to inflict disease on successful damage rather than on a wound, and made it so you cannot contract two diseases at once

<br>
Modified Quick Draw to only give the first Ready Weapon action for free

<br>
Changes to Advantages

<br>Specified that precision strikes, Penetrate Armor, Forceful Impact, and Press Advantage are attack only.
<br>Added block to the compatible actions on Overextend


<br>
Specified that power attack is before damage on successful attack

<br>
Modified power attack to add damage to a damage roll rather than the attack to enable pumping damage on each damage roll for mighty cleave and similar talents/abilities.

<br>
Added the new version of the Call of Nature spell for the Warden EA. Works similarly to summoning Daedra, except there is no opposed Wp test to keep them in line. This is balanced out by the fact that the summoned creatures are generally much weaker than daedra, Giants being a small exception.

<br>
Modified the "flesh" spells, previously Shield spells, to be barriers that have HP rather than give the caster HP. As part of this, removed the rule that we added saying that damage taken to the shield 

<br>
Fixed Dispel Strike enchant - new value is 300 x SL

<br>
Renamed "Defensive Overload" to "Reinforce"

<br>
Added below to the upkeep spell attribute:

If the spell has no listed duration, then the character cannot upkeep the spell if they have cast a different spell since the original cast. If a spell has the Attack attribute, then upkeeping the spell counts toward the maximum attacks per round limit.


<br>
Gave the Fatigue, Water Walking, and Water Breathing conventional spells and appendix spell effects the Upkeep Attribute

<br>Added "When included in a Toxin, this spell effect is not considered to have the Upkeep Attribute." to the Spell Effect for Fatigue


<br>
Made the conventional invisibility spell lvl 5 to match the unconventional spell effect

<br>
Made the unconventional feather spell effect lvl 3 to match the conventional spell

<br>
Clarified how the Weak Immune System character trait interacts with the Resist Disease trait

<br>
Added "This spell can stack and each instance of this spell is upkept separately." to burden

<br>
Added a "Sling" weapon quality: "This weapon does not use conventional ammunition, but rather uses small rocks and other similarly-sized and shaped objects. Ammunition can be specifically purchased or crafted for this weapon but the material’s damage bonus is not applied." Added this quality to the Sling.

<br>
Added a clarification to the Spell Absorption trait:<br>
"If a character with this trait would be affected by the Reflect spell, then the effects of each should be resolved in the reverse order to which they were applied.<br>
For example, if a character with this trait has the Reflect spell effect applied to them after this trait is applied, then when the character is affected by another spell effect they would resolve Reflect against that effect first, then Spell Aborption if the effect is not reflected."  

<br>Clarified that specializations are affected by favored characteristics.


<br><br>
<br>Modified The Whirling School talent to read the following (the old one didn't work at all)


<br>The character can use a bola to make a special Precision Strike to attempt to wrap the bola around either the target's neck or their legs. Upon a successful hit, if the attack is against the neck, the target loses 1 SP per round (does not stack). If the attack is against the legs, then the target gains the immobilized condition. Either effect ends when the bola is removed, which can be attempted by the target or a character within 1m as a Primary Action by making a +0 Strength test.



<br>Added a new talent to the berserker tree which doubles SB and SP gained from the condition
<br>made it so the Berserker talent causes the frenzied character to only lose 1 SP at the end of frenzy, and the Controller Anger talent cause no SP loss.
<br>Added doubling WT to the 'tis but a scratch talent
<br>Added the Cutthroat and the Death by a Thousand Cuts talents for additional support for the bleeding condition
<br>Modified turn undead to be more specific in how the undead flee.
<br>Changed burning to apply at the end of the affected character's turns
<br>Allowed either the target character or the "caster" to burn luck for regrowing limbs on blessed touch
<br>Added the concept of Special Advantages in a character's combat style. Modified the base advantages to not include special actions by default, but rather reference the character's available Special Advantages.
<br>Reset attack attributes on spell to the v2 state. Previously they were arbitrarily over-applied.
<br>Modified the Primary Cast Magic action to be used for both attack and non attack spells.
<br>Added the Instant Spell Attribute and Modified the Secondary Cast Magic action to only be usable for spells with the Instant Spell Attribute.
<br>Added the Instant Spell Attribute to a number of spell effects which apply non-negative effects to the target.
<br>Added Magical Diseases, Lycanthropy, and Vampirism
<br>Added EAs for lycanthropes (Beast Within), vampires (child of the night + vampire lord), and Shadow Magic
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/5-beta-changelog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/5 - Beta Changelog.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 03:33:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 - Full Release]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Changed the Flyer option for mutate to use base speed instead of speed x 2
<br>Changed cost for White-Gold artificer to not require burning luck for non-ayleids, instead cost double XP
<br>Fixed costs for dragonscale armor
<br>Swapped stat arrays for Aundae and Cyrodilic vampire bloodlines
<br>Increased the Silver material EL to 550
<br>edited unstoppable might for clarity and to allow for dual wielding of two-handed weapons without benefitting from the dual fighter talent
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/6-full-release.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Changelogs/6 - Full Release.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 22:23:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Character Creation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Read and follow the instructions for Character Creation contained in Chapter 2 in the presented order, following these rules where applicable:<br>
<br>All races are available
<br>Characteristic Scores (including luck) and Birthsign should be rolled with the GM present.

<br>GM should allow for up to three rerolls for Characteristics


<br>XP, Drakes, and Equipment Restrictions are determined by the Power Level for your playtest. If you aren't sure what power level you're playing, consult with your GM.<br>
- There will be rest periods where the player can recoup, use resources, attempt repairs, or pay for NPC services for repairs, healing, and other services. Be sure to consider this when making equipment purchases - drakes and other resources might be useful to have on hand in session!

Note: No optional rules are being used for this playtest.


<br>]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/3ev4-beta-playtest/character-creation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/3ev4 Beta Playtest/Character Creation.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 22:16:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Encounters]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Large Scale

<br>1 high difficulty (Like a Lich)
<br>2x players of low difficulty NPC


<br>Classic bandit crew
<br>Dwemer automata
<br>Spider Daedra + Giant Spiders
<br>Werewolves vs Vamps vs Party
<br>Dragon
<br>Dragon Priest + Draugr
<br>Goblins
<br>highest XP playtest, everyone gets to select a unique artifact (GM approval)
<br><br><br>
<br>3x Goblin Grunt

<br>2x Goblin Bow
<br>1x Goblin Blade


<br>1x Berserker

<br>Sledge


<br>1x Shaman

<br>Shock Bolt Staff


<br>1x War-Chief

<br>Shield + Axe


<br><br>Short Rest<br><br><br>
<br>1x Spellsword
<br>1x Mage (Conjurer)

<br>Attempts to summon up to 2x Scamps in their first turn
<br>Spells:

<br>Summon Daedra (Scamp)
<br>Summon Daedra (Clannfear)
<br>Sunder Binding
<br>lvl 4 Frost Bite
<br>lvl 2 shock storm
<br>lvl 2 disintegrate armor




<br>1x Mage (Support)

<br>Spells:

<br>Lvl 4 Heal Ally
<br>Lvl 2 Calm
<br>Lvl 4 Paralysis
<br>Lvl 2 Panic
<br>Lvl 2 Heal
<br>Lvl 3 Replenish




<br>1x Mage (Destruction)

<br>Spells:

<br>Lvl 2 Chain Lightning
<br>Lvl 3 Fire Bolt
<br>Lvl 4 Frost Bolt
<br>Lvl 2 Disintegrate Weapon
<br>Lvl 4 Fatigue
<br>Lvl 2 Frost Ball




<br>1x Archmage (Destruction + Alteration)

<br>Spells:

<br>Lvl 6 Chain Lightning
<br>Lvl 5 Fire Bolt
<br>Lvl 3 Fire Ball
<br>Lvl 4 Burden
<br>Lvl 4 Ward
<br>Lvl 2 Shield




<br><br>Long Rest<br><br><br>
<br>Lich

<br>Lich Staff Spell: Frost Bolt 3
<br>Spells:

<br>Lvl 4 Reanimation
<br>Lvl 5 Summon Wraith (Gloom Wraith)
<br>Mark
<br>Recall
<br>Lvl 5 Absorb Life
<br>Lvl 3 Dispel
<br>Lvl 4 Poisonbloom
<br>Lvl 4 Weakness to Magic
<br>Lvl 5 Frost Bolt




<br>[# of players] Skeletons

<br>1/2 Spear
<br>1/4 Shortbow
<br>1/4 Battle Axe


<br>[# of players] Zombies
<br><br>Short Rest<br><br><br>
<br>Dwemer Centurion

<br>Great Axe + Lance
<br>Consider Colossus as an audible for the high XP group


<br>x3 Dwemer Sphere

<br>2x Spear &amp; Shield
<br>1x Mace &amp; Crossbow


<br>x2 Dwemer Ballista
<br>x5 Dwemer Spider
<br><br>Long Rest<br><br><br>
<br>1x Dovah
<br><br>Emotionally cope with the finality of death<br>
Tear up player character sheets<br>]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/3ev4-beta-playtest/encounters.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/3ev4 Beta Playtest/Encounters.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 22:42:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Consider an increase to silver-scarred for lycanthropes, probably have it ignore natural toughness. Maybe increase 3-4

<br>decrease nat toughness for all forms of lycans by 1 (1, 2, 3 respectively)
<br>consider a werewolf buff


<br>Dying isnt defined
<br>stablize should help with wound effects
<br>Room for conditions on character sheets
<br>private gm roll for sheet macros
<br>Bold horror table results name in foundry IE Momentary blackout
<br>infinite stamina w/ controlled anger
<br>specify summon gloomwraith distance
<br>Vampiric disease cuts off too soon
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/3ev4-beta-playtest/notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/3ev4 Beta Playtest/Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 04:30:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Assignments]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>
<br>Copy <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1d7leImojwvY2knCO0TnVVYotlD5q4p_bPEdqpVJMg0k/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1d7leImojwvY2knCO0TnVVYotlD5q4p_bPEdqpVJMg0k/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank">this template</a> into your own google drive (File &gt; Make a Copy)
<br>Copy the rules for each statblock as-is from your assigned Scroll(s), merging into the formatting in the template

<br>If there are any issues from this process that need to be addressed, like incorrect abilities/spells, egregious inconsistencies, etc, discuss with the team before making any changes. List the changes made in the internal changes section of the statblock
<br>Use your best judgement (and quick research as necessary) for the new parts of the template (Difficulty, Morale, Lair Chance, and Grouping). If there is any doubt here, discuss with the team.
<br>Make sure to fix the little formatting issues that comes with copy+pasting from .pdfs, like the newlines being included in the copy + paste. This will make it easier for us later when it comes to merging the statblocks into the project.


<br>To solve the variants problem, take the following action and note in the statblock changelog:

<br>Variants which only contain small changes to stats or make otherwise insignificant changes, discuss with the team whether or not this variant should be dropped.
<br>Variants which contribute well to the book, either in flavor or in stats/abilities, but make minor changes that are easily referenced can remain as variants.
<br>Variants which make additions to Special Abilities or have a significant number of additional traits should be split off into their own statblocks.


<br>Some variants explicitly set Bonuses to a number - we should instead break that off into its own statblock
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/(alpha)-inhabitants-of-tamriel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/(Alpha) Inhabitants of Tamriel.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 23:32:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Collaboration Documents]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>LIST
FROM "Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab"
WHERE file.name != this.file.name
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/collaboration-documents.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/Collaboration Documents.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:03:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[IoT Design]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Guidlines

<br>General Style Guide: 

<br>Name (#): Thing, Thing; Other thing, Other thing; More thing, more thing


<br>Generally, Soul Size should be based on difficulty with some exception:

<br>Trivial: 10-100
<br>Minor: 100-200
<br>Average: 200-500
<br>Major: 500-1000
<br>Extreme: 1000+




<br>Outline

<br>Chapter 1: Getting Started

<br>Statblocks

<br>Mention that all Stamina Abilities are available per GM discretion except for heroic action
<br>Difficulty

<br>Trivial
<br>Minor
<br>Average
<br>Major
<br>Extreme
<br>Legendary

<br>(Reserved mainly for custom + Dragons)






<br>GM-Assigned Keywords

<br>Specify that one does not need to be assigned
<br>Minion

<br>describe the rules and usage


<br>Legendary (they can use heroic action)

<br>describe the usage




<br>Designing Encounters

<br>Choosing Combatants

<br>Action Economy
<br>Damage Output and Consistency
<br>Damage Mitigation (or Player Damage Output and Consistency)




<br>Customizing Statblocks
<br>Harvesting Materials &amp; Ingredients

<br>Survival Crafting
<br>Alchemy Ingredients




<br>Chapter 2: Beasts

<br>Common Traits

<br>Bestial




<br>Chapter 3: People

<br>Common Traits


<br>Chapter 4: Undead

<br>Common Traits


<br>Chapter 5: Daedra

<br>Common Traits


<br>Chapter 6: The Cursed (Tent.)

<br>Common Traits
<br>Future for Vampires + Lycanthropes


<br>Chapter 7: Dwemer Contructs

<br>Common Traits


<br>Chapter 8: Dragons

<br>Common Traits


<br>Chapter 9: Ayleids

<br>Common Traits


<br>Appendix

<br>Diseases

<br>Creatures
<br>Undead


<br>Loot tables

<br>table for each chapter?


<br>Maybe for special abilities. But probably not.
<br>Additional Resources (probably other books too)

<br>UESP
<br>Tuna's Drive

<br>Longtime respected homebrewer, link to the drive


<br>TIL






]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/iot-design.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/IoT Design.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:49:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Contributors]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Storm
<br>Gonk
<br>Tuna
<br>Herma
<br><br><br>
<br>The Lover Stone - move "as a secondary action" to after "spend a stamina point" for clarity
<br>Ritual Stone - add that it is a free action

<br>Made a Primary Action instead


<br>Serpent Stone - specify as a free action
<br>Shadow Stone - specify that it is a free action

<br>Made it a Seconary Action


<br>Tower Stone - Change to unlock any locked door or container that was locked by normal means once per day as a secondary action. Name "Warden's Key".
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Unbridled Power: Needs to specify Spending a luck point instead of burning, to stop confusion on whether the character burns luck.
<br>Keening: Kagrenac's Blade should change wording to grant Power Well (50) instead of describing the effect.<br>
Leave Unchanged Otherwise
<br><br>(Leave objects unchanged unless otherwise noted below)<br>
ALL ARMORS: remove the material in armor types and just use partial/full<br>Note for most artifacts with (cast) qualities: look into number of charges per long rest.<br>
<br>Anvil of Mithas/Hammer of Gharen: Keep +20 to smithing tests, Remove modification aspect and replace with the following: while creating items using the Hammer of Gharen with the Anvil of Mithas the character ignores the penalty to craft Superior weapons and armor. Additionally, items created using the anvil and hammer gain the Mithas' Protection quality. ✅ 2024-10-29

<br>Mithas' Protection: Items created via the Anvil of Mithas and the Hammer of Gharen cannot be damaged by physical or magical means. These items ignore effects that would cause them to gain the Damaged (X) quality. ✅ 2024-10-29


<br>Auriel's Shield: Look at the Magic Shield effect to determine rate at which temp HP refreshes. - refresh at the start of each round ✅ 2024-10-29
<br>Azura's Star: Add in "recharge" to the aspect of creating Enchanted items with the star: "It is not destroyed when creating or recharging magic enchanted items." ✅ 2024-10-29
<br>Bittercup &amp; Oghma Infinium: Add in either "The Bittercup/Oghma Infinium disappears when used." Or give it a time for the nectar to refill/the book to recharge (Can only be used by a character once). For bittercup, specify that the cup becomes a non-magical cup without the ability. ✅ 2024-10-29<br>
Made it so the bittercup only refills when Clavicus "wills it so".<br>
Also made it so the Oghma Infinium "returns to its master".
<br>Bloodworm Helm: Reword Dominate Undead to make more sense. ✅ 2024-10-29
<br>Brush of Truepaint: Formatting (already discussed) (not in TOC, review for typos and formatting) ✅ 2024-10-29
<br>Chrysamere: Damage is a little low, recommend at least +2/3 instead of +1, look at cast enchants to make sure they are giving the appropriate resources (12 hp for heal 6) ✅ 2024-10-29<br>
The values listed in the shorthand for enchantments are values for spell strength, not spell level. See Chillrend's Paralyze effect for an example.
<br>Crusader's Relics: ✅ 2024-11-01

<br>Aedric Favor Quality only affects armor. Maybe add an additional benefit for weapons (Increase Strength by 10 when wielding a weapon in addition to the full suit, or doubling strike enchants on weapons.) ✅ 2024-10-29

<br>Increase SB by 1 for the purposes of resolving damage w/ weapons ✅ 2024-10-29


<br>Shield of the Crusader: Fix wording ✅ 2024-10-29
<br>Mace of the Crusader: Add a Turn undead Strike Enchant (SL 4, Y 2) ✅ 2024-10-29


<br>Dragonbone Mail: Change resistance (fire, 10) to Immunity (Fire), Change Dragon Breath range to 10m cone and require a cast magic action to use. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Ebony Blade: Reword Vampiric Blade Quality to reflect an Absorb Life enchantment, but for half of the damage dealt, rather than a set value. Add a silence strike enchant (SL 3 Y 1) ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Ebony Mail: Add a Constant Enchant: Muffle (SL 4) in addition to existing effects. Lower resistance (magic, 10) to resistance (magic, 5) ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Eleidon's Ward: Increase BR to 13 and Magic BR to 10, Rewrite Cast enchants below the item table to reflect Heal 5 and Heal Other 5. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Fork of Horripilation: Replace DR with Natural Toughness. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Gray Cowl of Nocturnal: Reword mechanics to make more sense. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Helm of Oreyn Bearclaw: Change the Type to Full, change Light quality to Heavy. Increase AR to 8, Magic AR to 6. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Dumac's Wedding Gifts: Change note on strike enchants for both Hopesfire and Trueflame to deal 6 bonus [type] damage on strike instead of 5. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Lord's Mail: Reword Bull's Endurance to grant Regeneration (1) instead of describing the trait. - This isn't the regeneration trait because no End test is made - they just get the regen. It should also count as magical healing imo
<br>Mace of Molag Bal: Replace the Fatigue Strike enchant with a custom Strike Enchant to Absorb [Strength] SL 2 for 1 round. (Following existing spell) and add a Soul Trap strike enchantment. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Masque of Clavicus Vile: Change Light quality to Heavy, increase AR to 8, magic AR to 8. ✅ 2024-11-01
<br>Necromancer's Amulet: Change AR 5 for Resist Normal Weapons (5) and give Regeneration(1) ✅ 2024-11-01

<br>opted for regeneration(2) because there's a test involved


<br>Ring of Namira: Replace DR with Natural Toughness ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Sanguine Rose: Change SL 3 or lower Daedra to Any Daedra, make the summoned creature hostile to every being including the summoner, remove "but does not obey..." ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Savior's Hide: Increase AR to 8, and Magic AR to 3. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Scourge: Change SL 3 or lower Daedra to Any Daedra. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Skull of Corruption: Reword Duplication (formatting and typos) ✅ 2024-11-02

<br>Also removed the last sentence which allowed the wielder to create but not control past the WB limit - that sounds like a fucking nightmare for the GM.


<br>Staff Of Chaos: Add Attack Tag to Obliterate. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Staff of Magnus: Add Attack Tag to Siphon Energy. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Umbra: In Soul Siphon, replace DR with natural toughness ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Vampiric Ring: Change Source Character to Caster. 3 charges per long rest. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Volendrung: Increase damage to 2d8 +4. Maybe create a quality to have a target lose 1 stamina point when they take a wound, which is absorbed by the wielder. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>Wabbajack: Potentially change some animals for non-existent statblocks to ones that exist in IoT. ✅ 2024-11-03

<br>Let's go over these real quick


<br>Warlock's Ring: Increase to 2 charges per long rest. ✅ 2024-11-02
<br>White Phial: Remark on a potion's amount of liquid in the Phial. ✅ 2024-11-02
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/tamrielic-artifacts-notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Collab/Tamrielic Artifacts Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 03:01:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Contributor List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Dagoth.wav
<br>Herma Mora
<br>Stormrider57
<br>Zuka Brukal
<br>sigmafrenic
<br>Eygrima
<br>Gonk
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/contributor-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Contributor List.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 04:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core System]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Currently, stamina being depleted to 0 adds a level of fatigue. This needs to be updated with the v4 rule (below 0).

<br>add an option to use the legacy fatigue rule


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/foundry-update-needs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Foundry Update Needs.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:13:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feedback from a player (Alex)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1XHmHPgDJ0O2WKrwna4X-w07IFW4V9ldj8q6F-RsIhVA/edit?pli=1" target="_blank">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1XHmHPgDJ0O2WKrwna4X-w07IFW4V9ldj8q6F-RsIhVA/edit?pli=1</a><br><br><img alt="Pasted image 20240313220253.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/pasted-image-20240313220253.png"><br>
<br>Wall Form    

Leaves behind a persistent zone in this area for 1 round that causes the same effect to any characters who pass through it<br>
Maybe say “enters it” instead    


<br>Storm initial effect is rather strong?    
<br>Consider applying a penalty based on enchantment skill level to the enchanting test    
<br>Evade - Maybe evading AoE should only halve damage if you can move out of its range?    
<br>Weakness should NOT stack
<br>Manifold enchanter items -<br>
<img alt="Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Images/Untitled.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled.png">

<br>BS being based on DoS makes the enchantment potentially very expensive.


<br>Elemental Strike Enchant Costs:<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240313220515.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/pasted-image-20240313220515.png">
<br>Weapon Stuffs
<br><img alt="Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Images/Untitled 1.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled-1.png"><br>
Rejuvinate<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240313220610.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/pasted-image-20240313220610.png"><br>
<img alt="Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Images/Untitled 2.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled-2.png">
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/v4-backchannel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/v4 Backchannel.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:11:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/pasted-image-20240313220253.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/pasted-image-20240313220253.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3e v4.a4.0 Feedback]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>“Sload Player Characters” is at the wrong heading level
<br>There’s a weird font issue in the optional generate Characteristics rule on pg. 45
<br>Orc racial talent and sload stuff need a second look. That is way too much HP
<br>Purchase cost of spells at CC should be x10 instead of x5
<br>Specify that Natural Toughness applies to all damage types
<br>The Cursed Constant enchantment optional rule’s cost is way low.
<br>Consider changing elemental strike enchant cost from 375 to 300
<br>Ranged is doing okay now that we can power attack @range - but something more is still necessary. Proposing a talent which allows you to scale the big three weapon qualities off of Ag rather than Str for ranged weapons.
<br>Consider changing characteristic advances to use old bonus instead of new.
<br>Rejuvenate is rather expensive and not very often (or ever) used as a result
<br>Feint Special action from player reference does not match that of the rulebook
<br>We should change feint to allow the target to defend, but to do so at a -10. They’re still “Hidden” for the purposes of the talents.
<br>Spell costs for conjuring creatures were not propagated to the appendix.
<br>Review common potion prices - rejuvenate should be priced as if the alchemist has the alchemy talent
<br>description of upkeep should specify that the casting test does not need to be rerolled
<br>Skill listings on char advance and char creation tables should have numbers listed
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/3e-v4.a4.0-feedback.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Feedback/3e v4.a4.0 Feedback.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[3e v4.a4.1 Feedback]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/3e-v4.a4.1-feedback.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Feedback/3e v4.a4.1 Feedback.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[v4.a3.2 Feedback]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>GM Reference needs Alchemist and Enchanter fees (and any other similar fees)
<br>Spell XP cost at character creation is too cheap, doesn’t really line up with in-game spell purchase costs. might consider 10 x SL
<br>Consider adding grappling rules to the player reference
<br>Consider putting attack vs defense resolutions into the GM ref
<br>Consider adding panic + horror tables to the GM ref
<br>Fix the bit about still using 1 AP if you do nothing in the Action Types section<br>
<img alt="Untitled 2.png" src="lib/media/untitled-2.png">
<br>Add “until” their first turn<br>
<img alt="1000002708.jpg" src="lib/media/1000002708.jpg">
<br>Pg. 57 rapid recovery typo
<br>We need rules that define what happens when the summon spell is willingly dropped by the caster (unpaid upkeep)

<br>Current thought is that the summoned creature is unsummoned if they are bound when the spell expires


<br>We need rules that specify that summon creatures cannot be unsummoned by the dispel spell
<br>Clean up the whole ass paragraph cause that shit is tough to parse. Maybe summoning rules should be separated from the spell itself.
<br>Clarify that summoned creatures do not retest their Wp test on upkeep, unlike standard upkeep rules

<br>Current thought is to have them retest at the end of every minute/10 rounds


<br>Misspelled Become Ethereal in the Constant Enchants section. Also consider separating out the allowed and disallowed effects sentence for clarity.
  <img alt="Untitled 1 2.png" src="lib/media/untitled-1-2.png">
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/v4.a3.2-feedback.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Feedback/v4.a3.2 Feedback.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:11:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/untitled-2.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/untitled-2.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alpha Playtest Targets]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Spell Absorption between Spells, Dragonskin Breton Talent, and Birthsign
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/alpha-playtest-targets.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Alpha Playtest Targets.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apocrypha Merge Canditates]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is not a final list, but rather a list for the community to review.<br>
<br>Implement Black Book Version of Conjuration
<br>Warden Elite advance - Book of Y’ffre’s Wrath
<br>Substitute Scroll of Undeath EA with the EA found in the BB - Book of Revenant Shades
<br>replace Bound Trait with the following from the BB:

This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together by magic. It must obey the commands of their master, unless it is to defend themselves. If attacked by its master for any reason, it turns hostile and immune to commands. Items with this trait use their creators Willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test (Except Combat Style), and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.


<br>But, consider changing it to:


This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together by magic. They must obey the commands of their master, except they will always prioritize defending themselves. Additionally, if attacked by their master for any reason, they turn hostile and lose the bound trait. Items with this trait use their creators Willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test (Except Combat Style), and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.


<br>Bring over everything from the Book of Shifting Tides chapter, except:

<br>Voice of the emperor from the BB needs future consideration when we decide what v3 items to bring over
<br>Openly discuss summoning (summoner’s death) - currently the idea is that we would remove the idea that the creature dies on summoner's death, since it already only lasts until upkeep is not paid
<br>Telekinesis (only fixes v3)
<br>IF we port over Forceful Impact advantage from v3, make sure to use the errata included in this section. Otherwise, disregard


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/apocrypha-merge-canditates.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Apocrypha Merge Canditates.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Balance-Tweak Considerations]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Creating Poisons, Paragraph 1: ✅ 2024-10-20
  <img alt="Untitled 4.png" src="lib/media/untitled-4.png">
  Dagoth’s Notes:
  The poison duration should be limited to a bit more than an entire minute. Adding a whole ass die that ignores armor? Sure, it’s save or suck, but it lasts the entire fuckin encounter (1 min). This is broken kinda like how people thought v2’s splitting was broken. Except this actually is broken. My suggestion (in blue) is we just copy the rule from Toxins—1 min or 3 successful hits. I truly don’t think poisoning my dagger with an extra save-or-suck 1d4 poison damage is much different in strength from poisoning it with a +20 paralyze toxin
  Added a way to recover unused poison (highlighted green). Or we could state that the poison is lost if they apply it and don’t use it. Or is this something we leave for the GMs?<br>

<br>Suggestion for Toxins, Paragraph 2 ✅ 2024-10-20
  <img alt="Untitled 1 4.png" src="lib/media/untitled-1-4.png"><br>

<br>Consider adding rules for crit successes in potionmaking ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider spiltting reload from ready as a primary action ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Be specific with specializations ✅ 2024-10-20

<br>With spellcasting specializations, specializations can be for a spell (would apply to any level of that spell. ✅ 2024-10-20


<br>Dual wielding is mentioned, but never defined. We need to define that somewhere. ✅ 2024-10-20
  Dual wielding is mentioned, but is not consistent in its hyphenation. All instances should be set as a crossref and should use no hyphen<br>

<br>Feedback from Mario ✅ 2024-10-20
  <img alt="Untitled 2 2.png" src="lib/media/untitled-2-2.png"><br>

<br>For the Undead Trait, come up with some solution that resolves the ability to exploit SP use with the inability to become fatigued. ✅ 2024-10-20
  Current idea is to disallow the use of abilities with an SP cost once the character with the undead trait is at 0SP.<br>

<br>Issue with berserker talents brought up by angathor ✅ 2024-10-20
  <img alt="Untitled 3 2.png" src="lib/media/untitled-3-2.png">
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/balance-tweak-considerations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Balance-Tweak Considerations.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:10:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/untitled-4.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/untitled-4.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Black Book Merge Finalists]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Book of Shifting Tides

<br>Beast Tongue
<br>Bound Trait

This creature is bound to this world, or simply bound together by magic. They must obey the commands of their master, except they will always prioritize defending themselves. Additionally, if attacked by their master for any reason, they turn hostile and lose the bound trait. Items with this trait use their creators Willpower score when forced to roll any relevant test (Except Combat Style), and are practically weightless, counting as having an effective ENC rating of 0.


<br>Stunted Magicka
<br>Summoned trait

This creature or item has been conjured from another<br>
plane of existence. Upon its death or<br>
destruction, it returns to where it came from immediately.  


<br>Damaged (x)
<br>Frenzied Errata

<br>Condition
<br>Berserker talent
<br>Controlled Anger talent




<br>Black Book Conjuration, but don’t add an extra attribute for Mental Capacity, keep in it the rules def
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/black-book-merge-finalists.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Black Book Merge Finalists.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Content Suggestions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Bleeding talents

we'd reduce anything that applies bleed to just apply bleed(1). Then an expert level talent, or a pair of them, could increase that to bleeding(2). If there's two talents, they'd probably be adept level and conditionally apply bleeding(2)


I'm thinking a couple of talents. One to increase the WT loss, and another to add 1 to bleeding conditions applied by the character


<br>Suggested talents from fistocuffs:


<br>
Rght now, the talents are laid out in different sections, but Combat has the weapon specific ones and general combat stuff, but also not everything combat related. A possible change would be to put weapon specific talents in their own sections, like specialties and also look at some of the talents in Awareness that should be in Combat. July 17, 2023 5:28 PM

<br>
July 17, 2023 5:21 PMJuly 17, 2023 5:21 PMJuly 17, 2023 5:21 PM
All Out Attacks  
Preemptive Strike - Adept Agility<br>
The first time you perform a Counter Attack each round, you attempt an All Out Attack with a +20 attack bonus at no additional AP.  
Note: Still costs 1 AP to Counter Attack, but would gain +20 and stack synergies for Counter Attack or All Out Attack.  
Expose Weakness - Journeyman Strength or Agility<br>
When you perform an All Out Attack, you can choose to forsake the +20 attack bonus. If your attack hits, then the next Spell or Weapon attack against this target is made with +20 bonus.  
Bloodletting - Expert Strength or Agility<br>
When you perform an All Out Attack using a weapon with the Piercing, Slashing, or Splitting quality, you can choose to forsake the +20 attack bonus. If your attack hits, the target is inflicted with the Bleeding (1d4 + weapon material damage modifier) condition.  
Careful Aim - Journeyman Strength or Agility<br>
When you perform an All Out Attack, you can spend 1 Stamina Point to add an additional +20 attack bonus.  
Weapon Styles  
Close Quarters Training - Expert Strength or Agility<br>
When you hit with an All Out Attack made while unarmed, or using a fist, claw, or dagger weapon, you make an additional attack against the same target with its own attack and damage rolls. This additional attack does not count toward your 2 attacks per round.  
Brutal Reclamation - Expert Strength or Agility<br>
Thrown weapons can be retrieved as a free action if the character is able to move to where the weapon landed. Retrieving thrown weapons from a creature causes it to be inflicted with the Bleeding (1d4 + weapon material damage modifier) condition.  



  Suggested by Angathor:

Couple of suggestions for changing the -mancer spell talents in the following iterations, let me know what you think:  
Pyromancer:<br>
Your fire-based spells inflict an additional +3 Damage against Unarmored body parts. Additionally, reduce enemy WT by one when they are hit with fire-based spells and inflict Burning (Spell Level) upon a Wound.  
Cryomancer:<br>
Your Frost Bolt and Frost Ball spells gain Splitting (Spell Level) quality. Additionally, if you inflict at least 1 damage (after mitigation) with a frost-based spell, make the enemy roll their Strength or Endurance or increase their Encumbrance Level by one until the end of that enemy's turn.  
Electromancer:<br>
When your shock-based spells hit an armored body part without the Magic property - increase the damage by one for every armor weight class above Light, double the bonus damage if the hit armor piece is Full Armor. Additionally, if you inflict at least 1 damage (after mitigation) with a shock-based spell, make the enemy roll their Endurance (+10) or apply Dazed (1) condition until the end of that enemy's turn.  


<br>Tuna suggests reducing the weaknesses of his vampires and werewolves if/when they’re merged
<br>Doidgestar provided an old Dark Paths doc
  “/Dark_Paths_Ideas_and_Information_Gathering.docx” could not be found.

<br>Loot

<br>A Table for Each existing 3e supplement
<br>Tuna Example<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240519235206.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240519235206.png">




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/content-suggestions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Content Suggestions.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 03:54:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240519235206.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240519235206.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scroll Merge Considerations]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Consider using BB Lich
  decided against it, though we did take the ability for the base lich from the BB.<br>

<br>Fix Pain Sorcerer using BB Errata
<br>Scroll of undeath and scroll of thu’um undead trait
<br>Elite advances from the black book
<br>BB Conjuration - no

<br>Conjured creatures last 1 round rather than 1 minute (upkeep per round)


<br>PhB talents are in dire need of rebalancing
<br>Just look at BB versions of everything to look for fixes
<br>Social Stigma should have the penalty multiplied by X, but the +100 XP for taking it at character creation should be capped at 1x.
<br>Keep an eye out for any statblocks that use percentages for Silver-Scarred and Sun-Scarred.
<br>The Daedric Weapons and Armor blurb under crafting refers to the Scroll of Oblivion, which will be deleted as the referred content is merged
<br>See image
  <img alt="Untitled 3.png" src="lib/media/untitled-3.png"><br>

<br>See Image
  <img alt="Untitled 1 3.png" src="lib/media/untitled-1-3.png"><br>

<br>Make a character sheet page for elite advances
<br>improve the wording of the natural weapons trait to reference the "default natural weapons profile" defined in the unarmed combat section, maybe tweak unarmed combat to use the same phrasing (instead of "fists" or something) and then clarify that the khajiit racial talent still ups the die for alfiq, they just don't get slashing.
<br>PHB

<br>Breton Expert talent: make spell absorption stack multiplicatively using percentages outside of spell effects.

<br>Note from Herma:

just have it so that, for each uniquly sourced effect (so no multiple spells unless you think its covered) you roll seperatly, so three sources (sign, talent, spell) you roll seperatly for each, instead of math


<br>Suggested text from Dagoth:

A character can have multiple instances of this trait simultaneously. If a spell successfully hits a target with this trait, resolve each instance separately


A character can have multiple instances of this trait simultaneously. If a spell successfully hits a target with this trait, resolve each instance individually rather than adding the values together

  We’ll go with some version of the second quote from dagoth<br>





<br>For treasure tables, use luck tests (or luck bonus) to determine what the result on the table is
<br>Separate Treasure Tables for each “scroll” of monsters/npcs
<br>See below while merging Flesh Magic
  <img alt="1000002398.jpg" src="lib/media/1000002398.jpg"><br>

<br>Merge Survival crafting from SoB
<br>We need to come up with a finalized cost reduction for summoning.

<br>potentially a small reduction, then add a talent which would reduce upkeep by some amount


<br>Consider a conjuration talent which would give a bonus to the opposed Wp test
<br>Switch the summoning spell to test willpower at the end of each round after unbound
<br>Specify on summoning what happens when a spell is not upkept.
<br>Pay special attention to the scroll of oblivions note on enchanting - that Conjuration cannot be used for const enchantments
<br>Slip this one in: A new talent which gives natural weapons the magic weapon quality.

<br>Use the following flavor text: "Your dedicated training in martial arts has culminated in your ability to now slap some bitch ass ghosts...and other things too I guess"
<br>We need a name for it
<br>Herma’s suggested rules text:

You have learned to focus your Magicka into your strikes, allowing them to hit opponents previously immune. Your hands and other natural weapons are considered magical, overcoming incorporeal and normal weapons.

  This would need some changes, including referencing the magic weapon quality explicitly and a slight tweak to the “oppenents previously immune” verbiage (imo)<br>



<br>Review v4.a3.2 feedback before wrapping this version
<br>Tweak bond examples. They should be something that gets under the “why” of the personality trait
<br>Reaction using dash is broken if done in response to an attack
<br>Discuss Blademaster talent and purge defensive stance from the book completely
<br>Natural Toughness needs to explicitly state that it reduces all incoming damage
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/scroll-merge-considerations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Scroll Merge Considerations.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 02:22:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/untitled-3.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/untitled-3.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scroll Merge To-dos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Point buy - budget reduced to 80, can no longer be spent on luck. Luck must still be rolled for.
<br>Alfiq - Add the following under “Other”

<br>Alfiq can take the Thought Caster talent without meeting any talent or characteristic prerequisites.


<br>reduce cathay Int to 20 to account for better Nat weapons
<br>reduce Ohmes-Raht to 25 Ag, boost Prs to 27
<br>Ohmes comes first
<br>reduce Ohmes End by 1
<br>Reduce Dagi-Raht Prc and Prs by 1, give them Powerwell(10)
<br>Fix spelling of Pahmar (not Pahmer)
<br>Pahmar - change description to say "More primal dialect of ta'agra"
<br>Add to Pahmar and Senche "Other" section

<br>The Pahmar/Senche can understand any language in their languages list, but can only speak Ta'agra.
<br>Looted armor must be modified by a smith before the Pahmar/Senche can equip it.
<br>The Pahmar/Senche does not have opposable thumbs, and will suffer penalties to any tasks requiring fine motor skills or grip, such as using a weapon. This is left to GM arbitration.


<br>All instances of "Bite" in the natural weapons profiles are removed. Add as a description for these traits "Attacks made with this natural weapon do not require a free hand"
<br>Character Traits

<br>All CrP values are divided by 100 and replaced with the Trait Points currency.
<br>New Characters start CC with 1 Trait Point, and can purchase a maximum of 5 traits (total between pos. and neg.).

<br>All Trait Points after CC are lost
<br>We need a couple extra 1 Trait Point Character Traits
<br>Add in an optional rule blurb describing how this system can be tweaked


<br>Severe Negative Traits

<br>Emphasize the bit about deliberation, doubly so for GMs
<br>Amnesia, Lingering Injury, and Star Cursed = 5 TP
<br>Blind, Deaf = 4 TP




<br>Change Telepathy trait to read “up to their WB” instead of “equal to”
<br>Bonds
<br>Mighty cleave - don’t make them choose to forsake the +20. Why didn’t we do this already?
<br>Increase spell purchase costs of XP to 10 x SL
<br>Decrease spell tome purchase Drake cost to 50 x SL
<br>Come up with a different name for danger sense character trait
<br>Inhabitants of Tamriel

<br>Provide an overview of how to evaluate a stat block and general "encounter balancing" advice.
<br>For each statblock (or group of statblocks), create a section that provides an analysis of the statblock and what, mechanically it is good at/bad at. This should serve to both inform GM strategy and provide more context for encounter balance. i.e. describe how the creature would fight, what it's good at, what it's bad at, and what tier of characters it would match up well against and in what number.


<br>’Tis But a Scratch - passive effects are already ignored by frenzy. Remove the bit that refers to it
<br>Tamrielic Artifacts

<br>go back to Great Welkynd Stones and make it truly special.
<br>There are some artifacts in secrets of the dwemer


<br>Statblocks

<br>talk about daedra hearts and their rarity. Legendary is too much


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/scroll-merge-to-dos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/Scroll Merge To-dos.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 01:34:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Enchanting]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>All Talents are pulled from the BB, as that is the “fixed” version of the v3 talents<br>
|   |   |   |<br>
|---|---|---|<br>
|Change|Merge?|Why/Why Not?|<br>
|In v3, a critical success gives a PC 1 LP which can exceed the maximum.  <br>In our version, the PC does not gain the LP.|No|Too rewarding on a success, too detrimental on a fail|<br>
|v3 removes this paragraph to the end of the “Critical Successes &amp; Failures” section:  <br>”In combat, critical successes and failures have specific effects  <br>for attack and defense rolls that are further explained in the  <br>appropriate section.”|No|Giving this specification adds to New Player experience without any real downsides other than the extra paragraph in the chapter. No real reason to remove it IMO|<br>
|v3 has a section in the “Critical Successes &amp; Failures” that deals with “Non Player Character Critcals” [sic].  <br>  <br>Note: fix this typo if we merge  <br>  <br>_This section has a table that specifies lucky numbers for NPCs based on CR.|Noish|I think a flat lucky numbers array for GMs is easier to keep track of. There’s no significant difference in “feeling” of gameplay to warrant the added complexity of basing it on CR. HOWEVER, we should probably specify what the NPC lucky numbers are here. If not a flat lucky numbers array, at least make it more general. I.e. 4 entries instead of the 8 or whatever.  <br>Also, we might just move this to the statblocks section/book and also put the creature’s lucky number right on their statblock.|<br>
|Wound Threshold|Noish|I think we should consider adding optional rules for removing wound threshold, as hinted at in the BB. It’s a simple enough thing to add for those who prefer playing without WT. This appears in Core mechanics section &amp; Finishing touches section  <br>IF we do this, we should include the relevant talents in the optional rules section, and not the talent section to avoid bloat)|<br>
|v3 adds rules for Linguistics, which determines what languages a character knows.|Yes|Consider specifying that this formula only applies during character creation. The character can choose to seek out additional languages, which is up to the GM to determine.  <br>Consider adding a GM check for exotic languages, as well as adding more exotic languages  <br>This appears in Core mechanics section &amp; Finishing touches section|<br>
|v3 rids us of the ability to work up to 4ap|Yes|Point: Nothing wrong with current rules, maybe specify that most characters will start with 3AP except in very high CrP starts  <br>  <br>Counterpoint:  <br>This appears in Core mechanics section &amp; Finishing touches section  <br>Review all talents and purge anything to do with AP calculation|<br>
|v3 adds perfect hit to the stamina spending options, which is basically ranged power attack|Yesish|Specify in power attack that it can be done with ranged weapons, rather than adding a new entry in the SP options.|<br>
|v3 moves bash to stamina spending and makes it a free action (no AP)|No|We take away an advantage option, and you can technically use heroic action to use an SP for it anyway.|<br>
|Skill Level Maximum|Yesish|The concept is good, but the CrP/XP amounts need to be changed. Appears in both the getting started and the Spend CrP sections|<br>
|v3 takes away spending XP on specializations|No|Dumb|<br>
|v3 adds learning a ritual|Yes|Duh|<br>
|v3 removes names for talents and uses talent levels|No (ish)|It’s a core flavor element - but adding a number in parenthesis might be worth it for reference.|<br>
|v3 has a different beast tongue trait for bosmer|No|Ours is the latest version of Beast Tongue|<br>
|v3 changes voice of the emperor|No|v3 version might have larger balance implications, and achieves basically the same thing. Though v3 might result in interesting character choices|<br>
|v3 adds tough trait to orcs|No|Orcs are strong as it is, no reason to add an additional trait when other races are less powerful. Thematically makes sense, but no mechanical reason for it.|<br>
|v3 changes ancestor guardian.|No, nerf ours|If we take our version, consider nerfing it.  <br>V4.a3 proposed version would have a ghost last 30 minutes, but disperse after a combat if it participates in said combat.  <br>v3 merged version would reduce the sactuary strength to 1 for 3 rounds, instead of 3 DoS for 3 rounds.|<br>
|v3 rewords Moonshadow power|No|original wording is fine.|<br>
|v3 changes untrained penalty to -10 from -20|No|A -10 bonus is not enough to incentivize players to purchase low level skill ranks. Also, for the most part, being untrained in something SHOULD mean you’re not very good at it.  <br>Maybe optional rule for more “casual” games|<br>
|v3 moves combat specializations to the skills chapter|Yes|During combat, it is not likely that this section will need to be referenced. Better fits the Skills section.|<br>
|BB Talents Skillful alternate requirement||So far the discussion is that it muddies the waters for players, but the skill requirements is an interesting mechanic.  <br>Needs further discussion.|<br>
|Talent Levels|No (ish)|Use the numbers in parenthesis|<br>
|Talent - Combat senses||Consider 2 x PcB + 2 rather than 3x PcB. Our version is a bit underpowered, v3 is too overpowered. Should do some IR math for different possible configurations and compare to the result of this talent.|<br>
|AP refreshing||Further discussion NEEDED|<br>
|Talent - Defender||If we use v3 AP refresh, use BB version|<br>
|Talent - BB Fearsome removes intimidating as requirement|Yes|The two are unrelated|<br>
|BB Introduces a new talent, Assassinate|Yes|Gives the player an option to advance their sneak attack damage|<br>
|BB Sneak attack is at Apprentice, rather than Journeyman|Yes|SA is not powerful enough for Journeyman|<br>
|Shadow Strike||Needs discussion.  <br>Our version requires melee attacks to kill to use the talent  <br>BB version requires melee attacks to forgo advantage to use the talent.  <br>Additionally, BB version is at Expert lvl rather than master.|<br>
|v3 removes the Perfect Hit talent|No, BUT →|Replace our wording: “Master (Perception): The character adds their Perception bonus to the damage dealt by Precision Strike attacks (either melee or ranged).”  <br>With: “Expert (Perception): The character can use their Perception Bonus for the purposes of determining Splitting, Slashing, or Crushing damage in place of their Strength bonus.”|<br>
|Master Alchemist Talent Goes from Master rank in our version to expert in BB|No, BUT →|If it’s not strong enough, then we should make it stronger. It’s called “Master”|<br>
|BB Grandmaster talent allows grandmaster spellcasting without penalty|Yes|It’s a common complaint that lvl 7 spells aren’t worth it. While it might not completely solve the issue, it gets us closer.|<br>
|BB Untouchable Talent: “The character can, before making a shock test, choose to expend a luck point to automatically succeed on the test.”  <br>Our Untouchable Talent: “The character replaces their Wound Threshold with three times their current Luck bonus.”|No|If we do a WT optional rule, then consider providing the BB version as alternative|<br>
|BB Interrogator talent decreases level from Journeyman to Apprentice|?|My thought is that it’s really not strong enough for Journeyman. It is already restricted to interrogations. So maybe we do merge this one.|<br>
|BB Prediction is OP as fuck, next (3x Intelligence for IR calculation AND decreased level)|HELL NO|Dumb|<br>
|BB Tactician lowers its rank to Adept from Expert|Naw bro|See above|<br>
|BB Hard Target Talent Removes the requirement for moving half speed|No?|There’s a thematic element that the half move speed enables, and the restriction itself isn’t all that steep.|<br>
|BB Unnaturally Agile brings talent level from Master to Expert|Yes|Having it at expert level gives the talent room to grow. Also AOE is relatively strong in this system, more AOE evade access makes sense.|<br>
|BB Stubborn adds the restriction of rerolling panic tests only once per test|Yes|BB version seems like RAI|<br>
|BB Fearless also adds the restriction of once per test for horror. Also has been brought to adept from master|Yesish|I understand wanting to reduce the level, but I think Expert would be more appropriate.|<br>
|Our Wall of Steel talent reduces weight class by one step, unless superior  <br>BB increases AR/BR by 1 and ignores speed penalty from any armor word|Yes|In our version, the inability to combine the talent with superior really sucks. Your talent just turns off if you’re wearing good armor. The BB version gives AR instead (good, but not crazy op) and gives an option for getting away from the armor speed penalty.|<br>
|BB Big words is reduced to Apprentice from Journeyman|No?|Why reduce? Charlatan, the very next talent, remains Journeyman. Seems arbitrary.|<br>
|BB into the fire removes the requirement for “leading the group”.|||<br>
|BB Adds Bladecaller talent|fuck yes|it’s a conjuration talent, much needed. Plus is just a good talent.|<br>
|BB Adds Weapon Echo talent|yes(ish)|It is pretty strong to attack as a free action, but your attacks are still limited. basically just frees up one or two AP for defence for conjurers. Potentially change it by saying  <br>“Once per turn, you may spend a free action to direct one of these summoned weapons to attack. You may spend additional AP to repeat this attack with that or any other weapons summoned this way. These attacks count toward the total number of attacks per round.”|<br>
|Big changes to many talents here. Not exactly merging from BB, but taking the opportunity now to fix some major issues with spellcasting talents.  <br>1 - Reduce Depth of understanding to Expert and modify it to add the Power Well Trait (X), where X = IB * 5  <br>2 - Force of Will is reduced to expert level, and renamed to “Magicka Cycling” ;)  <br>3 - Master of Magicka’s requirements are modified to either Force of Will OR Depth of Understanding  <br>4 - Any mutual exclusivity to do with the above is removed.|Yes, but not a merge|This is an attempt to balance these talents rather than simply merge them from the BB. We’re not happy with either version, and just took the opportunity to fix the glaring issues with the talents.  <br>  <br>We seem to have forgotten to record this: is depth of understanding dropping the “cannot utilize spell restraint” bit to make this work?|<br>
|BB adds living armor|No|Too powerful, and conjured armor is already pretty powerful. Not much of a need for talents for it, as nice as it would be flavor-wise|<br>
|Bearded Warrior|No, but|Rather than moving 1m closer, they can yank the target 1m in any direction that doesn’t cause their distance from you to increase.|<br>
|Beast of Steel|No, but|remove +10 Persuade (Str)|<br>
|Blademaster|No||<br>
|Bruiser|Yes, and|Change the lost stamina requirement to successful DAMAGE, reword If applicable to if chosen|<br>
|Firing Line|Yes|(bb version)|<br>
|Halberdier|No, but|change to: The character can choose to replace his halberd’s Splitting qual-  <br>ity with the Crushing quality instead. Additionally, change range to 3m. Additionally, you can spend 1SP to force the rider of a mount to roll Ride(+0) or fall off of their mount, becoming prone.  <br>_needs flavor text update|<br>
|Hammerblow|No, but|Reword to:  <br>When the character lands a hit with a warhammer or maul  <br>he can choose to either cause his target to lose one Stamina  <br>point, or make an all-out-attack to force the target to make an Endurance (+0) test. If the target fails  <br>this test, he gains the Dazed condition. The target may attempt  <br>one Endurance (+10) test on his first turn each round to remove the  <br>condition.|<br>
|Knife Fighter|No, but|Add to the beginning “When you use penetrate armor, add a d4 damage”|<br>
|Monster Hunter|No, but|Add support for the remove WT optional rule|<br>
|Viper’s Eye|Yes||<br>
|Point Blank|Yes, and|changing the advantage range to the melee range of target|<br>
|Power Draw|No||<br>
|Red Legion Throw|No, but|Remove the concept of “Speared”, and just explain what the concept does. Keep the first sentence|<br>
|Simple, Yet Effective|Yes||<br>
|Staff Master|No, but|remove precision strikes sentence|<br>
|Traits — added Bleeding (x)|Yes|Just forgot to add it|<br>
|Telekinesis|Yes|It’s a new cool thing that’s not OP|<br>
|Diseases|yes, but|only one stage, except for magical diseases.  <br>Add the Blight Disease, and consider adding variants. “Magical Diseases” are the only ones that progress.  <br>And then of course, vampiric and lycanthropic diseases. At stage, curing is no longer simple. GM defined for curing.|<br>
|Some general changes in he → they pronouns, that sort of thing|Yes, but|Let’s take care of this in the final proofreading pass, that we we take care of it all at once.|<br>
|Changes to initiative (combat overview section of ch. 5)|Yes, but|We’ve already discussed using v3 intiative as an optional rule|<br>
|v3 removes the verbiage “and can be taken when a character has gained Advantage in combat.” in the Special Actions section.|No, but|Add the text in bold: “and can be taken when a character has gained Advantage in combat. or as the listed action”.|<br>
|v3 adds a clarifying sentence to the Coup de Grace Attack action: “For Unarmed Coup de Grâce see Grappling rules”|Yes|It’s good to point toward the grappling section for unarmed|<br>
|v3 adds the ability to use the Aim secondary action for spellcasting|Yes, but|restrict it to just spells of the bolt form.|<br>
|v3 extends the clarification on Attack of opportunity following the 2 attack per turn max.|Yes, but|Not as verbose. We can just say “still following the 2 attack per round rule” or something of the like.|<br>
|v3 clarifies that attacks of opportunity can only be taken if they can see their target|Yes|It’s a good clarification.|<br>
|v3 combines the Block Parry, and Evade sections in the combat chapter to one section since they’re all being deferred to the Attack &amp; Defending section anyway|Yes|Good way to save space|<br>
|v3 removes the bash special action|No|See first instance of bash|<br>
|v3 Blind opponent is changed in three ways:  <br>1) More verbose wording in the first sentence without changing meaning or making any clarifications  <br>2) The target must be within SB meters of the opponent  <br>3) A character wearing a full helm automatically succeeds|No|1) It doesn’t really add much, though the v3 description does benefit from more generic pronouns (which we will do a pass for at a later stage  <br>2) It feels so arbitrary. I understand what they’re going for, but there’s got to be a better solution; but honestly, the bit about “reasonably have access” leaves it to GM fiat, and sometimes that’s just the right solution.  <br>3) … so full helms don’t have eye holes? Nah bro, leave it as is.|<br>
|v3 combines the take and disarm weapon actions|Yesish?|I think it benefits from being combined, but the two scenarios need to be better separated for the purpose of reading comprehension.|<br>
|v3 adds the Blinded condition to the list of resistible conditions in the resist action|Yes|Offering a way out of blindness is probably a good call.|<br>
|v3 adds the Feint Special Action|Yes|It’s a decent new option, and seems pretty balanced|<br>
|v3 untrained combat style uses the rules for untrained skills on combat styles (Attacking &amp; Defending Step 1)|No|make note of optional rule here|<br>
|v3 defines three attack types: Melee Weapon Attacks, Ranged Weapon Attacks, and Cast Magic Attacks|Yes|It’s good to specify weapon attacks when we’ve adding the magic attack type. And with the currently proposed rules for Spell attacks, this will be important|<br>
|v3 adds clarification for counter-attack if both characters pass their tests (Attacking &amp; Defending Step 3)|Yes|There is a general “best practice” that tied rolls result it a maintaining of the status quo. The status quo, in this case, is no effect.|<br>
|In Resolve Attack &amp; Advantage, will need an optional rule specifier for non wound threshold rules in Attacking &amp; Defending|N/A|N/A|<br>
|In v3, Advantages is it’s own section|No|I see the purpose, for ease of reference; but with the accompanying reference with our version it will not be necessary. The Advantages section, technically speaking, is still part of step 4: in the Attacking &amp; Defending section.|<br>
|v3 adds forceful impact as an advantage|yes|this was previously discussed; this is our replacement for the v2 errata damage rules. However, we remove the crushing trait stipulation.|<br>
|v3 adds Wounding Cleave as an advantage|?|?|<br>
|v3 adds Fortunate Hit as an advantage|?|?|<br>
|v3 removes Press Advantage advantage.|||<br>
|v3 removes Overextend advantage.|||<br>
|v3 removes Special Action advantage.|||<br>
|v3 adds a Critical Success/Failure section to that Attacking &amp; Defending section:  <br>If one character critically succeeded, treat it as if they succeeded  <br>with more degrees than their opponent (if their opponent suc-  <br>ceeded at all). They also gain an advantage. If one character  <br>rolls a critical failure, and their opponent passed, then their  <br>opponent counts as having critically succeeded. If both sides  <br>roll a critical success, then nothing happens.  <br>An attack made with a critical success causes a wound to the  <br>hit location of the attack.|Yes, but|use the last sentence regarding wounds in a wound optional rule clarification|<br>
|Under Improvised weaponry, the -10/-20 untrained penalty is referenced||Just noting for optional rule referencing|<br>
|Unusual Combat Scenarios section is moved as a subsection of Melee Combat|Uh, no|Unusual combat scenarios is not melee combat. Wut?|<br>
|Unarmed coup de grace causes the target to lose StB SP vs 1SP|||<br>
|v3 removes the Item Durability rules|Yes|This is being replaced by the Forceful Impact special action|<br>
|No rules for Holding your Breath in v3|no|Having the rule is better than not having it|<br>
|Note: Second holding your breath should be “Swinging or Jumping”|!|!|<br>
|Not v3 change: Under Damage Types, use a colon to punctuate the last sentence|||<br>
|v3 resets errata change for Magic Damage types (Damage Types → Magic Damage)|||<br>
|The “Death” section changes ‘pass an Endurance test each round” to “pass an endurance test on their turn”.|Yes|v3’s wording is more ambiguous and is compatible with the optional initiative rules.|<br>
|Optional rule support: Wounds. v3 wound rules trigger on a critical success, rather than Wound Threshold|optional rule|support for the v3 wound optional rule|<br>
|Optional rule support: In body wound bullet point, add an optional rule blurb for the alternate (v3) refresh rules|optional rule||<br>
|v3 moves the magic damage wound effect to Magicka points instead of losing a stamina point|?||<br>
|passive effects, under wounds - v3 removes the -2 penalty to initiative rolls|no|wounds should hurt|<br>
|passive effects, under wounds - v3 changes “the character has 30 seconds (5 rounds) before they drop to 0 HP from blood loss” to “The character has until the end of combat”.|no|What happens if the wound occurs out of combat? There’s no reason that I see to abstract the ruile.|<br>
|Removing the passive effects with first aid requires 1 turn (no AP) in our version, but v3 only takes a single AP.|no|Imagine being able to do a full first aid check and still make two attacks (or even one and defense) all in the same round. Taking the turn rather than an AP is a commitment, but still allows for defense by the character administering the first aid.|<br>
|v3 adds the following to “Treating Wounds”: Treating a wound related to the Crippled Condition can only be done once per long rest. If this test results in a dramatic failure, the limb immediately becomes Maimed.|yes|I like it — I feel like being able to go up to full health if you’re dealing with multiple cripplings should take a while to get over.|<br>
|Reminder: We’re going to want to change Fatigue to happen when you go below 0 SP.|n/a||<br>
|Frenzied condition first bullet point in v3 specifies separately that you may only make all out attacks, rather than smashing them into the same sentence|yes|good clarification|<br>
|Frenzied bullet point 3 Wound Threshold optional rules support|optional rule||<br>
|For organ damage, rather than reducing SP max and WT by 1, v3 has them healing damaging at half speed and increasing the passive wound penalty for all tests to -30|noish (optional rule)|We do need to account for the no WT optional rule. I propose we replace the WT increase by 1 with the -30 penalty from v3 for the no WT optional rule|<br>
|v3 stunned references our optional refresh rules|optional rule||<br>
|in v3, “snapping out” of fear always happens at the end of their turn|yes|I like it, it makes it so you still suffer the penalty for the fear test for your whole turn. Though I might reword the individual instances of fear rather than the general rule to add to specifity.|<br>
|v3 takes down the 1d10 falling damage to 1d8.|nah|d10 worked|<br>
|v3 adds Holding your breath section to Movement &amp; Size rather than unusual combat scenarios|no|I think we should consider a different contextualization for the “combat” chapter.|<br>
|Not v3 merge related: Fix “Inspire heroism” to read:  <br>”Once per round as a free action, the character can make a command test to inspire an ally who can perceive them. When inspired, the ally gains +10 to their next combat test.”|←——||<br>
|—————————-CHAPTER 6—————————-|————-|————————-|<br>
|Spellcasting &gt; Effect Durations changed.  <br>  <br>v4.a2.0: Effect durations are measured in rounds, and end immediately after the initiative step on which they took effect. For example, if an Orc is stunned for 2 rounds on his turn, he remains stunned until right after the end of his turn 2 rounds later (assuming his turn takes place at the same initiative “step” as it did originally).  <br>  <br>v3: Effects that last for one or more rounds last until the start of the caster’s next turn (after they were triggered, if applicable), and then an additional amount of rounds equal to their listed duration. For example, a fire storm spell deals its damage when first cast, then at the start of the caster’s turn, they can choose to upkeep the spell or not. If they choose to upkeep it, it deals the damage again immediately.|No, but|After discussion in chat, the general consensus seems to be to keep the v2 version but make a better example. Let’s keep an eye on this one during playtesting|<br>
|Casting Spells &gt; “Step 2: Casting test in v3” expands on how to determine your character’s effective spell level|Yes|Missing from v2; but v3’s version should be reworded.|<br>
|v3 adds the following to “Step 3: Resolve the Spell”: “Any spell that requires a test of the target(s) cannot be willingly failed.”|No|After discussion in chat, the idea was brought up that absorbing magicka can be abused; but a universal rule is overkill for that.|<br>
|Seems like v3 removes the section “Resolving opposing spell effects”.|No|Not sure why you wouldn’t want a section that helps resolve this.|<br>
|v3 adds the Mage Guard spell attribute||Depends on how it’s used|<br>
|v3 changes R/M Attack (range) to R/M/Direct Attack (range)|No, but|We have in our ideas list to “consider splitting out all of the spell attributes”, rather than combining them (like R/M/Direct) to aid in the differentiation between spell attributes.|<br>
|v3 adds the Mindlock(X) spell attribute|Yes|This is from the scroll of oblivion|<br>
|—————————SPELLS————————|—————|———————————|<br>
|ALTERATION|———-|————|<br>
|Armor adds the attribute “Mage Guard(+WpB to AR)||Kneejerk reaction is that +WpB is WAY too high, even if you’re forced to spend more magic re: Mage Guard attribute. Just at level 1, this spell would give most mages access to 5-6 AR for a minute with a LEVEL 1 SPELL. Then, it increases by 1 EACH spell level.  <br>I get the idea, but this is way, way too much. Let’s talk about alternatives.|<br>
|Burden costs in v3 are modified|Yes||<br>
|Feather cost is reduced by 1|Yes||<br>
|Jump cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|Levitate cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|Lock cost is increased by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|Magic Armor cost is reduced by 1 for all levels, and is given the Mage Guard(+WpB to Magic AR) attribute|Yes just to cost|See Armor above, but like  <br>WORSE  <br>WTF|<br>
|Magic Shield cost is increased by 1 for all leves  <br>Mage Guard here as well, +WpB to bonus HP but loses free upkeep|Yes to cost|This feels a little more balanced, since it can be lost and you lose the free upkeep when “overloading”. I don’t mind this one so much.|<br>
|Open cost is increased by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|Repair cost is increased by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|Shield cost is increased by 1 for all levels  <br>Gains mage guard, same as Magic Shield but for physical damage|Yes to cost|Same feeling as with Magic Shield|<br>
|Slowfall cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|Yes||<br>
|[Type] Armor Cost is reduced by 1 for all levels  <br>Gains the Armor mage guard formula for [Type] damage.|Yes to cost|Same feeling as with other armor spells — it’s just too, too much|<br>
|[Type] Shield cost is reduced by 1 for all levels  <br>Gains the Shield mage guard formula for [Type] damage|Yes to cost|Same feeling as with other shield spells|<br>
|Water breathing cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|Yes|Let’s add upkeep here as well. ADD TO EFFECT AS WELL|<br>
|Water walking cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|Yes|Let’s add upkeep here as well. ADD TO EFFECT AS WELL|<br>
|Ward gains Overload(+WpB to BR)  <br>Cost is reduced by 1 for all levels  <br>v3 makes ward have BR instead of flat damage reduction|Yes to cost and base mechanic|COME THE FUCK ON  <br>YOU DON’T HAVE TO USE WpB 1:1 FOR EVERYTHING  <br>+WpB is just too damn high for BR/AR in addition to the baseline levels|<br>
|CONJURATION|—————|———————-|<br>
|in v3 Summon Daedra, hunger’s spell strength is changed from 2 to 1|Yes||<br>
|v3 Sunder binding adds Upkeep, Direct traits|Yes to direct, no to upkeep||<br>
|v3 Sunder binding description changed from:  <br>The caster picks a target  <br>with the Summoned trait that must make  <br>an opposed Willpower Test vs the caster with a [Spell Strength]  <br>modifier or be sent back to the place from whence it came.  <br>to: The caster picks a target  <br>within 50m that has the Summoned  <br>trait  <br>that must make an opposed Willpower Test vs the caster  <br>with a [Spell Strength] modifier or be sent back to the place  <br>from whence it came.|Yes|specifying range is good|<br>
|v3 Conjure armor spell costs have increased relatively significantly|||<br>
|v3 conjure weapon switches from created daedric weapons with Inferior/common/superior quality to having a [Spell str] damage modifier.||I don’t see a problem that is being resolved by the v3 change. The scroll version of the spell is pretty straightforward and I don’t see any particular issues. If the spell’s conjured weapon is op, then so are the weapon qualities; and I don’t think they are.|<br>
|DESTRUCTION|—————|——————————|<br>
|v3 changes chain lightning from Direct to R Attack (100m)|Yes|Chain lightning being direct was always a terrible idea|<br>
|Chain lightning cost is increased significantly for all levels|Yes|Damage output for CL is massive, increased cost makes sense.|<br>
|v3 Drain [Type] is changed from a R attack to a Direct attack|Yes||<br>
|v3 Drain [Type] cost is increased significantly for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Drain [Type] flavor text has changed|No|I like ours better|<br>
|v3 Drain Magicka cost increased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Fatigue cost increased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Sunbeam cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] Ball cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] bite cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] bold cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] Cloak cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] Cone gains the R attack attribute|No||<br>
|v3 [Type] Cone cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] Rune cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 [Type] Storm cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Weakness to [Type] cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 weakness to magic cost increased for all levels|||<br>
|ILLUSION|—————|——————————|<br>
|v3 Blind is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Blind Cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Calm is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Calm cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Chameleon cost is reduced by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Charm is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Charm cost increased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Courage cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Frenzy is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Frenzy cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Horror is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Horror cost increased significantly for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Invisibility cost is decreased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Light cost decreased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Muffle cost decreased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Night Eye cost decreased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Panic is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Panic cost increased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Paralyze is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Paralyze cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Sanctuary cost decreased by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Silence is changed from “Direct” to “Direct Attack”|Yes||<br>
|v3 Silence cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|MYSTICISM|—————|——————————|<br>
|v3 Absorb Life cost increased by one for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Absorb Magicka Direct changes to Direct Attack and loses the Overload attribute|Yes||<br>
|v3 Absorb Magicka - all spell levels are removed but level 4, but level 4 is given the cost and magicka loss of level 7|No||<br>
|v3 Detect [Type] cost reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Dispel Cost reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Ethereal form cost reduced by 1|||<br>
|v3 Mark cost is decreased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Mark maximum is changed from  <br>&gt; Use common sense when deciding how many different marks  <br>a character can keep track of at once.  <br>to  <br>&gt; The amount of marks a character can keep track of is equal to  <br>their Intelligence Bonus.|Yes|For some things, GM fiat makes sense; but here, it doesn’t feel like there’s any context to help the GM make this decision. WpB feels right, as for most casters this will range from 3-5; which seems reasonable.|<br>
|v3 Recall cost is reduced by 1|||<br>
|v3 reflect cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Soul trap cost is increased by 3|||<br>
|v3 Spell Absorption cost is reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Telekinesis cost reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|v3 Telepathy cost reduced by 1 for all levels|||<br>
|RESTORATION|——————|———————————|<br>
|v3 Cure Paralysis cost increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Curing Disease lvl 4 cost reduced by 1|||<br>
|v3 Fortify spell costs increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 heal ally spell costs increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 healing touch spell costs increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 heal spell costs decreased by 1|||<br>
|v3 rejuvinate spell cost increased by 6|||<br>
|v3 replenish spell costs increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Resistance to Type cost decreased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Resistance to Magic cost decreased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Stabilize cost increased by 1|||<br>
|v3 Turn Undead costs increased by 1|||<br>
|Ward gains Overload(+WpB to BR)  <br>Cost is reduced by 1 for all levels  <br>v3 makes ward have BR instead of flat damage reduction|Yes to cost and base mechanic|COME THE FUCK ON  <br>YOU DON’T HAVE TO USE WpB 1:1 FOR EVERYTHING  <br>+WpB is just too damn high for BR/AR in addition to the baseline levels|<br>
|RITUALS are added in v3|YES||<br>
|pg. 104 minor effects seem to have been cut off, if not check out v3’s they seem to have expanded.|||<br>
|ALCHEMY ——————————-|——————|———————————————-|<br>
|v3 renames the “Toxins” subsection of poisons to “Non Damaging Poisons”|||<br>
|v3 changes the reference to the “[Toxin] tag” to read “the Toxin attribute”||Depends on if any changes were made to spell effect keywords|<br>
|————-Ch. 7 ————-|||<br>
|v3 big three removes the examples|yes|I actually think less is more in this case. The examples read out more like word problems than further explanations to me.|<br>
|We have 3 potential versions of Splitting:  <br>v2: Weapons with this quality can deal savage wounds when properly brought to bear. They deal bonus damage equal to the wielder’s Strength bonus (or X, if another value is given), but only if the initial damage result causes the target to lose 1 or more HP.  <br>v3: …but only if the DoS of the attack are higher than the AR value of the hit location.  <br>BB: If the initial damage result causes the target to lose 1 or more HP, they inflict the Bleeding Condition equal to the wielder's Strength Bonus (or X, if another value is given). If the target is immune to Bleeding, the weapon counts as Crushing for the purpose of choosing the Forceful Impact Advantage.|no (keep our version)|While it could be argued that v2 Splitting is too strong, I’m of the opinion that BB adds too much additional book-keeping to the combat flow and v3 is too weak.|<br>
|v3 refers to Bash as an action in the Concussive weapon quality|no|we’re keeping our version of bash, so no need to take this|<br>
|v3 specifies that damaged quality does not stack, but ours does. v3 Damaged quality also doesn’t specify that natural weapons cannot be damaged|no|Our version of damaged is something that is already modified from v2 and is likely the final v4 version|<br>
|v3 adds an addendum to Focus: “The weapon does not increase the range of any spell, due to it’s reach”|Yes, but|It’s a good clarification, but the wording and grammar is horrible and should be fixed to read “The weapon does not increase the range of any spell as a result of its reach”|<br>
|v3 adds the “Arcane” weapon quality, which gives the item the Focus quality as well as DOUBLING … doubling the number of… charges……..|NO|This is likely a result of v3 enchanting having fewer charges than v3 enchanting overall; we definitely, definitely do not want to be doubling our charges.|<br>
|v3 equipment Enchant Lvl changes across the board in v3|no|v2 EL is the one compatible with our Enchanting version|<br>
|v3 Dwemer weapon material Price mod drops from 6.0 x price to 4.0 x price and gains +1 ENC|no?|this feels kind of arbitrary. Not sure what the motive is on this one.|<br>
|v3 Orichalcum Price Mod drops for 4.0 x to 3.0 x|no?|see above.|<br>
|v3 Runed special melee weapon quality adds the following text: “Only found among Dawnguard or specialized Skyrim blacksmiths”|no|This is a lore tidbit that I’m not sure serves any purpose. There are a lot of regional materials and qualities throughout the book, and restricting things based on lore should be up to GM choice|<br>
|v3 moves Throwing Star/Dart to a thrown weapons section|no|I think we added ours at some point.|<br>
|v3 Dwemer ranged material has the same changes as the melee material|no|see the melee material|<br>
|v3 Orichalcum ranged material has the same changes as the melee material|no|see the melee material|<br>
|v3 Dwemer and Orichalcum Ammunition materials also see these changes|no|^|<br>
|v3 removes the Thrown Ranged Weapons entry, likely because they don’t have the throwing stars|no|we have throwing stars|<br>
|Don’t forget to fix the arrow types as we’ve discussed.|||<br>
|v3 adds a thrown weapons section|no|this is just a bunch of repeated equipment|<br>
|v3 Damaged armor quality is changed|no|Ours is already something we’ve discussed|<br>
|v3 Armored spellcasting penalties are added in the Weight classes section|no|already discussed|<br>
|v3 adds reinforced clothing/robes|no|already discussed, and is part of the Armored spellcasting penalties|<br>
|v3 moves the Armor &amp; shield quality section and the Shields section|no|v2 version is a logical placement|<br>
|v3 adds the arcane focus special armor quality|no|this is part of the armored spellcasting penalties|<br>
|Not sure if there are any changes to v3 armor equipment lists, but frankly I don’t think it matters. the current version is pretty sufficient and I don’t see any major changes in the v3 version|||<br>
|v3 seems to have removed quite a few items|||<br>
|v3 Alchemist Fee table goes up to 7+ — or ours is just cut off|yes|ours needs to cover all levels|<br>
|———— Appendix|||<br>
|SPELL ATTRIBUTES|||<br>
|v3 adds the toxin tag|yes|I think we forgot to add it here|<br>
|v3 adds the mindlock attribute|yes||<br>
|v3 spells out Ranged and Melee in the R/M Attack (range) attribute|yes, but|It’s good for legibility but we’re also splitting these out|<br>
|v3 adds Direct Attack with the text: Spell counts as a Attack for the purposes  <br>of the attack per round limit, as well as requires a primary  <br>action to cast.  <br>These kinds of spells cannot do damage.|yes, but|we also need to add this description to the attirbutes in ch. 6, if they’re not already there|<br>
|v3 adds the mage guard attribute|yes, and|take the changes to mage guard from ch. 6|<br>
|SPELL FORMS|||<br>
|v3 Decreases the self form cost to 1|||<br>
|v3 increases Touch form cost to 1 from 0|||<br>
|v3 increase Target form cost to 4 from 3|||<br>
|v3 adds the following text to the Target description: If this  <br>spell would alter the the Targets mind, or harm them in any  <br>way, this form becomes a Direct Attack.|yes|This feels like a good call. Aggressive spells should take an attack|<br>
|v3 Chain form is changed from Direct to R Attack (50m)|yes||<br>
|v3 Cloak form cost is decreased from 5 to 4|||<br>
|v3 Pulse form cost decreased from 5 + Z to 4 + Z|||<br>
|v3 Adds the Bind form|yes|this comes from conjuration|<br>
|SPELL EFFECTS|||<br>
|Alteration|||<br>
|v3 Elemental Armor gains the Mage Guard attribute|yes||<br>
|v3 Magic Armor adds mage guard tag|yes||<br>
|v3 Amor adds mage guard tag|yes||<br>
|v3 Physical Shield text is changed to accommodate Mage Guard:  <br>Affected target gains SL temporary bonus HP against physical damage for 1 round. Any damage the caster takes reduces this HP first.  <br>This bonus HP can exceed his HP max, and if any remains at the end of 1 round then the spell is free to upkeep (the bonus HP refreshes entirely), unless the Caster decides to use Mage Guard, in which case the spell still costs MP to upkeep. If all of the bonus HP is lost by the end of the round then the spell cannot be refreshed via upkeep and must be cast again.|||<br>
|v3 Magic Shield and Elemental shield have the same accommodations for mage guard|||<br>
|v3 adds ward to the alteration spell effects|yes|seems like an oversight (or could be cut off in our table (actually it’s included on the page after conjuration, just a formatting bug|<br>
|v3 adds conjuration school (doesn’t seem to be included in the scroll either)|yes||<br>
|Destruction|||<br>
|v3 Drain [Characteristic] moves the “choose character at purchase” text to the effect column|no|seems silly. It’s a rule, keep it in the rules section|<br>
|v3 Drain [Characteristic] adds a willpower test to resist the effect|no|v3 doesn’t even add that requirement to the spell. The test would make more sense if it were a Direct Attack.|<br>
|v3 Drain [Characteristic] costs is increased to 8 x SL|yes|seems like a reasonable spell cost increase, especially since we’re not having them test|<br>
|v3 Fire, frost, and effects are increased to 2 x SL cost from 1 x SL|yes|if we’re taking the v3 costs, we should take the v3 spell effect costs|<br>
|v3 sunlight is increased to 3 x SL from 2 x SL|yes|if we’re taking the v3 costs, we should take the v3 spell effect costs|<br>
|Illusion|||<br>
|v3 Calm adds the note: “If a character while under this spell’s effect is struck by a Frenzy  <br>effect, than this spell effect is immediately nullified”|yes|good note|<br>
|v3 Frenzy adds the inverse note to calm’s: If a character while under this spell’s effect is struck by a Calm effect,  <br>than this spell effect is immediately nullified|yes|^|<br>
|Mysticism|||<br>
|v3 Absorb magicka always counts as lvl 4|no|We didn’t take this change in the spell either|<br>
|v3 changes cure disease text to read: Affected target removes the Diseased SL Condition  <br>Spell Level 2 = Common  <br>Spell Level 4 = Magical  <br>Note: This effect always counts as being either Spell Level 2 or Spell Level 4.|yes|This is pretty well clarified in v3|<br>
|v3 rejuvinate cost is increase to 25 from 20|yes|if we’re taking the v3 costs, we should take the v3 spell effect costs|<br><br>
<br>Using v2 as base
<br>cap the number of upkeeps at Binding Strength (BS)
<br>BS comes from DoS of the enchanting test rather than Enchant Skill level

<br>Add a talent which adds a minimum BS of Enchant Skill Level


<br>Exclusion list for const enchants — Become Ethereal,
<br>Includes Water Breathing &amp; Water Walking
<br>Add an additional effect for constant enchantments — “Cursed” - the wearer cannot deactivate this enchantment
<br>Add a formula for charges rather than the energy pool/max
<br>Fix the optional rule to read “previous page”
<br>Specify that spell restraint and overload do not apply to enchantment effects
<br>Specify that once an item is enchanted it gains the magic quality
<br><br>
<br>Keep an eye out for weird shit in v3
<br><br>
<br>Use v2 as base, v3 optional rule
<br><br>Mage Guard spell tag does nothing on its own. We add two talents — one that is Journeyman level that gives a flat +1 bonus when you do not spell restrain (not to be confused with overloading), and a second with the previous as a prereq at master level that grants you half your WpB (round up) when you don’t spell restrain<br><br>
<br>Fix the second Haggling for a Bargain in our version to the correct title - Unscrupulous Traders
<br>Remove magic tag from adamantium armor
<br><br>Change the “Utilizing Untrained Weapons/Armor” section to read:<br>
Characters who use Weapons, Armor, or other equipment that they are not trained to use suffer the usual -20 penalty for using an untrained skill on any associated combat tests, movement tests in the case of armor, or any other tests that the GM deems appropriate. The GM may choose to alter or ignore this penalty if they feel the circumstances do not apply.<br>
Then, provide an example where a GM might rule out a penalty.
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/v3-merge-candidates.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/v3 Merge Candidates.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[v3 Merge Finalists]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Add a “Non-Player Character Critical Rolls” section to the “Critical Successes and Failures” Section

<br>1-3 Critical Failure
<br>98-100 Critical Success


<br>Add optional rules for removing wound threshold for those who prefer to play without

<br>Make sure to find all mentions and interactions with wound threshold and define alternatives ✅ 2024-12-03
<br>There are talents specific to Wound Threshold; those should be ported over as optional talents ✅ 2024-12-03


<br>Merge the v3 rules for linguistics (Core Mechanics and Finishing Touches).

<br>Specify that this formula is only for character creation. The character can then seek out learning languages in the greater world, which is up to the GM to determine how this is done.
<br>Check with the GM to gain exotic languages
<br>Add more exotic languages from lore as additional options


<br>Get rid of the ability to gain 4 AP
<br>Specify that power attack can be done with ranged weapons.
<br>Merge the skill level maximum amounts, perhaps changing as we merge them (appears in getting started and Spend CrP sections
<br>Add rules for learning a ritual
<br>Nerf ancestor guardian, ghost should last 30 minutes or disperse after combat if it participates, whichever comes first
<br>Move the Combat Styles section to the skills chapter
<br>Combat senses talent — take BB version? but use 2 x PcB + 2 rather than 3x PcB. Do some IR math, and if we don’t like it just keep our version
<br>AP Refreshing — use v2 version as default. Add an optional rule for “Turn-Based AP Refreshing” and explain how that will work
<br>Fearsome Talent - remove intimidating as a requirement
<br>Add the assassinate talent from the BB
<br>Move the Sneak attack rank from journeyman to apprentice
<br>lower shadow strike to expert level
<br>Change requirement for shadow strike benefit to “if the attack is a melee attack, the<br>
character must forgo the advantage gained by being hidden to use this talent.”<br>

<br>Perfect hit talent - replace<br>
“Master (Perception): The character adds their Perception bonus to the damage dealt by Precision Strike attacks (either melee or ranged).”<br>
To: “Expert (Perception): The character can use their Perception Bonus for the purposes of determining Splitting, Slashing, or Crushing damage in place of their Strength bonus.”<br>

<br>Look at a way to buff the Master Alchemist talent to justify the rank of Master
<br>Merge the Black Book Grandmaster talent
<br>Reduce the Interrogator talent from journeyman to apprentice
<br>Reduce the Unnaturally Agile talent from Master to Expert
<br>Stubborn Talent - Add a restriction of rerolling panic tests only once per test
<br>Fearless Talent

<br>Add a restriction of rerolling horror tests only once per test
<br>Reduce level to Expert


<br>Wall of Steel Talent - Merge the BB version
<br>There were some Conjuring talent notes here, but we should save that for the scroll merge for consistency’s sake. We didn’t have a full conversation around Conjuration talents either
  we wound up<br>

<br>Reduce Depth of Understanding talent to Expert and modify it to add the Power Well Trait (X), where X = IB * 5.
<br>Reduce Force of will to expert level, and rename it to “Magicka Cycling”. Remove Magicka Cycling.
<br>Modify Master of Magicka talent’s prerequisites to be either Force of Will OR depth of understanding.
<br>Remove any mutual exclusivity when it comes to talents involve in the previous three items
<br>Bearded Warrior talent — change it - rather than moving 1m closer, they can yank the target 1m in any direction that doesn’t cause their distance from you to increase.
<br>Beast of Steel Talent - Remove +10 Persuade
<br>Merge the BB Bruiser talent and change the lost stamina requirement to successful DAMAGE, reword If applicable to if chosen
<br>Merge the BB Firing Line talent
<br>Halberdier Talent - Change to: The character can choose to replace his halberd’s Splitting quality with the Crushing quality instead. Additionally, change range to 3m. Additionally, you can spend 1SP to force the rider of a mount to roll Ride(+0) or fall off of their mount, becoming prone. needs flavor text update
<br>Hammerblow talent - Reword to: When the character lands a hit with a warhammer or maul<br>
they can choose to either cause their target to lose one Stamina Point, or make an all-out-attack to force the target to make an Endurance (+0) test. If the target fails this test, they gain the Dazed condition. The target may attempt one Endurance (+10) test on his first turn each round to remove the condition.<br>

<br>Knife Fighter Talent - Add to the beginning “When you use penetrate armor, add a d4 damage”
<br>Monster Hunter - Add support for the remove WT optional rule
<br>Viper’s Eye talent - merge from BB
<br>Point Blank talent - Merge from BB and change the advantage range to the melee range of the target
<br>Red Legion Throw talent - Remove the concept of “Speared”, and just explain what the concept does. Keep the first sentence
  I actually think this is fine as is.<br>

<br>Simple, Yet Effective talent - merge from BB
<br>Staff Master - remove precision strikes sentence
<br>Traits - add the Bleeding (X) trait
<br>Merge Telekinesis trait
<br>Merge Diseases - but only one stage, except for magical diseases.

<br>Add the Blight Disease, and consider adding variants. “Magical Diseases” are the only ones that progress.
<br>And then of course, vampiric and lycanthropic diseases. At stage, curing is no longer simple. GM defined for curing.


<br>In the Special Actions section, add the emphasize text: and can be taken when a character has gained Advantage in combat or as the listed action
  This is already in, but listed first in the sentence<br>

<br>Add the clarifying sentence to the Coup de Grace Attack section: “For Unarmed Coup de Grâce see Grappling rules”
<br>Add the ability to use the Aim secondary action for spellcasting, but only for spells with the “Bolt” form.
<br>Merge the clarification in v3 for Attack of Opportunity following the 2 attack per tern max, but not as verbose. We can just say “still following the 2 attack per round rule” or something of the like.
<br>Take from v3 the combination of the Block, Parry, and Evade sections in the combat chapter into a single chapter
<br>Merge v3’s combination of the take and disarm weapon actions, but separate it a little better.
  Actually chose to go all-in on combining the two, and just opted to call it “Disarm”.<br>

<br>Add the blinded condition to the list of resistible conditions in the resist action
<br>Add the Feint Special Action from v3
<br>Merge v3’s defining of three attack types: Melee Weapon Attacks, Ranged Weapon Attacks, and Cast Magic Attacks
<br>merge v3’s added clarification for counter-attack if both characters pass their tests (Attacking &amp; Defending Step 3)
<br>In Resolve Attack &amp; Advantage, will need an optional rule specifier for non wound threshold rules in Attacking &amp; Defending
<br>merge v3’s added forceful impact as an advantage
<br>Add a critical success/failure section to the Attacking &amp; Defending Section:

If one character critically succeeded, treat it as if they succeeded with more degrees than their opponent (if their opponent succeeded at all). They also gain an advantage. If one character rolls a critical failure, and their opponent passed, then their opponent counts as having critically succeeded. If both sides roll a critical success, then nothing happens.

  This is actually already in, but under Step 3. I say we keep it there as that’s where it belongs in the steps.
  Optional rule for wound threshold removal:

An attack made with a critical success causes a wound to the hit location of the attack.


<br>Remove the rules for item durability - this is being replaced by forceful impact.
<br>There are two “Holding your breath” sections. The second should be “Swinging or Jumping”
<br>Under damage types, use a colon to punctuate the last sentence
<br>In the “Death” section, change “pass an Endurance test each round” to “pass an Endurance test on their turn”.
<br>Optional rule support: Wounds. v3 wound rules trigger on a critical success, rather than Wound Threshold
<br>Optional rule support: In body wound bullet point, add an optional rule blurb for the alternate (v3) refresh rules
<br>Add the following to “Treating Wounds”: Treating a wound related to the Crippled Condition can only be done once per long rest. If this test results in a dramatic failure, the limb immediately becomes Maimed.
<br>Change fatigue to trigger when a character goes BELOW 0 SP , rather, than at 0.
<br>Frenzied bullet point 3 Wound Threshold optional rules support ←?
<br>On organ damage, add a blurb for the alternative wounds system to replace the WT decrease by 1 with -30 passive wound penality from v3.
<br>use v3’s notion of “snapping out of fear” — at the end of the affected character’s turn.
<br>Fix “Inspire Heroism” to read:

Once per round as a free action, the character can make a command test to inspire an ally who can perceive them. When inspired, the ally gains +10 to their next combat test.


<br><br>
<br>Casting Spells &gt; Step 2: Casting Test — expand on how to determine your character’s effective spell level as v3 does, but reword it
<br>Split out the R/M/Direct attacks to individual entries in the attributes list

<br>Specify that M Attacks do not provoke attacks of opportunity


<br>Add the Mindlock(X) spell attribute
<br>Modify the Mage Guard Attribute to only be activated by the new talents (also write the new talents)
<br><br>
<br>Take costs from v3 for the following

<br>Burden
<br>Feather
<br>Jump
<br>Levitate
<br>Lock
<br>Magic Armor
<br>Open
<br>Repair
<br>Shield
<br>Slowfall
<br>[Type] Armor
<br>[Type] Shield
<br>Water Breathing
<br>Water Walking
<br>Ward


<br>Add the (modified) Mage Guard tag to the following

<br>Magic Armor
<br>Magic Shield
<br>Shield
<br>[Type] Armor
<br>[Type] Shield
<br>Ward?


<br>Give Ward the BR instead of flat damage resist from v3
<br>Specify that casting Ward does not provoke attacks of opportunity
<br><br>
<br>Take the v3 summon daedra hunger spell strength
<br>Give Sunder Binding the Direct tag
<br>Take the v3 description for Sunder Binding
<br>Take Conjure Armor spell costs
<br><br>
<br>Chain Lightning - Change Direct tag to R Attack (50m)
<br>Drain [Type] - change from R attack to Direct Attack
<br>Take v3 costs for the following spells

<br>Chain Lightning
<br>Drain [Type]
<br>Drain Magicka
<br>Fatigue
<br>Sunbeam
<br>[Type] Ball
<br>[Type] Bite
<br>[Type] Bolt
<br>[Type] Cloak
<br>[Type] Cone
<br>[Type] Rune
<br>[Type] Storm
<br>Weakness to [Type]
<br>Weakness to Magic


<br><br>
<br>Change Blind from Direct to Direct Attack
<br>Take v3 costs for the following spells

<br>Blind
<br>Calm
<br>Chameleon
<br>Charm
<br>Courage
<br>Frenzy
<br>Horror
<br>Invisibility
<br>Light
<br>Muffle
<br>Panic
<br>Paralyze
<br>Sanctuary
<br>Silence


<br>Change from Direct to Direct Attack for the following

<br>Calm
<br>Charm
<br>Frenzy
<br>Horror
<br>Panic
<br>Paralyze
<br>Silence


<br><br>
<br>Take v3 costs for the following spells

<br>Absorb Life
<br>Detect [Type]
<br>Dispel
<br>Ethereal Form
<br>Mark
<br>Recall
<br>Reflect
<br>Soul Trap
<br>Spell Absorption
<br>Telekinesis
<br>Telepathy


<br>Change from Direct to Direct Attack for the following

<br>Absorb Magicka


<br>Remove overload tag from Absorb Magicka
<br>Change the upper limit on mark to:

The amount of marks a character can keep track of is equal to<br>
their Intelligence Bonus.  


<br><br>
<br>Take v3 costs for the following spells

<br>Cure Paralysis
<br>Cure Disease
<br>Fortify
<br>Heal Ally
<br>Healing Touch
<br>Heal
<br>Rejuvinate
<br>Replenish
<br>Resistance to Type
<br>Resistance to Magic
<br>Stabilize
<br>Turn Undead


<br>Change Ward here to match what was done in Alteration
<br>Including the AOO rule
<br><br>
<br>Add them
<br><br>
<br>Change references to “[Toxin] tag” to read “toxin attribute”?
<br><br>
<br>Pg. 104 - Minor effects look to have been cut off
<br><br>
<br>Remove examples from the big three
<br>Add an addendum to Focus:

The weapon does not increase the range of any spell as a result of its reach


<br>Rename the arrow types to just splitting and slashing
<br>take v3 alchemist table (goes up to 7+), or fix ours if it’s cut off
<br><br><br>
<br>Add the toxin attribute to the list
<br>add the mindlock attribute to the list
<br>Spell out range and melee in the Attack attributes. Also, split these out to match the tags in the spellcasting section
<br>Add the Direct attack tag with the text: “Spell counts as a Attack for the purposes<br>
of the attack per round limit, and also requires a primary<br>
action to cast.<br>
These kinds of spells cannot do damage.”

<br>Add this description to the Spellcasting chapter as well


<br>Add the modified mage guard attribute
<br><br>
<br>Decrease the self form cost to 1
<br>Increase touch form cost to 1
<br>increase target form cost to 4
<br>Add the following text to the target description:

If this spell would alter the the Targets mind, or harm them in any way, this form becomes Direct Attack.


<br>Change the Chain form from Direct to R Attack (50m)
<br>Decrease Cloak form cost to 4
<br>Decrease Pulse form cost to 4 + Z
<br>Add the Bind form from conjuration
<br><br>Alteration<br>
<br>Give the following effects the Mage Guard Spell Attribute

<br>Elemental Armor
<br>Magic Armor
<br>Armor


<br>Physical Shield Text

Affected target gains SL temporary bonus HP against physical damage for 1 round. Any damage the caster takes reduces this HP first.<br>
This bonus HP can exceed the target’s HP max, and if any remains at the end of 1 round then the spell is free to upkeep (the bonus HP refreshes entirely); unless the Caster decides to use Defensive Overload, in which case the spell still costs MP to upkeep. If all of the bonus HP is lost by the end of the round then the spell cannot be refreshed via upkeep and must be cast again.  


<br>Take the v3 accomodations for mage guard for Magic Shield and Elemental Shield as well
<br>Fix the formatting issue with the conjuration page spliiting ward off to the next page
<br>Add conjuration spell effects<br>
Destruction
<br>Increase Drain [Characteristic] cost to 8 x SL
<br>increase Fire, Frost, and Shock effects to 2 x SL
<br>increase sunlight to 3 x SL<br>
Illusion
<br>Add the following to the Calm description:

If a character while under this spell’s effect is struck by a Frenzy effect, than this spell effect is immediately nullified


<br>Add the following to the Frenzy:

If a character while under this spell’s effect is struck by a Calm effect,<br>
than this spell effect is immediately nullified  


<br>Mysticism<br>
none<br>
Restoration<br>
<br>Take the v3 description for Cure Disease
<br>Increase rejuvinate cost to 25
<br><br>Start with the existing text in the latest prerelease doc<br>
<br>Write in a cap to the number of upkeep refreshes to the BS of the enchantment
<br>Have Binding Strength determined from the DoS of the enchanting test rather than the Enchant Skill Level

<br>Write and Add an Enchanting Talent which will make the minimum Binding Strength of a character’s enchantment equal to their Enchanting skill level


<br>In the Constant Enchantments section, specify that Become Ethereal is excluded from the available spell effects
<br>Include Water Breathing and Water Walking as available Constant Enchantments
<br>Add an optional rule for Constant Enchantments - a “Cursed” effect, which means the wearer cannot deactivate the enchantment, and must test Willpower to remove it once per turn.
<br>Write in a formula to calculate the total charges rather than the energy pool maximum. This formula should round down the charges.
  This actually doesn’t work in the case where two spells go into the same cast enchantment. We’ll just have to keep it as is unless someone can come up with an alternative.<br>

<br>Fix the existing optional rule to read “previous page” (or otherwise properly point to the referenced location
<br>Specify that spell restraint and overload do not apply to any enchantment effects
<br>Specify that once an item is enchanted, it gains the Magic Weapon/Armor quality
<br><br>
<br>Use v2 AP refreshing as the base. Then, add an optional rule Called “Turn-Based AP Refreshing” which explains how to implement the v3 version of AP refreshing.
<br>Change Mage Guard to do nothing on it’s own; have it be activated by two talents, which we will create.

<br>Create a Journeyman level talent that gives a flat +1 bonus when you do not spell restrain (not to be confused with overloading) on Spells with Mage Guard
<br>Create a Master level talent with the above as a prereq that grants you half your WpB (round up) when you don’t spell restrain on Spells with Mage Guard


<br>Fix the second Haggling for a Bargain in our version to the correct title: “Unscrupulous Traders”
<br>Remove the Magic tag from Adamantium Armor
<br>Change the “Utilizing Untrained Weapons/Armor” section to read:

Characters who use Weapons, Armor, or other equipment that they are not trained to use suffer the usual -20 penalty for using an untrained skill on any associated combat tests, movement tests in the case of armor, or any other tests that the GM deems appropriate. The GM may choose to alter or ignore this penalty if they feel the circumstances do not apply.

  Then, provide an example where a GM might rule out a penalty.<br>

<br>Specify that the aim action only applies to spells with the bolt form.
<br>Change “Dovah” to “Dovahzul” in languages
<br>specify in the Replenish description that one cannot give more Magicka than they spend
<br>We should probably specify that only one effect can be used for an enchantment unless the enchanter has the manifold enchanter talent
<br>Organize Summon Daedra table using the following priorities: Level, Cost, Spell Strength, Name
<br>For living armor, add limit of 1 effect rather than all, and rename to Living Armory.
<br>For Weapon echo, make the first attack with the weapon echo a free action, then all subsequent attacks are done with 1 AP. (Still subject to attack limit)
<br>Seasoned Conjurer - take the BB version
<br>Taskmaster &amp; Master of the Hordes - take the BB version
<br>Quickref

<br>Group hit locations, advantages, defense resolutions, and spending stamina into a section (misc combat?)
<br>Nix spell attribs (from v2 ref)
<br>Grouping Restoring hp and wounds tables from v2 quickref
<br>Character Advancement Tables
<br>Luck


<br>GM quickref

<br>Item/Weapon Quality Modifiers
<br>Item Availability and Qualities
<br>Loot tables?
<br>Backfire tables
<br>Horror/fear tables
<br>Commerce section
<br>Rests
<br>travel pace
<br>Difficulty Table
<br>NPC Crits


<br>Optional Luck Section? Where tf did that go?
<br>Modify the Feint Special Action to be a Primary Action, then change to the following rules:

A character attempts a Combat Style test against an opponent's Observe within a 2m range. If successful, they treat their next melee attack against the target as if they were Hidden. This effect only applies if the attack occurs before the end of the character's next turn.

  This is already in the changelog, so just modify that changelog entry.
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/v3-merge-finalists.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4/v3 Merge Finalists.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 04:57:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023-12-02- Scroll of Undeath, Oblivion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>SoO

<br>Traits from SoO

<br>From Beyond - specify that they’re immune to toxins, not non-damaging poisons
<br>Bite becomes a weapon quality called “Binding”, and should be worded generically so it can be used by any weapon.

<br>Give this quality to the khajiit bite attacks


<br>Nix Magic Resistant Trait
<br>Merge Quadruped
<br>Do not merge the following traits (will be for Inhabitants of Tamriel)

<br>Minion
<br>Savage
<br>Teamwork
<br>Thick Skull
<br>Unrelenting
<br>Weak Point
<br>Natural Armor




<br>Rituals from SoO

<br>Modify the following paragraph

If the circle is imperfect, the Daedra is summoned unbound,<br>
and is free to cross the threshold and murder the conjurer and<br>
everyone in the immediate area.  

  to also specify that the creature cannot be subjugated<br>

<br>Rite of Princely Summoning

<br>Remove elite keyword, specify that it can’t be taken at character creation


<br>Rite of the Creation of Flesh

<br>Modify harvesting test to be a -20 alchemy test limited by lore




<br>Enchanting for Conjuration (SoO pg 13)

<br>Take the Weapon/Armor rules as-is, the summoning rules are fixed by our misc changes




<br>SoU

<br>Necromancy

<br>Limit enchanting tests by Necromancy skill when using black soul gems
<br>Spells

<br>Recheck that costs are consistent with uncon
<br>Reanimation: specify that it is up to the size of the spell str

<br>Creatures are reanimated with full HP, Full SP, Full MP, Full AP, and any uses of limited use abilities
<br>Add traits to the list of what they retain.
<br>Specify that they do not retain powers gained from their race
<br>Specify that creatures turn to a pile of ash and cannot be reanimated when they die after they are reanimated or the spell is not upkept.


<br>Summon Ghost

<br>Reduce duration to 1 round and cost to 12
<br>Add a lvl 3 version that summons Ancient Ghost and costs 16 MP&lt; post a question to it


<br>Summon Wraith

<br>Reduce duration to 1 round and cost to 18
<br>Add a lvl 5 version that summons gloom wraith and costs 22 MP. Keep mindlock 2


<br>Add them to spell effects




<br>Rituals

<br>Rites of Undeath

<br>specify action type for adding new order (Second)
<br>Give context for the henchman rule
<br>merge them with following considerations

<br>Bonewalker

<br>Specify SL 5 or higher


<br>Bonelord

<br>say that it knows up to six spells that you yourself know.
<br>Binding words must be to guard a specific location and cannot be issued additional commands not directly relevant to guarding that location




<br>paragraph that reads

A Necromancer can repair any of his undead to full<br>
HP with a simple 30 minute ritual using supplies worth<br>
a number of drakes equal to the HP healed.  

  should be at the top level<br>



<br>Ritual of Necromantic Transcendance

<br>Specify that incantation test is also made at +10
<br>Cannot be taken at CC


<br>Ritual of Soul Sight

<br>On fail, the ritual cannot be reattempted for 7 days


<br>Ritual of Mortal Transference

<br>Specify that it can’t be taken at CC
<br>Specify +0 Necromancy skill test in 1st paragraph
<br>Dire quality should be magic quality
<br>Specify that it requires a chalice worth at least 500 Drakes


<br>Soulsnare

<br>Specify that it can’t be taken at CC


<br>Rite of Unlife

<br>Successfully completing these rites requires passing a -20 Necromancy skill test (say “a single”)


<br>Elite advance lich

<br>Bring in from BB:

<br>Dark Sight
<br>Skeletal Claws
<br>Dark Ceremony








<br>Misc

<br>Highest speed out of your speed types is your maximum movement budget for a turn
<br>You can mix and match movement types, up to their individual budget, until you reach your turn’s maximum movement budget.
<br>Cap number of upkeeps at one instead of BS
<br>Specify that Conjuration or necromancy effects cannot be used for constant enchantments
<br>Specify that mindlock is still paid by caster in cast enchants


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2023-12-02-scroll-of-undeath,-oblivion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2023-12-02- Scroll of Undeath, Oblivion.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 23:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023-12-09- Wonders of the Ayleids]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Ayleid Playable Race

<br>Dropping the Colovian Variant


<br>Ayleid Equipment

<br>White-Gold Artificer EA
<br>Talents

<br>Consider making these exclusive to WGA


<br>Ayleid Stone Rituals
<br>Ayleid Trinkets and Devices


<br>Flesh Magic

<br>Pain Sorc EA


<br>Elite Advances Chapter

<br>Key Points

<br>No CC
<br>Optional - GM discretion
<br>Advice for introducing into a campaign


<br>Within this chapter lies the path to extraordinary power and legendary prowess, where characters transcend beyond their already formidable abilities. These Elite Advances are not mere steps in a character's journey, but leaps into realms of almost mythic capabilities.  
  It's crucial to note that Elite Advances are not intended for character creation. They represent a level of power and knowledge that is typically beyond the reach of novice or even intermediate adventurers. These advanced paths are optional and are best introduced thoughtfully and sparingly. As a Game Master (GM), you should consider the inclusion of Elite Advances on a per-character basis, ensuring that it aligns well with the character's development, the narrative, and the overall balance of your campaign.  
  Moreover, we strongly encourage introducing Elite Advances through the rich tapestry of the game's narrative. These extraordinary powers should feel like an integral part of the world your players are exploring. As a GM, weave these opportunities into your story, allowing characters to discover and pursue them through their in-game actions and choices. This approach not only enhances the immersion but also maintains the organic flow of the story.  
  Elite Advances should feel like hard-earned rewards or significant milestones in a character's journey. Whether it's uncovering ancient secrets, undergoing rigorous training, or being chosen by the gods, the path to these powers should be as memorable as the abilities themselves.  
  As you venture into this chapter, consider the impact and possibilities these Elite Advances bring. They are tools to elevate your campaign and provide your players with experiences that are truly legendary.


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2023-12-09-wonders-of-the-ayleids.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2023-12-09- Wonders of the Ayleids.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:37:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Things to Cover]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Orc and Sload talents - WAY too much HP. 13 HP will steamroll
<br><a data-href="3e v4.a4.0 Feedback" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/3e-v4.a4.0-feedback.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">3e v4.a4.0 Feedback</a>
<br>Review Spell Tags
<br>Book of Circles

<br>Weapons and Equipment
<br>Talents

<br>Retiarus

<br>split out the net portion (1st paragraph)
<br>Change the name since (some reason)




<br>[ ] Expanded Crafting (incl. equipment modifications section)

<br>[ ] Modifications + Reforging go under crafting
<br>[ ] Smithing Services go under goods and services
<br>[ ] Equipment Modifications in Appendix


<br>Shehai


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-01-13.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-01-13.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:59:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crafting]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Runed Weapons/Armor should specify that the enchantment test cannot be repeated on failure
<br>Merge SoO Daedric Weapons &amp; Armor as-is
<br>Make Runed Weapons/Armor, Repairing Weapons/Armor, and Daedric Weapons/Armor have their own sections
<br>Rather than refer to calculating the cost in the last step, just refer to the items cost found in chapter 7
<br><br>
<br>Modifications

<br>Don’t merge, add it to the beta docket


<br>Reforging

<br>Save it for the beta


<br>Smithing Services

<br>Save it for the beta


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-01-27.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-01-27.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-02-03]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Go over common potion costs
<br>Finish Pain Sorc
<br>[ ]
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-02-03.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-02-03.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-02-10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Merge BoC Weapon Talents

<br>‘Tis but a scratch<br>
Goes wherever berserker is  

The character can channel their frenzy to ignore debilitating wounds.<br>
Expert (Endurance), Requires Berserker<br>
While the character is frenzied, they ignore the Passive Effects of Wounds, and any Crippled or Lost Limb/Body Conditions that they gain during this frenzy. These effects are immediately applied as normal once the character loses the Frenzied condition.  


<br>Kensai - as-is, in Weaponry
<br>Daisho - as-is, in Weaponry
<br>Retiarius becomes “From Oblivion’s Heart” (capt. ahab ref)

_To the last I grapple with thee; from Oblivion's heart I stab at thee; for hate's sake I spit my last breath at thee.  
_Expert (Strength)<br>
Should an attack made by the character with a trident inflict a wound, the enemy gains the Bleeding(1) condition regardless of the shock test. Additionally, any Trident the character wields gains the Thrown (5/10/20) quality. If a thrown attack with this weapon hits the target, the attack counts as having the Entangling quality, except it can be blocked, and inflicts damage as normal.  


<br>Riposte - as-is, but fix the reference to the “Dueling Weapon” Quality
<br>The Whirling School - as-is, minus the last paragraph (re: wrapping around neck)
<br>Rain of Steel - becomes “Slinger’s Wail”

The character’s missile sings at it flies through the air; a note of imminent death inciting terror in your enemies.<br>
Expert (Agility)<br>
When the character attacks while Hidden, characters who are unaware of them within the weapon’s short range must make a +0 Panic test.  


<br>Pugilist - take it as-is, but remove agility from gov. char.
<br>Rip and Tear - Taking the first + second sentences, ignore the third, fourth sentence remove the requirement to spend SP.


<br>Merge She Hai
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-02-10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-02-10.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 01:00:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-02-25]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Shehai

<br>Techniques
<br>Talents
<br>Shehai


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-02-25.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-02-25.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 01:05:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-03-02]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Wonders of Ayleids paired quality
<br>Bleeding condition - profession medicine test to staunch bleeding (maybe by DoS?)
<br>Shehai Shen She Ru

<br>Talents
  Shehai Effects Talent

<br>Rename “Blinding” effect to “Radiant”

The character can, as a free action, change the composition of his Shehai. When he does this, the blade glows brightly and hits with the Shehai deal Sunlight damage.


<br>Remove “Cleaving”

<br>Rename “Proven” to “Tested”
<br>Change “Soul Rending” to simply reduce WT by 1
<br>Remove Stable (no swords have Unwieldy anymore)
<br>Change Tearing to read: Attacks that do damage apply the Bleeding(1) condition
<br>Thirsting: Change Savage to “Proven” quality, Have not has
<br>For the effects which change the damage type (incl sunlight), modify them to require a secondary cast magic action

<br>Add an expert talent, called “Prismatic Blade” which allows switching those effects as a free action.






<br>Shehai
  Merge the Shehai as-is, but increase the second level penalty to -30, and the third level to -60


<br>Scroll of Thu’um
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-03-02.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-03-02.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 01:24:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-03-10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Big 3 elite advance costs should be consistent, all should be 1000/1500XP
<br>Thu’um

<br>Skill
<br>Learning Words of Power

<br>Note on the skill that a test may not be required if the character already has dovahzul as a language
<br>Fix the wording on the Learning Words of Power formula


<br>Using the Thu’um

<br>remove the last sentence of the second paragraph
<br>Last paragraph

<br>Remove the first sentence
<br>Bold and modify the text:

Once a character uses a Shout, they may not<br>
use that Shout again for a number of rounds equal to<br>
the number of words used in the Shout.<br>
To read:<br>
Once a character uses a Shout, they may not<br>
use that Shout again until after a number of rounds equal to<br>
the number of words used in the Shout.  






<br>Shouting

<br>Step 1

<br>Remove the last sentence and clarify that the character must use a shout they know in the first sentence




<br>Talents

<br>Voice of the ancients<br>
Remove all text after “however, to those not initiated”<br>
Add rules which allow the character speak with their full voice to gain +20 on intimidation tests made while doing so. In combat, they can use a Secondary Action and 1 SP to force all characters who can hear them clearly to make an Endurance test. Those who fail gain the Dazed condition until the end of their next turn.<br>
Increase the Talent Rank to Master


<br>Shouts

<br>In general, the third words that further double the range need to specify “double an additional time”.
<br>Modify Aura whisper to say apply Unnatural Senses “Creatures” instead of Living Things

<br>Fix flavor text


<br>Modify Become Ethereal to end the effect as a free action

<br>Remove Incorporeal condition, instead specify that the character cannot affect or be affected by any attacks, spell effects, or other aspects of the physical world while the shout is active. The character can move through the world as if they had the Incorporeal trait, including gaining the Flyer(Speed) Trait.


<br>Cure Disease

<br>Modify second word to increase range to 200m


<br>Cyclone

<br>First Word<br>
Change range to to 1m. All ranged attacks that pass through the affected area, including the character’s, are made at -10.
<br>Second Word

<br>reduce damage 1d8 Crushing(1)
<br>increase affect area to 2m
<br>Increase Ranged Attack penalty to -20


<br>Third Word

<br>Reduce damage to 1d12 Crushing(2)
<br>Increase Ranged Attack penalty to -30




<br>Decoy

<br>Change to “Creates an illusory representation of the character…”


<br>Disarm

<br>Change 3rd word to match the presentation of the other similar 3rd words


<br>Dismay

<br>First word

<br>Reducing range to 15m.


<br>Third Word

<br>change to require that the character forfeit the bonuses from both the 2nd and 3rd word.








<br>Herma’s Talent suggestion for spell talent:

<br>Practice spells

_The Mage has Acquired a set of spells that use just the barest of magics to initiate the barest of effects<br>
_Journeyman (Willpower)<br>
The character can invoke any spell the character knows to induce minor effects, like using fire to start some tinder, ice to cool their drink, Conjuring inconsequential utensils, or putting out a calming aura. Spells used in this way require a +0 test of the school the spell belongs to, and the cost is reduced to 1 MP.




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-03-10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-03-10.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-03-17]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Shouts

<br>Dragonrend

<br>move to legendary
<br>Modify to "compel the dragon to land as soon as possible using however much movement or AP required to do so." They still lose the SP. 
<br>Make the time start when the dragon lands


<br>Drain vitality

<br>add "also" to the second word
<br>2nd word - add "or remaining Magicka" in case the creature has less than 20
<br>3rd word - specify that the character heals the amount of damage dealt.


<br>Frost AND Fire Breath

<br>Damage steps from: 1 - 1d8, 2 - 2d8, 3 - 4d8
<br>Remove damage mitigation bypass rule


<br>Fleshrend

<br>change damage dice to 1 - 1d8, 2 - 1d10, 3 - 1d12
<br>words 1, 2, and 3 deal bleeding 1, 2, and 3 respectively
<br>Modify base difficulty to +0


<br>Ice Form

<br>Ice form - modify "check" to "test"
<br>Change stun condition to paralyzed, remove the part about "effects that would allow them to..."
<br>Change 3rd word to -30


<br>Lightning Blast

<br> step damage as follows: 1 - 2d4, 2 - 3d4, 3 - 5d4
<br>have each word increase AR/MR ignorance by 1: 3, 2: 5, 3: 7


<br>Restore Life

<br>modify "the Blood Loss" to read "passive wound effects"
<br>modify base difficulty to +0, and stepped difficulty to -30
<br>word 1: 2d6, word 2: 4d6, word 3 as-is


<br>Restore Magicka

<br>Modify values to a flat 15, 30, 45
<br>make it also able to target others


<br>Slow Time

<br>Keep the amount of max AP and Attacks you get consistent (+1) through all 3 words
<br>1st word = until end of next turn, 2nd word = 4 rounds
<br>3rd word as-is


<br>Storm Call

<br>Damage steps: 1 - 1d8, 2 - 2d8, 3 - 4d8
<br>Give the storm a 200m radius
<br>Once per round the character may, as a free action, command the storm to strike a specific target within the storm radius. This command is resolved as a Direct Attack which counts toward the character's attacks per round limit. At the end of each round, if the character has not commanded the storm this round the storm will attack a random character within the storm's radius.


<br>Unrelenting Force

<br>Change to a 3m wide, 15m long beam.
<br>Remove stun, use dazed condition
<br>Damage becomes 3d6 (3rd)
<br>Base difficulty is -10


<br>Whirlwind Sprint

<br>+10 to the base difficulty
<br>Add to the first word that the movement does not provoke AoO.
<br>Other actions cannot be performed during this movement. 




<br>The Whisper Problem

<br>Write a paragraph which specifies that all shouts are audible within a 50m radius or the affected radius, whichever is larger. If the shout is tagged as a Whisper, the Tongue may choose to make the shout only audible within 1m instead.
<br>Tag Throw Voice, Aura Whisper, and Shadow Form as Whisper.


<br>The Cone Problem

<br>Remove all instances of reference to degrees on the cones.


<br>The Retreat Problem

<br>Specify "voluntary" movement on pg 92


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-03-17.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-03-17.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 03:36:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-03-24]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Cover spell absorption stacking
<br>Trait Stacking

<br>Write a short rule stating that traits do not stack unless otherwise specified, and X values take the highest.<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240324202635.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240324202635.png">
<br>Traits with  values - a different value of  is considered a distinct trait, so all instances apply.
<br>Traits Changes to Make

<br>Resistance and Weakness - remove instances of saying they stack, double check racial traits to make sure they are consistent
<br>Remove second paragraph (that we added) from Spell Absorption (X)
<br>Telepathy can now stack 




<br>Reduce Sunder Binding Costs - change the cost to 1 x SL in the effects, propagate to the conventional spells
<br>Ritual cost in character creation/advancement XP tables (25 XP) - add it
<br>Instances of both "Hit Points" and "Health Points"

<br>Going with "Health Points"


<br>Remove the note that mentions the 100XP minimum for Char advances. both char creation and advancement.
<br>Discuss whether Languages can be purchased and how, or how else.

<br>"Throughout the course of the game, Characters that wish to pursue learning languages can do so. Please discuss with your GM on ways to do this."


<br>Change from "Effective Spell Level" to "Spellcasting Level" w/ crossref
<br>Cover Legendary Thu'um

<br>Bend will

<br>1 + 2nd words, add the word "reasonable" to the first sentence.
<br>2nd word, make the Wp test a +10 test
<br>3rd word, make the Wp test a -10


<br>Call of Valor

<br>Heroes of Sovngarde

<br>Power Attack is still using old PA rules. Change to match current rules.
<br>Move the "Summoned" rules to the Shout.
<br>Remove Warrior-Spirit
<br>Variants

<br>Mage of Sovngarde

<br>Fix "Ward Bolt"
<br>Give it Power Well (20)


<br>Greater Hero of Sovngarde

<br>Rename "Tough" to "Hardy"
<br>"Uses either the Hero or the Mage of Sovngarde as a base"






<br>The Shout

<br>Specify in the first word "Hero or Mage of Sovngarde"
<br>2nd Word - Typo, "Greater  Hero"
<br>Change the difficulty. Keep base, change incremental to -20




<br>Dragon Aspect

<br>Add an asterisk that states that the shout can only be used successfully once per long rest.
<br>Add "Natural Toughness (3)" to the second word


<br>Form Change

<br>Make it a whisper shout
<br>Difficulty - 0 base, -20 incremental


<br>Earthen March

<br>Remove "at the cost of slowing them" in the flavor text and the penalty to the word
<br>Change difficulties to -20 base, -20 incremental


<br>Song of Destiny

<br>"Prophesy" &gt; "Prophecy"
<br>As we merge this one, pay close attention and edit for clarity, consistency, and readability
<br>Also reduce max AP by 1 while singing


<br>Soul Tear

<br>1st word - Choose targets equal to WpB. If target dies within 1m, fill soul gem (word like soul trap) 
<br>2nd word - Halve the targets' HP Maximum for 1 min. If a targets current hp is higher than this new max, reduce their current HP to their max. Once this effect wears off, the Current HP remains at the value.
<br>3rd word - If the character dies during the shout's duration, the corpse rises for 5 minutes


<br>Words of Surety

<br>Make it a Whisper




<br>Thu'um Rituals

<br>The Knotted Tongue

<br>Cannot be used for Legendary Shouts
<br>Remove from the flavor text "making it a tool to strengthen those already strong in the Voice"
<br>Regardless of the results of the test, the ritual ingredients are consumed except for the tongue itself.




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-03-24.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-03-24.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 03:14:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240324202635.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240324202635.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-03-31]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Discuss a way to determine the attack tag for spell creation/uncon

<br>The target form handles this pretty well. We'll probably just want to apply that to all forms.


<br>"Page 21 of the v4 PDF says each item ENC is halved in a container, but page 172 of the PDF says containers halve the effective value of the ENC within them. The former implies the ENC is halved by item, the later implies the total ENC in the bag is halved. This is the difference between a Large Backpack with 20 items of ENC 1 having an effective ENC of 2(for the bag itself) plus 2(for 20 effectively ENC 0 items) or 2 plus 10."
<br>"Alfiq, Phamar, and Senche Quadruped trait says they triple run speed when Dashing. But page 86 says Quadrupeds move twice their speed when Dashing and Triple when Sprinting."
<br>Typo in Slash n Stash talent
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-03-31.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-03-31.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 23:33:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-04-14]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>cover: 

The Conjure Weapon spell effect is different between Chapter 6 and the Appendix. Chapter 6 contains the V2 version of the spell, the level determines the weapon profile (Inferior, Common, Superior). The Appendix contains a modified version of the V3 version of the spell. The weapon is created with a damage modifier equal to SL-1. No mention of weapon profiles.


<br>Costs look different as well


<br>cover Dart Thrower talent affecting darts
<br>note from sigma

<br>Drain [Characteristic] in chapter 6 specifies that the bonus the caster receives only affects tests that use the same characteristic, while in the appendix it simply states the caster gains the bonus for the duration of the spell. Important b/c the former rules out the possibility of affecting attributes.
<br>Also worth noting that this is the only effect I've read that states "for the duration of the spell" every other effect seems to just state "for 1 round" "for 1 minute" or "for SL minutes"


<br>Consider "Drain Char" becoming "Absorb Char"

<br>Also, this is in desto but maybe should be myticism


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-04-14.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-04-14.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:55:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-04-28]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Change alfiq to halve CR, not ENC
<br>Change Regaining SP section to use the proper rules found in Long Rest section
<br>Talk about necromancy backfires (or lack thereof)
<br>Damaged quality - AR AND MR
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-04-28.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-04-28.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:13:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-05-19]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>BB Warden Elite Advance
<br>Specify that natural weapons cannot be enchanted
<br>Damaged quality should also reduce MR
<br>Look at inconsistency between applying toxins and potions
<br>pg. 65 of v4.a4.1: modify the sentence Combat Styles may encompass up to five different types of equipment to start. to specify that these 5 types of equipment are only added when the skill is purchased for the first time.
<br>Dagi Raht power well description doesn't match the 20 PW it's given
<br>Talk about the Pain Sorc Attack problem. Consider how other EAs deal with abilities and attacks as well.
<br>re-roll vs reroll
<br>Statblocks kick-off

<br>Variants

<br>Small changes to stats or otherwise insignificant changes, consider dropping the variant
<br>Additions to abilities and significant additions to traits should be their own statblocks 
<br>Variants which contribute well to the book but make minor changes that are easily referenced can still exist in their own variants


<br>Tuna's suggestion of info to add to statblocks

<br>Treasure type: a type added to the statblocks that defines the treasure table

<br>loot section
<br>Treasure table for each current supplement with creatures


<br>% chance in lair: did the players stumble across the creature in its home or its lair?

<br>encountering this creature, sandbox subsection


<br>number appearing: how large is the avg. group? 2d6, etc

<br>encountering this creature, sandbox subsection


<br>Morale: chance that the creatures bail on the encounter if bad thing happen

<br>d100 TN, on Attribs






]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-05-19.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-05-19.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 04:22:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-05-26]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-05-26.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-05-26.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 23:10:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decisions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Discuss a talent for conjuration restraint
<br>Feedback

<br>Sword Singer 3rd talent typo (says second shehai)
<br>pg. 187 rite of unlife "then hey"
<br>Shouldn't learning from a trainer be easier? maybe this is the tradeoff for having a physical book vs being taught. Maybe -1 training days or something.
<br>pg. 200 - Master of the voice, should replace prudent voice?
<br>consider giving leeching vines a 1 round duration and the Upkeep tag


<br><br>
<br>Dropping the optional sandbox section, but keeping morale. We decided that it needed more support and would fit better in a GM guide than in the IoT supplement.
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-06-02.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-06-02.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:22:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-06-16]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>allow power attack for crossbows/arbalests?<br>
no
<br>double check that we fixed master of the voice
<br>found by @azzoicEnnead: On pages 13 and 46, while explaining characteristics Willpower Bonus is abbreviated to WB.  This is also used on pages 79 (Arcane Defender), 89 (Telepathy trait), 188 (Ayleid Bondage), and 189 (Trollblood).  However, Willpower Bonus is abbreviated as WpB on pages 15 (Wound Threshold), 38 (Alfiq Telepathy trait description), 49 (Calculate Attributes section), 78 (Weapon Echo), 80 (Master of the Hordes and The Mending Tides of Oblivion), 89 (Telekinesis trait), 128-130+133+221+223 (Overload damage bonuses), 187 (Dark Ceremony), 189 (Flesh Blade), 197 (Tested and Tearing effects), 200 (Voice of the Ancients), 206 (Form Change and Earthen March), 207 (Soul Tear), and 212 (Leeching Vines).  WpB is more common than WB but WB is used in both sections that I'd expect to set the abbreviation, so I'm not sure which is intended. There are also a few talents that write out [characteristic] bonus, which is fine but the capitalization of "bonus" isn't consistent. Also, Rite of Mortal Transference's second paragraph (page 144) is missing a number:
<br>clarify that chain form is caster's choice
<br>Whats up with summon daedra removing bound trait on failure? Last paragraph. After discussion in chat: remove the retest 1/minute 
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-06-16.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-06-16.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 23:41:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-07-07]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Zuka's Questions:

<br>Inconsistent style choice between usage of "character" or "creature"

<br>stick with character


<br>Wants to add soul gems to loot pools of dwemer animunculi

<br>sure, why not?


<br>Minion trait - how will it be presented?

<br>We should remove it from statblocks and add a section explaining the mechanic at the start of the book, describing when and how it might be used

<br>maybe do this with others?






<br>Project Plan:

<br>Alpha:

<br>Inhabitants of Tamriel:

<br>Finish individually assigned statblocks by July 21st
<br>Create the indesign document for the Inhabitants
<br>Review and Merge the individual assigned work


<br>Tamrielic Artifacts:

<br>Recreate the idd doc
<br>Brush of True Paint isn't on the TOC
<br>Numbers Checks - look for underpowered/overpowered

<br>Dremora will look into this


<br>Tools of Kagrenac
<br>Standing Stones


<br>Rules Compendium:

<br>Finish warden (the summoning spell)
<br>Any minor fixes that come up




<br>Beta:

<br>Vampirism

<br>Statblock(s)


<br>Lycanthropy

<br>Statblock(s)


<br>Shadow magic
<br>Dragons
<br>Crafting Rework
<br>Prerelease &amp; Open Playtesting
<br>Formatting
<br>Release




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-07-07.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-07-07.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:13:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-07-14]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-07-14.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-07-14.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 22:07:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-07-22]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Core Racial Talents and Magical Disease header not showing up ✅ 2024-07-21
<br>Review the Introduction Chapter, what it should be called, and what sections we need ✅ 2024-07-21
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-07-22.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-07-22.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 03:20:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-07-28]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Better rule for diseased trait ✅ 2024-07-28
<br>Check into defender, consider raising range to 2m ✅ 2024-07-28
<br>Talk about Blight, whether to add in beta ✅ 2024-07-28

<br>yes - use tuna's doc as a starting point


<br>Changed Weak Point to a trait with the changed rules ✅ 2024-07-28
<br>Shouldn't we have the Quick Draw talent only reduce drink potion to 1 AP rather than no AP? Essentially, it shouldn't be included in the first part of the verbiage. ✅ 2024-07-28
<br>Advantages - most are attack only, let's just say that. Also, let's give overextend to all defenders ✅ 2024-07-28
<br>Power attack - specify "before damage, after test" ✅ 2024-07-28
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-07-28.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-07-28.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 05:28:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-08-18]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Scroll of People Notes ✅ 2024-09-15

<br>Spells on Agent were incorrectly copied ✅ 2024-09-15


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-08-18.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-08-18.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 01:33:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-08-25]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Now that SoB is merged, fix Warden ✅ 2024-09-15
<br>New verbiage for the shield (flesh) spells ✅ 2024-09-15<br>
Target character within 50m of the caster gains a magical barrier that envelopes them and protects against physical damage for 1 round. Any damage the caster takes reduces the barrier's HP first.<br>
This barrier's HP does not belong to the target, but rather is the HP of the barrier before it breaks. If any of the barrier's HP remains at the end of the duration, then the spell does not cost MP to upkeep and the barrier's HP refreshes entirely. Otherwise, if all the HP of the barrier is lost at the end of the duration, then the spell cannot be refreshed via upkeep and must be cast again.
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-08-25.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-08-25.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 03:13:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-09-08]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Look at nettleburns feedback on the dispel strike enchant ✅ 2024-09-15
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/archive/2024-09-08.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/Archive/2024-09-08.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 03:13:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-09-22]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Under Aim action: <img alt="Pasted image 20240919112749.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240919112749.png"> ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>change "or fire the aiming" to "or fire the aimed". 
<br>Add a sentence at the end to clarify that, once fired, the bonuses from the Aim action are reset.


<br>Add a chart for damage die steps to the Rules Compendium ✅ 2024-10-13
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-09-22.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-09-22.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:10:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240919112749.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240919112749.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-09-29]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Treasure Tables ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>Look at Tuna's Guide to Loot


<br>Final Once-Over of IoT ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>Bear's Maul ability needs 1 AP added to the cost I think ✅ 2024-09-29
<br>Same as above but for Rat Leap on the rats ✅ 2024-09-29
<br>For the ~Loot section on Bears, you can either choose the make "two pieces of full bear fur armor or one full bear fur chest." I think we should change this to "two limb pieces of bear fur armor or one full bear fur chest" for clarity ✅ 2024-09-29
<br>Lamia spells overflowed by one line to right column -Wolf needs an assigned moral ✅ 2024-09-29
<br>Disease carriers might need to be changed


<br>Kickoff Tamrielic Artifacts ✅ 2024-10-13
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-09-29.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-09-29.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:08:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-10-06]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Cover Defensive Overload ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>rename? reinforce + bolster are current candidates.


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-10-06.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-10-06.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:08:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-10-20]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Continue <a data-href="Ideas and Things to Look At" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/ideas-and-things-to-look-at.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ideas and Things to Look At</a> and  <a data-href="Balance-Tweak Considerations" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/balance-tweak-considerations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Balance-Tweak Considerations</a> ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Finish the starting section of the dragons chapter ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Take a look at the following statblocks' attributes: ✅ 2024-10-20

<br>Crusader (speed too fast?) ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Pilgrim and slave (speed incorrect?) ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>bonelord and bonewalker (speed to slow?) ✅ 2024-10-20


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-10-20.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-10-20.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:39:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-11-03]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Clarify intent for the "Weakened Immune System" Character Trait, specifically to do with the Resistance to Disease trait. ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>Talk about and finalize conversations related to upkeep from this week.

<br>Specify that spells with the upkeep attribute that do not have a listed duration cannot be upkept if a different spell has been cast since the original cast. Maybe clarify that the old instance of the spell effect doesn't continue into the new instance of the upkept spell ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>Add the upkeep attribute back to the Fatigue spell and review any others that previously had upkeep and were removed due to not having a listed duration. ✅ 2024-11-03

<br>Fatigue ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>Water Walking - remove from constant text ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>Water Breathing - remove from constant text ✅ 2024-11-03




<br>ENC

<br>Specify that the backpacks themselves do not halve their ENC (in Ch 1 Items &amp; Encumbrance and the other spot that that paragraph appears, probably ch 7)

<br>Specify that the contained ENC is halved (round down)


<br>Make sure the Armor Attributes section mentions that ENC halving rounds down for clarity


<br>Consider adding a general rule on rounding. Probably down, unless otherwise specified
<br>Burden and similar spells. might consider specifying that they can stack considering they don't have much use case without stacking ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>Review TA changes and finalize for final alpha
<br>Fixes ✅ 2024-11-03

<br>Invis + Feather need to be marked as lvl 4 in the spell effects instead of 5 ✅ 2024-11-03


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-11-03.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-11-03.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 23:58:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-11-10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Vampirism Approach

<br>In flavor text, talk about how vampires not connected to clans struggle to survive without things like the rituals for blood potions and thralls.
<br>Base Vampirism should be much simpler than history uesrpg which is based on oblivion + skyrim, instead opting for daggerfall (morrowind-ish) inspo.

<br>Gain Weaknesses
<br>Gain Strengths
<br>Must feed on one creature with a black soul per day, if you do not then you cannot gain the benefits of a short or long rest

<br>blood potions important in this




<br>Thralls

<br>Vampire Thrall Ritual: By feeding your Vampiric Blood to a target with a Willpower less than the Vampire allows the Vampire to Enthrall them. Doing so calls for a +0 Willpower test from the Target, if they fail they become completely under the control of the Vampire. If they succeed, they become immune to enthrallment for a week. Thralls half their Intelligence Scores while enthralled and lose the ability to think more critically. Following the orders of their Vampire Master to the letter, with little to no nuance. A Dispel Effect of 5th level or higher breaks the Enthrallment A Vampire can only have a number of Thralls equal to their WpB or PsB (whichever is higher)

<br>Work out ritual aspects of above
<br>maybe have a hemomancy or nox arcana test in the ritual




<br>Work out blood potion ritual
<br>Bloodlines - gained from your vampiric "parent" (no darker paths test)

<br>base vampires get a passive based on their bloodline
<br>an EA talent can be picked up for some bloodline specific talent 
<br>keep sanguiphage


<br>New Dawn-Cursed(X): X * 3 damage per round if uncovered, or X per hour if properly covered

<br>1 is base, 2 is EA, 3 is VL


<br>Nox Arcana + Hemomancy not talent for opp. cost, instead use the RAW in tuna's doc for learning the abilities and make the skill available for anyone with the EA


<br>In Elite advances section, talk about the fact that the path to power with some exception is through magic. martial who want to advance into EAs will need to start to stat into casting characters
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-11-10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-11-10.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 01:46:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-11-17]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Cover whirling school talent ✅ 2024-11-17

<br>From Sigma: "I'm a bit confused with the Bola's talent. The Whirling School give the Bola the Impaling quality, but the Impaling quality necessitates that the weapon deals at least 1 damage in order to stop the target. The Bola doesn't do any damage.<br>
The other part of the talent allows the character to use the Trip action as a reaction to anyone moving in the Bola's short range. Isn't this already possible since Tripping is a Secondary action and the Bola possesses the Snare quality? Or does movement not count as a threat or event as stated in the Reactions paragraph? Am I missing something here?"


<br>undead fortitude: Use only the last sentence, reduce rank to adept ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>Nox Arcana and Hemomancy go under Vampiric Secrets, the associated skills must be learned for the first time in character, but then can be advanced for XP. ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>Nox Arcana ✅ 2024-11-21

<br>Shrouding mist should simply reduce the X value of Dawn-Cursed ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>Bat form - refer to actual tiny size benefits ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>Night Cloak - ✅ 2024-11-17

<br>Change to 1d6 poison ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>reduce radius to 2m ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>specify that the damage occurs at the end of the vampire's turn ✅ 2024-11-17
<br>specify total damage dealt for HP regain. take away upkeep ✅ 2024-11-17




<br>Hemomancy ✅ 2024-11-21

<br>Hemomancy spells cannot benefit from restraint ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Vampiric drain should cost 11 MP ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Blood Grasp - remove restrained condition, make it so that this forced movement can provoke AoO ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Sanguine Shield - the shield should function as if it had sun-scarred 5, cannot regain health, remove upkeep ✅ 2024-11-21


<br>make it so the master level of the nox and hemo skills are mutually exclusive ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Reduce warden to 750 XP cost, 1000 XP for non ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Vampire Lord

<br>change the "sanguiphage" requirement to feeding on vampire lord ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>Dawn-Cursed becomes 3 ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>Reduce Evolved wings to flyer (movement speed) ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>Blood of Bal -- Essentially make this improve the enthralling rite ✅ 2024-11-23

<br>Reduce vampire's DoS threshold to 10 DoS (the target's is unchanged) ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>take the 6+ dispel requirement ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>make it so you can see through the eyes and hear through as the old one works ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>make it Wp governed ✅ 2024-11-23
<br>Thralls do not take int penalty ✅ 2024-11-23


<br>For "Legendary" Nox and Hemo spells, also put them in the secrets section but specify that they can only be cast by VLs and must have master rank in the associated skill ✅ 2024-11-22
<br>Crimson Sphere - increase AP cost to 3 ✅ 2024-11-21
<br>Consuming Blast - increase MP cost to 16 MP ✅ 2024-11-22
<br>Change black shadow to summoning a gloomwraith for 2 SP ✅ 2024-11-22


<br>Fix the Gloom Wraith in IoT ✅ 2024-11-21
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-11-17.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-11-17.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 10:12:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-11-24]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Talk about dragon damage mitigation ✅ 2024-11-24

<br>Just upped the AR of all dragons


<br>Lycanthropy Rules

<br>Transformation and Feeding

<br>You may transform once per day, if you do you make a Willpower test with a -5 penalty for each day since the last transformation in which you had a sufficient feeding. Upon failure, you become feral and are hostile to all nearby creatures until you have sufficiently fed. Sufficiently feeding requires that the lycanthrope consume the equivalent of at least two standard-sized creatures or the heart of a creature with a black soul, both of which must have been killed by the lycanthrope during this transformation.
<br>Make consuming the corpse of a creature take 2 AP as an extended secondary action to consume a killed creature, gaining the creature's EB HP. 3 AP to consume the heart of a black soul creature, gaining the creature's EB x 2 HP.
<br>On a full moon, the lycanthrope is forced to transform and automatically fails their transformation Willpower test regardless of if they already transformed that day.
<br>Transformations last 6 hours. The lycanthrope can attempt to end the transformation early by spending 3 AP and passing a Wp test. This test gains a -10 for each attempt after the first and an additional -10 penalty if the lycanthrope has not sufficiently fed during this transformation.


<br>Attribute bonuses:<br>
- in order: str, end, ag, prc<br>
- Wolf: 5, 5, 10, 10<br>
- Boar: 5, 15, 5, 5<br>
- Bear: 10, 10, 5, 5
<br>New traits in normal form:

<br>Silver-Scarred (2)
<br>Immune (Disease)
<br>Wolf - Natural Toughness (2) (wolf) 
<br>Bear - Natural Toughness (3) (bear)
<br>Boar - Natural Toughness (4) (boar)
<br>Restless: The character only restores half the health and stamina they normally would when resting. 


<br>Fighting as the Beast

<br>restore up to max + 2 SP
<br>increase max HP by 10 (but not current)
<br>Silver-Scarred and Natural Toughness both double
<br>All gear is dropped, all worn gear gains the Damaged (1) quality
<br>Dark Sight
<br>Quadruped
<br>Strong Jaws trait
<br>Halve jumping penalties
<br>Wolf

<br>Natural Weapons (Fangs, 1d8 Splitting)
<br>Natural Weapons (Claws, 1d10 Slashing)
<br>Gains the "Latch On" Stamina Ability (1 SP): If the creature successfully Bites a target which results in a grapple, it latches on with all its strength, and the bitten Hit Location counts as Crippled. This lasts until the grapple is broken.


<br>Bear

<br>Natural Weapons (Fangs, 1d10 Splitting or Crushing)
<br>Natural Weapons (Claws, 1d12 Slashing or Crushing)
<br>Gains the "Maul" Stamina Ability (1 AP + 2 SP): The bear performs a melee attack as a primary action that deals 2d8 Crushing damage to a target creature within 1 meter. Additionally, all creatures within reach that are Medium or smaller must succeed on an Acrobatics or Athletics test or be knocked prone.


<br>Boar

<br>Natural Weapons (Tusks, 1d8 Slashing)
<br>Natural Weapons (Claws, 1d10 Slashing)
<br>Gains the "Gore" Stamina Ability (1 SP): &nbsp;As part of a successfully damaging attack with their tusks, the wereboar can spend a Stamina Point to immediately deal a bonus SB damage.




<br>New Skill: Bestial Instinct (Str, Ag, Prc)

<br>Covers unarmed CS, evade, survival, stealth, athletics, acrobatics, navigate and observe. Apply the governing characteristic associate with the specific test being made.
<br>Ranks cannot be purchased with XP, instead granted by talents. Starts at Apprentice.


<br>New Artifacts:

<br>Ring of Hircine: 

<br>is not dropped or damaged on transformation
<br>Wearer automatically passes the Wp transformation test, and the test to end the transformation
<br>For lycanthropes, the wearer is no longer limited on their transformations per day.
<br>For non-lycanthropes, allows the wearer to transform into a lycanthrope at will. Which form is chosen when the wearer transforms for the first time.


<br>The Ring of Bloodlust

<br>While in beast form, bite and claw attacks inflict +4 damage
<br>All Wp tests associated with transformations suffer an additional -10 penalty
<br>is not dropped or damaged on transformation


<br>Ring of Instinct

<br>+10 to Bestial Instinct tests
<br>is not dropped or damaged on transformation


<br>Ring of the Hunt

<br>While in beast form, wearer gains Regeneration (2) and gains +2 HP when feeding
<br>is not dropped or damaged on transformation






]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-11-24.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-11-24.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 05:26:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-12-01]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Discuss Dagger Sneak Attack Bleed Talent- "successful sneak attacks with daggers apply bleeding (1), and any damage dealt with a dagger against an opponent with the bleeding (x) condition applies an additional bleeding (1)". Would be master and require sneak attack ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Discuss new katana talent - would require daisho and be master - "If you successfully deal damage with a katana or a wakizashi, you apply bleeding(1) to the target" ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Discuss a way to make a berserker build more viable. Perhaps controlled anger should avoid the SP loss after leaving the condition. ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Talk about dispel and how it shouldn't unsummon creatures ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Sling talent doesn't mention the sling ✅ 2024-11-30

<br>


<br>Ring of Khajiiti should not grant the invisible condition inherently, should be an enchant instead. ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Talk about the Ag/Burning condition problem - maybe Str OR Ag? ✅ 2024-12-01
<br>Discuss Lycanthropy EA

<br>Use from Tuna

<br>From tuna - get rid of or replace call of the pack ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>As Sharp as my Spear ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Thrill of the Chase ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Add strength to govn chars
<br>make it once per round


<br>Aspect of Strength ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Aspect of Guile ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>this aspect becomes the combination of aspect of speed and aspect of guile, no other changes


<br>Blessed Hide ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>rename to Hide of the Boar ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Replace effect with "can reroll tests made to resist magic once per test" and give them Thick Skull trait, but still grant skill increase ✅ 2024-12-14


<br>Ursine Might ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Rename to Might of the Bear ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>keep it, reword it ✅ 2024-12-14


<br>Call of the Pack ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>rename to Call of the Wolf ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>replace effect with "once per day, can howl to cause all who can hear within 20m to make a +10 panic test" ✅ 2024-12-14


<br>Enhanced Instinct ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Increase the bestial instinct skill by 1 ✅ 2024-12-14




<br>Use from Darker Paths ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Take Sharpened Claws as-is ✅ 2024-12-14


<br>New Talents ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Gorging Feast ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>FT: "You do not allow a single morsel of flesh to go wasted on your kills, even stripping the flesh off of wiry tendons and cracking bones for their marrow."
<br>HP gained from feeding is doubled


<br>aspect of tenacity ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>"the ability to outlast and wear down the prey"
<br>Increase Natural Toughness by 2, penalties from passive wounds effects are halved. Also increases current HP by 10 on transformation. ✅ 2024-12-14


<br>Bestial Dominance ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>make it increase the bestial instinct spell


<br>One With The Beast ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>+10 bonus to tests associated with transformation in and out of beast form. Additionally, can test Wp as normal to resist going feral when transforming as a result of the full moon. ✅ 2024-12-14






]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-12-01.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-12-01.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:32:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-12-08]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Character sheet, make more room for armor notes, can take away from conditions and/or wounds
<br>Lycanthropy EA passives ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Dark sight in normal form ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>+10 to Wp tests related to transform into and out of beast form. ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>You gain the Savage trait in beast form ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Increase Bestial Instinct skill by 1 ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Passives ✅ 2024-12-14

<br>Werewolf: Unnatural Senses (Smell, 3) in normal form and (Smell, 6) in beast form ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Wereboar: Tough (3) in both forms ✅ 2024-12-14
<br>Werebear: Vicious (SB + 2) both forms ✅ 2024-12-14




<br>Define Degrees of Failure: To calculate Degrees of Failure, simply add 1 to the difference between the tens digit of the result of your failed test and the tens digit of the target number. So if you failed with a 56 against a target number of 30, you scored 3 degrees of failure. ✅ 2024-12-15
<br>Shadow Magic Changes From sigma's port

<br>Purchase Requirement: 400 XP + Adept Lore + Shadow Magic Spec ✅ 2025-01-19
<br>Correction: There is no limit on to how much CR you can dedicate to a spell or ritual. ✅ 2025-01-19
<br>Remove; Additionally, if they roll doubles (11, 22, 33...), the power triggers a minor disharmony. If the character fails by more degrees of failure than his Willpower bonus and also rolls doubles, or simply rolls a critical failure, the power triggers a major disharmony. For Disharmonies, see page 7. ✅ 2025-01-19
<br>Add: On crit failure, a major disharmony is triggered. On crit success, no disharmony regardless of CR expenditure. If no disharmony would be trigged, add TBD CR to the cast of the spell. ✅ 2025-01-19
<br>Spells:

<br>Rename spells back to powers
<br>Invisibility

<br>Becomes Vanish
<br>condition is lost under same circumstances as the invis spell
<br>should be rounds, not minutes
<br>50 XP 


<br>MIrror Image

<br>Add that they can see through the eyes, hear through the ears, and speak from the mouth of the mirror image.
<br>100 XP


<br>Shadow Drain: 

<br>make the damage Shadow Damage, add the Shadow damage type


<br>Shadow Sight: 

<br>Change N to Y, otherwise unchanged


<br>Shadow Weapon

<br>While summoned, the weapon is considered part of the characters combat style
<br>Make the material bonus 3
<br>Make the damage gained from the big three Shadow Damage, and the value for the quality should be CR
<br>100 XP




<br>Rituals:

<br>Bind Shadow Weapon: completely remove in favor of a ritual which binds an existing weapon to the character, making it so that weapon can be summoned and unsummoned at will. The character and the bound weapon are intrinsically linked, casting the ritual again with a different weapon replaces the previously bound weapon, which is lost to the shadow planes. If a daedric artifact is attempted to be bound, then the associated daedric prince might intervene.
<br>Shadow Gate: 75 XP




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-12-08.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-12-08.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 23:56:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-12-15]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Shadow Magic

<br>Shadow Magic Acquisition Rituals (to get the elite advance):

<br>Adding three rituals: Rite of Insight (Prs), Rite of Perception (Prc), Rite of Knowledge (Int). Double check the names, and the ritual infuses the character with the shadow of the nature of the ritual. The chosen ritual determines what characteristic governs shadow magic. ✅ 2025-01-19

<br>Rite of Dark Conspiracy ✅ 2025-01-19

<br>isolation
<br>Circle of Polished Obsidian Mirrors - require a -20 lore test to set up the mirrors appropriately
<br>Within the CoM, destroy an object or creature of personal import. You witness the other versions of yourself performing the same ritual through the mirrors.
<br>Opposed Prs test against your own base Prs to convince the other versions of yourselves to your cause, that you are all worthy of each other. 
<br>On a failure, the shadows abandon the character, and the character gains a +10 bonus to the next attempt of the ritual.
<br>On a success, you gain Shadow Magic governed by Prs


<br>Rite of Penumbric Insight ✅ 2025-01-19

<br>Isolation
<br>Perform at a site of a conflict which includes a decisive and pivotal moment, identified by a -20 lore test
<br>requires the character have a tattoo of an eye using ink made of obsidian dust and the consumption of a rare hallucinogen of some kind
<br>Opposed Prc test against your own base Prc to witness an alternate ending of the conflict amongst the shadows whilst ignoring your own perception of the world around you and of your hallucinations.
<br>The ritual takes 1 week to complete. The character can eat to sustain themselves during this time.
<br>On a failure, the tattooed eye closes, requiring a new tattoo on the next attempt, and the hallucinogen's effects wear off. and gain a +10 bonus to the next attempt of the ritual.
<br>On a success, you gain Shadow Magic governed by Prc


<br>Rite of Secret Knowledge ✅ 2025-01-19

<br>Requires Isolation
<br>Requires the creation of a special book over the course of a week, the covers of which are crafted from polished obsidian, and the pages bound by the hair of a creature with a black soul. Also requires the use of ink which is mixed with a small amount of your own blood, which deals 1 damage.
<br>Make -20 lore test to correctly inscribe your understanding of Shadow Magic into the book
<br>A book which other versions of yourself are also writing into, and each version is simultaneously trying to glean knowledge of shadow magic while obfuscating the knowledge to inhibit the work of the others.
<br>Opposed Int with your own base Int. The succeeding version claims the book
<br>On a failure, the book is taken by the victor. You gain a +10 bonus to the next attempt
<br>On a success, you gain shadow magic governed by Int






<br>Continue Review

<br>Review rituals from 2e supplement from Shadow Double and on

<br>Shadow Double: 8 Hours - increase XP to 300 XP, specify that the character is brought over with none of their belongings
<br>Shadow Portal as-is
<br>Shadow Scry as-is
<br>Shadow Walk - 100 XP - have the GM roll the test in secret, specify that they have to send a willing or helpless character






]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-12-15.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-12-15.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:52:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024-12-22]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>
Shadow Magic

<br>Continue Review ✅ 2024-12-22

<br>Review Talents from Sigma's version and the book, probably adding back in the ones removed re: handed casting ✅ 2024-12-22
<br>Review the disharmony Tables ✅ 2024-12-22
<br>Port the Sliver of Umbraketh and the shadow horror ✅ 2024-12-22


<br>Revisit

<br>Spells

<br>Foreboding: Remove or Rework

<br>As a secondary action, when the character uses this power, the next successful attack made against them has its DoS reduced by the CR committed when this power was used. If this would reduce the attacker’s degrees of success to zero or lower, the attacker counts as having failed the attack test. This effect lasts until the character's next long rest.
<br>Keep XP cost and difficulty the same


<br>Shadow Meld: Talk about removing it, if we don't remove it make it not stack with the fortify spell ❌ 2024-12-22


<br>Port the Shadow Horror, consider it with the summon spell balance-wise

<br>Using Zuka's statblocks

<br>Shadow Horror

<br>No Soul ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Up WT to 15 ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Change tendril damage to 1d10 and nix entangling ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Use our verbiage for frightening ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Remove Bestial ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Change to say "Mysticism or Illusion ingredient" ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Make a second weapon, "Grasping tendrils", give it entangling ✅ 2025-01-07


<br>Sliver of Umbra-Keth

<br>No Soul ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>change HP to 160 ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Penumbric Tendrils: remove entangling ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Add grasping tendrils as above ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Shadows from Beyond: only snuff Natural lights, not magic lights ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Change the fear trait to +0 horror + panic ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Natural Toughness (8) ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>Spell reflect, change to "2", correct "Spell is resolved against" ✅ 2025-01-07
<br>loot -- mysticism and illusion, change to a Skein of Conflict, make it a Legendary ingredient ✅ 2025-01-07




<br>With spell, remove the +20; add mindlock (appropriate value), give it the summoned and bound traits






<br>
Take a look at turn undead suggestion and undead morale ✅ 2024-12-22

<br>
Fix goblin shaman focus focus

<br>
Notes from last week's shadow magic talk after james left: Keep as-is aside from what is recommended below.<br>
Note: should be no d5 rolls, instead d4 or some other die value for disharmony tables.
Minor Disharmony:<br>
36-38: change from terrifying(-10) to Frightening (-10) trait.<br>
42-44: Maybe list a duration to effects of casting shadows. Lose 1 stamina point instead of gaining a level of fatigue.<br>
45-47: Specify panic test instead of fear test.<br>
51-53: Specify "thrown in a random direction by 1d10 meters"<br>
54-56: Panic Test instead of fear test.<br>
63-65: Lose 1d4 stamina points instead of gaining levels of fatigue.<br>
66-68: Panic Test instead of fear test.
Major Disharmony:<br>
0-5: Panic test (-20) instead of fear test.<br>
10-13: Panic Test (-30) instead of fear.<br>
14-18: 1d10 frost damage instead of 3d10 +5<br>
25-30: change willpower to the stat that is used with Shadow Magic (Prs, prc, int). Specify at the beginning of each round.<br>
31-38: specify minute duration instead of 2d10 rounds.<br>
39-46: d8 damage instead of 2d10+5<br>
47-55: Test Horror (+0) instead of Fear test.<br>
56-61: reduce effect duration to 1 minute instead of five.<br>
62-67: the horror is summoned for a minute instead of 2d10 rounds.<br>
68-72: d6 damage instead of 2d10.<br>
73-78: Horror Test (-20) instead of fear.<br>
79-82: 2d6 damage instead of 4d10.<br>
91-96: change willpower to the stat that is used with Shadow Magic (Prs, prc, int). Change 3d10 to 30 days.
Note: Sliver of Umbra'keth should be very scary!

<br>
Talents:

<br>Change Willpower characteristic to the governing characteristic of Shadow Magic.
<br>Re-add Abriged Congruence and Mental congruence talents (or decide ultimately if Spell Sword/Though Caster should apply. If included, Mental Congruence should be Master rank to match Thought Caster.)
<br>Cut Shadow Caster talent entirely.
<br>Shadow Sense: "Powers or Rituals" instead of Spells or Rituals/Powers (Sigma's/2e)
<br>Harmonic Safeguards: Use Sigma's version and revise as needed.


<br>
Blight Diseases

<br>Using <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.google.com/document/d/18Ni8a5ZiYssr7yQ9rNdMyF0h_QjRiLTw5B-QAYmMD4I/edit?tab=t.0" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/18Ni8a5ZiYssr7yQ9rNdMyF0h_QjRiLTw5B-QAYmMD4I/edit?tab=t.0" target="_blank">Tuna's</a> as a Base

<br>Have a subsection section for Blight Diseases in magical diseases section

<br>Disease Progression

<br>Each blight disease has an entry for its Gestation, which is a combination of a length of time and a difficulty modifier. When the disease's current stage gestation period has passed, the character must succeed an Endurance test at the start of each day using the listed difficulty modifier. On a failure, the disease progresses to the next stage.


<br>Individual Diseases, unchanged unless otherwise noted, generally keeping Gestation and effects only

<br>Ash Woe

<br>Difficulty: -10


<br>Ash Chancre

<br>Difficulty: -10


<br>Black-Heart Blight

<br>Difficulty: -10
<br>Change each stage's second effect to Lose 5 End, 10 end, and 15 End respectively


<br>Chanthrax Blight

<br>Difficulty: -15
<br>Change the first stage's second effect to -1 Max Speed










]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2024-12-22.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2024-12-22.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 23:58:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-01-05]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Vampire Statblocks ✅ 2025-01-06

<br>Vampire Thrall
<br>Vampire Fledgling
<br>Vampire
<br>Master Vampire
<br>Vampire Lord


<br>Lycanthrope Statblocks ✅ 2025-01-17

<br>Werewolf
<br>Werewolf Vargr
<br>Wereboar
<br>Wereboar Gore-Tusk
<br>Werebear
<br>Werebear Brute


<br>Reword the bit in combat styles about the "nobleperson": ✅ 2024-12-25

<br>"For example, a noble who is used to fighting honorable one-on-one duels is forced into a chaotic bar-brawl."


<br>In the targe rules, specify that the free hand is only for those listed. "free hand, but only for" ✅ 2024-12-25
<br>Go take a look at recent feedback in #3e-general and #3ev4-development , discuss merit ✅ 2025-01-05
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-01-05.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-01-05.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:24:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-01-12]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Find and implement the actual Shehais of each level in CH 8. ✅ 2025-01-12
<br>Rite of Motion is not showing up in the ToC
<br>Consider an optional rule for only spending gold on spells ✅ 2025-01-12
<br>Finish lycanthropy statblocks
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-01-12.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-01-12.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-02-02]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Add the From Beyond Trait
<br>fix the spell refresh abilities
<br>Shadow Strike should be limited to attacks that inflict damage
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-02-02.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-02-02.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:34:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-02-09]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Executioner needs to specify that the bonus is only to axes and scimitars
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-02-09.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-02-09.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 23:55:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-03-02]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Finish Shadow Magic @ Rituals
<br>Merge Shadow Magic Statblocks
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-03-02.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-03-02.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 09:07:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2025-03-09]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Instant tags, write the cast magics to incorporate
<br>TA: eleidon's ward needs charges, like chrysamere
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/vc-notes/2025-03-09.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/VC Notes/2025-03-09.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:16:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Core Packs]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Birth Signs
<br>Standard Skills ✅ 2024-11-24
<br>Exotic Skills
<br>Core Races

<br>review for latest v4 rules ✅ 2024-11-25
<br>Review values ✅ 2024-12-03


<br>Expanded Races ✅ 2024-12-03
<br>automate racial choices
<br>Talents

<br>In progress - finished through Racial (not yet extended)


<br><br>
<br>Move into the system ✅ 2024-11-24
<br><br>
<br>Automate penalty selection during birthsign flow ✅ 2024-11-25
<br>Automate Racial Choices
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/foundry-migration.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Foundry Migration.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 03:16:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ideas and Things to Look At]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>~Add optional rules for Luck Point replenishment where the GM rewards LP based on “Important/significant Character Moments”.~ ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>~Move detailed Stamina Point rules to the combat section of the book, leaving behind a passage informing the reader that SP is important for a martial character’s build and where to reference the detailed rules.~ ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Review the idea that you must spend at least 1 AP on your turn. Not much reason for that that we can see at this point. ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>~Review how disease procs from diseased creatures, potentially forcing the diseases endurance test when the creature gains advantage rather than on a wound.~ ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>~Make a Reaction keyword for spells, rather than cast magic as a secondary action.~ ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Review the following spellcasting talents: ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>Depth of Understanding
<br>Magicka Cycling


<br>Consider moving the “Unusual Combat Scenarios” Section to after the Ranged combat section ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>~Consider splitting out attack spell attributes into their own entries~ ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Panic/Horror Tables - Removed as it falls outside the scope of what we’re trying to do with this project ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>Herma’s proposal

<br>Reverse the order of tables so that the severe effects are on the lower end
<br>Use the roll to resist as the rolled effect.

  The goal is to incentivize not only throwing out as many tests as possible, but also cast higher levels of Fear Spells<br>

<br>Counterpoint: fear is not only triggered by magical attacks, but also for frightening situations.


<br>Consider removing the Upkeep attribute from the Drain Magicka and Fatigue spells, and their related effects. ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Review the Magic Armor Quality and how it interacts with the Incorporeal Trait and other traits that might affect it (Ghost). ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Consider removing the idea of “Bodkin” and “Broadhead” arrows. Just call them slashing/splitting. ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Potential Fix for magicka Cycling - from Herma: - review this ✅ 2024-10-13<br>
”so, MY main problem with magicka cycling is that it makes unconventional WAY to worth it. Once you get magicka cycling (cause the other alternative is basically useless at higher levels of play) there is NO reason mechanically to not do uncon, you cant backfire twice. Which is why i would do several things.  

<br>Make multiple different sources of backfiring stack. Essentially, if there is one way you were to backfire its a d4, then two is d6, then three is d8 and so on. Making it actually a punishment to double down on backfiring.
<br>Make magicka cycling not as good, this is kinda hard to do without nerfing it into oblivion or making it a static bonus to restrain. I would do one of several things for it.<br>
a. Make the bonus to restrain equal to your IntB instead of doubling restrain. this makes you have to focus more into both stats if you want more restrain and doesnt double the bonuses from talents.<br>
b. Add your WpB modifier again. This would basically just nock it down by 2-4 points, removing the doubling from talents.<br>
c. If those arnt harsh enough add half WpB, or IntB. Still a significant boost for a mage, but not as game breaking.  
<br>Make the Alternative better. One of the reasons magicka cycling is the best choice for your average mage is that the other option doesn’t scale. You have a chance to not expend magicka on a fail, that's planing to fail. When you get your TN up to 100 then its completely useless. So I would change it to something different. Honestly I don't know what without changing some fundamental things about how magic works.

  Me and Mephala talked about if the restrain systems was altered. Basically for our new system instead of restraining you would prepay for how long you wish for a spell to be cast, in doing this we could make two separate trees for mages to go into. One based around restrain to make spells as cheap to come by, and one for big costly spells that would refund magicka if you ended the duration early.”<br>

<br>Consider that special actions should be locked behind 1m distance ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Consider changing the Blind special action to apply the “Partially Blind” condition, rather than the full effects of blindness. (-15, -30 respectively) ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Consider using a specific spell as the example for the Effect Durations section in the Spellcasting Chapter ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Take a look at the incomplete “Unarmed Coup de Grace” from the errata ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Review the Falling Damage wording for clarity/balance. ✅ 2024-10-13
<br>Necromancy Backfires ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Take a look at frenzy condition. Why use the frenzy spell if it only attacks their enemies? Consider modifying the condition to say “attack all” and the berserker talent to somehow specify that the frenzied condition only forces you to attack someone else ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Review conjuration backfire effect 6-7 ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider adding, near the armor class section, that if a wearable item, spell, or effect doesn't specify that it provides an armor class, than it does not modify the existing armor class. ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>If we wind up taking the Forceful impact advantage over Item Durability, then we’ll need to “remove the last sentence of the Forceful Impact bullet point” as per the BB ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Review soul gem prices ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider adding an option rule to use v3 wound rules (removing WT) ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Talk about how the magic armor spell stacks against existing armor ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>we should also mention that quickdraw allows poison application as a free action as well ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider adding learning languages to character advancement, with the ‘cost’: “Learned during downtime from books or a teacher” ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Look at specialization examples for illusion ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider drastically lowering the cost of rations. 10g, potentially ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Review the salaries of laborers ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider highlighting words and phrases that indicate specific mechanics (don’t break our backs over it though) ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>IMPORTANT: Review end of round effects - remove step 5 in combat steps, and consider using start/end of next turn instead (or use 1 round according to effect durations). ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>A slight buff to sneak attack (and potentially assassinate, depending) is worth a chat ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Idea from Dagoth.wav (generally well received, promote discussion when we’re at this stage): ✅ 2024-10-20

As for movement advantages, what about something like Overwhelm: your attack (or defense) engages all the opponent's attention allowing the next ally to move by your opponent do so without provoking AoOs.


<br>Make it so 0 SP has no effect, and fatigue starts at -1 SP ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>If we remove ability to get 4AP we need to get rid of Smart Fighter and Nimble talents ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Maybe boost Magica gain on short rests? ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Take a look at coup de grace ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Change constant fortify attrib from +5 to +2 ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>take a look at minute long durations ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Consider bestial conjuration (grab from eyg). Flavor — from Hircine’s realm? ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>See below image for AoO modification/rules, except modify approach to read “immediately after” rather than “when” ✅ 2024-10-20<br>
<img alt="Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Images/Untitled.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled.png">
<br>Discuss the potential for adding ranged advantage ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Just in case we haven’t already added this — consider applying a skill level maximum only to CS, Evade, and Magic skills ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>In “Spending Stamina” in Chapter 1, we need to clarify how frequently stamina points can be used. “cannot spend for more than one effect per player turn” suggests you can spend stamina on your turn and as a reaction on someone else’s turn, but “they can either modify an action on their turn, or a reaction on an opponent’s turn” specifically doesn’t allow that. ✅ 2024-10-20<br>
Better wording would be “cannot spend for more than one effect per round”  
<br>Increase price of quarterstaff ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>With size basically any +10 hits apply to both melee and ranged ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Change Cure Disease to a single lvl 3 spell that only removes common disease, and add special considerations to diseases that we want to be considered “magical” ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Eygrima Rules for combat ✅ 2024-11-08
<br>Specify that damage from multiple sources are not totaled for the purposes of calculating damage for wounds. This would be best done by changing the wording of wounds to read “Damage from a single source” rather than “Damage from an attack”. Additionally, in the strike enchantments, specify that total damage from the enchantment is considered a single source. Look for other instances where specifying that damage is from a single source would help with rules clarity. Lastly, specify in the wounds section that, if multiple damage types would cause a wound, apply the effect type that did the most damage. If equal, then GM fiat. ✅ 2024-10-20

<br>Edition change, not rule change

<br>Wording on this: “Physical Damage (such as the Big Three) and Magical damage (Fire, Poison, etc.) should be considered separate for the purposes of determining if the attack results in a Wound. If there are multiple types of damage in a single roll, then the maximum damage amount determines the Shock effect of the Wound.”




<br>Counter-Attack rules definition in Ch 5, Attacking &amp; Defending section could use some cleanup ✅ 2024-10-20<br>
<img alt="Screenshot_20221008_180431.jpg" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/assets/screenshot_20221008_180431.jpg">
<br>The wording for enchanting scrolls needs to be reviewed. The 2nd step in which magicka is spent for the spell that the scroll is being enchanted with does not seem to understand how spell restraint works in the first place. ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Implement an XP advice section and potentially a basic XP activity table example
<br>Rename all instances of CrP to XP, and specify anything that can only be purchased in character creation (namely PhB character traits and spells during character creation). ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Idea for untrained armor: -5 untrained penalty for limbs and head, -10 for body. These stack if multiple untrained pieces are worn.
<br>Talk about moving a magic damage wound effect (under Wounds &gt; Shock Test) to a fourth effect. Current ideas: ✅ 2024-10-20

<br>Frost is moved to a fourth effect, and the character gains the slowed condition for a round
<br>Poison damage could damage tests to some degree


<br>Combine abilities of NPCs which use multi-target melee attacks with a common rule: ✅ 2024-10-20

**Multi-target Melee Attacks  
**Some special abilities call for characters to make a melee attack against multiple enemies in a single action. One attack roll should be made against all targets, then each defender reacts separately. They may only defend with Block or Evade, as such attacks cleave through parry and counter-attack attempts. Damage is rolled separately for each target, and the attacker cannot benefit from advantages gained during this attack.


<br>On the subject of multi-target attacks and resolving advantage: ✅ 2024-10-20

If we make it so the attacker can only gain one advantage, we should make it so that if the attacker fails, only one defender can get a defensive advantage. And it kinda makes sense-you attempted to attack multiple people but failed and so the first defender stops the attack from continuing on. That way a multi attack won't absolute fuck the attacker should they fail.<br>
-Dagoth.wav  




<br>Review and improve the suggestions for Skill Specializations ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Revisit Alchemy: “in potion making you dont get the +1 to the skill thingy for what level potion making you can do without penalty(…) it needs a few things to flesh it out, like using more than one ingredient for 1 effect” (Herma) ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Suggestion from Gay Mer Girl:
  Point-buy variant rule where, rather than only being able to put up to 20 points in any one characteristic, you instead can't increase any of your characteristics past 50 (before birthsigns and CrP)
  This encourages build diversity by letting any race start with a 50 in their main stat. The tradeoff is that it makes race choice matter less. Making it a variant rule would let individual tables decide whether or not they want to make that tradeoff
  Race balance is bad for mages right now, because the only way to start with 50 willpower is to play a Breton. If any race could point-buy up to a 50, Bretons would no longer automatically be the best choice for any mage build<br>

<br>Discuss and add crit bonuses for enchanting, alchemy, and other crafting tests. ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Swim speed penalties per armor type ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Just in case we haven’t actually written this stuff down: ✅ 2024-10-20<br>
<img alt="Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Misc/Images/Untitled 1.png" src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled-1.png">
<br>Character creation quickref ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Hunger’s Daedric Poison ability should specify that the damage ignores armor ✅ 2024-10-20
<br>Dark seducer’s seducer’s touch should ✅ 2024-10-20
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/ideas-and-things-to-look-at.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Ideas and Things to Look At.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:11:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/misc/images/untitled.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Proofreading]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>
From the Bound trait, “creators” should be “creator’s”

<br>
In the Toxins section: “brewn” isn’t a word; it’s “brewed”. Search other potential instances of this too. ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>
Talent - Killing Blow: change from ✅ 2024-10-13

When the character spends a Stamina point to make a power attack, he adds three times the amount of stamina spent to a maximum of 3SP for +9 damage. 

to:    

When the character spends a Stamina point to make a power attack, they add 3 times the amount of stamina spent to a maximum of 3 SP for +9 damage.


<br>
Unusual Combat Scenarios → Climbing: “all of this combat skill tests…” ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>
From Dagoth: An immediate concern for enchanting that aggravated me when i first read thru the book is that in the section about binding strength, it tell you what binding strength is without telling you what it is i.e. it gives the flavor text without informing you that BS = DOS achieved on the enchant test to make the item (V3) or = the enchanter's skill rank (V2). These explanations comes at the very end of the fast enchantment section ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>
Forgot size on character sheet ✅ 2024-10-13

]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/proofreading.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/Proofreading.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:01:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alpha]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is the project plan that will take us from the v4.a4.2 prelease version of the system to final release.<br><br><br>
<br>1- ⏳ 2024-07-21 (Dremora, Graybeard, Zuka, Herma) Finish the individually assigned statblocks (<a data-href="(Alpha) Inhabitants of Tamriel" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/(alpha)-inhabitants-of-tamriel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">(Alpha) Inhabitants of Tamriel</a>)
<br>2- ⏳ 2024-07-21 Create the Indesign Document
<br>3- Review and Merge the work from step 1. ✅ 2024-09-22
<br>4- Write Chapter 1 ✅ 2024-10-13

<br>Anatomy of a Statblock ✅ 2024-09-22
<br>Designing Combat Encounters ✅ 2024-09-22


<br><br>
<br>1- Recreate the Indesign Document ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>2- ⏳ (Dremora) Numbers Checks - look for underpowered/overpowered rules ✅ 2024-07-14

<br><a data-href="Tamrielic Artifacts Notes" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/collab/tamrielic-artifacts-notes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tamrielic Artifacts Notes</a>


<br>3- Add the Tools of Kegrenac ✅ 2024-11-10
<br>4- Add Standing Stones ✅ 2024-11-10
<br><br>
<br>1- Finish the warden EA (Summoning Spell) ✅ 2024-09-07
<br>2- Review all pending feedback and determine action to be taken, if any ✅ 2024-11-03
<br>3- Minor Fixes ✅ 2024-10-13
<br><br><br>
<br>1- Vampirism

<br>Links:

<br>Tuna's Vampirism: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1jTKvn0uHkCFZ_MGE5PhUWC6LKqvVfm0Gybc_g2XCMFQ/edit?tab=t.0" target="_blank">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1jTKvn0uHkCFZ_MGE5PhUWC6LKqvVfm0Gybc_g2XCMFQ/edit?tab=t.0</a>
<br>3e WIP Darker Paths: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/193nbdw5KPRwup6qkZQKTwOLDNh71spYx/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/file/d/193nbdw5KPRwup6qkZQKTwOLDNh71spYx/view?usp=sharing</a>




<br>2- Lycanthropy

<br>Links:

<br>Tuna's Lycanthropy: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ijAyyKlmNOg1HH6gZxvvrQ9OMkpmfdh2_gbdnKw_iQw/edit?tab=t.0" target="_blank">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ijAyyKlmNOg1HH6gZxvvrQ9OMkpmfdh2_gbdnKw_iQw/edit?tab=t.0</a>
<br>3e WIP Darker Paths: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/193nbdw5KPRwup6qkZQKTwOLDNh71spYx/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/file/d/193nbdw5KPRwup6qkZQKTwOLDNh71spYx/view?usp=sharing</a>




<br>3- Shadow Magic

<br>make any damage sources use Shadow type damage as a new damage type
<br>Links:

<br>Sigma's Writeup: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/191bVxLY5Q9cSIJYrrWXhVsAlihPhvNW9/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/file/d/191bVxLY5Q9cSIJYrrWXhVsAlihPhvNW9/view?usp=sharing</a>
<br>2e Arcane Arts: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B2KESbIjtwHsY015ck1ueVlTUFk&amp;resourcekey=0-Kj-uN36P1rUAtqWBWMkw8A&amp;usp=drive_fs" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B2KESbIjtwHsY015ck1ueVlTUFk&amp;resourcekey=0-Kj-uN36P1rUAtqWBWMkw8A&amp;usp=drive_fs</a>




<br>4- Blight Diseases (use tuna's diseases as a starting point)
<br>5- Crafting Rework (probably will be cut)
<br><br>
<br>1- Vampires
<br>2- Lycanthropes
<br>3- Dragons ✅ 2024-11-02
<br><br>
<br>1- Announced Prelease &amp; Open Playtest
<br>2- Formatting Pass
<br>3- Final Release
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-final-stretch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Final Stretch.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 19:10:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alpha]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Changes, fixes, and merges<br>
<br>1- Apply <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1gyHHhqV9DedAU7JLNcfiNWN45uyYVkFfCoEyOEK1-fU/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1gyHHhqV9DedAU7JLNcfiNWN45uyYVkFfCoEyOEK1-fU/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank">v2 errata</a> to the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-YYtjV-6McY2MYodl722M41jFiM2Qf9I/view?usp=sharing" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-YYtjV-6McY2MYodl722M41jFiM2Qf9I/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">v2 CrB</a><br>
<a data-href="1 - v2 Errata Merge Changelog" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/1-v2-errata-merge-changelog.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">1 - v2 Errata Merge Changelog</a><br>
<a data-href="UESRPG_3e_v4.a1.0_-_Core_Rulebook.pdf" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/assets/uesrpg_3e_v4.a1.0_-_core_rulebook.pdf" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a1.0_-_Core_Rulebook.pdf</a>

<br>Reviewed


<br>2- Apply relevant rules and errata from the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://drive.google.com/file/d/17MKMdUyQaDy3c3Wwbzf25V0_Z9d8m109/view?usp=sharing" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/17MKMdUyQaDy3c3Wwbzf25V0_Z9d8m109/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">v3 Black Book of Apocrypha</a><br>
<a data-href="Apocrypha Merge Canditates" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/apocrypha-merge-canditates.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Apocrypha Merge Canditates</a><br>
<a data-href="Black Book Merge Finalists" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/black-book-merge-finalists.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Black Book Merge Finalists</a><br>
<a data-href="2 - Black Book Merge Changelog" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/2-black-book-merge-changelog.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">2 - Black Book Merge Changelog</a><br>
<a data-href="UESRPG_3e_v4.a2.0_-_Core_Rulebook.pdf" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/assets/uesrpg_3e_v4.a2.0_-_core_rulebook.pdf" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a2.0_-_Core_Rulebook.pdf</a>

<br>Reviewed


<br>3- Carefully review all changes made to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xc5Xl5rOCtrSiDlbdPczZZTNkKBMVwCj/view?usp=sharing" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xc5Xl5rOCtrSiDlbdPczZZTNkKBMVwCj/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">v3</a> and take the best of them. Disregard the rest.<br>
<a data-href="v3 Merge Candidates" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/v3-merge-candidates.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">v3 Merge Candidates</a><br>
<a data-href="v3 Merge Finalists" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/v3-merge-finalists.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">v3 Merge Finalists</a><br>
<a data-href="3 - v3 Merge Changelog" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/3-v3-merge-changelog.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">3 - v3 Merge Changelog</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.0.zip" data-href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.0.zip" href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.0.zip" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.0.zip</a><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.1.zip" data-href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.1.zip" href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.1.zip" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.1.zip</a><br>
📬 <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1rpeKH_2u5tt1iD0dPymRn11OU5BkL4s-vehrK1_iXM8?authuser=jamesdabone%40gmail.com&amp;usp=drive_fs" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1rpeKH_2u5tt1iD0dPymRn11OU5BkL4s-vehrK1_iXM8?authuser=jamesdabone%40gmail.com&amp;usp=drive_fs" target="_blank">3e v4.a3.0-1 Feedback</a> (actioned)<br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.2.zip" data-href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.2.zip" href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.2.zip" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a3.2.zip</a><a data-href="v4.a3.2 Feedback" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/v4.a3.2-feedback.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">v4.a3.2 Feedback</a>

<br>Reviewed


<br>4- Apply all the Scrolls onto the Core Rulebook and collate them into one PDF. ✅ 2024-10-13<br>
<a data-href="Scroll Merge Considerations" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/scroll-merge-considerations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Scroll Merge Considerations</a><br>
<a data-href="Scroll Merge To-dos" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/scroll-merge-to-dos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Scroll Merge To-dos</a><br>
<a data-href="4 - Scroll Merge Changelog" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/changelogs/4-scroll-merge-changelog.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">4 - Scroll Merge Changelog</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.0_-_Bundled.zip" data-href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.0_-_Bundled.zip" href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.0_-_Bundled.zip" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.0_-_Bundled.zip</a><br>
<a data-href="3e v4.a4.0 Feedback" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/3e-v4.a4.0-feedback.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">3e v4.a4.0 Feedback</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.1_-_Bundled.zip" data-href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.1_-_Bundled.zip" href="/UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.1_-_Bundled.zip" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">UESRPG_3e_v4.a4.1_-_Bundled.zip</a><br>
<a data-href="3e v4.a4.1 Feedback" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/feedback/3e-v4.a4.1-feedback.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">3e v4.a4.1 Feedback</a>    

<br>Reviewed ✅ 2024-10-13


<br>5- Review the <a data-href="Ideas and Things to Look At" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/ideas-and-things-to-look-at.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ideas and Things to Look At</a> page, the “Proofreading” page, and the “To Dos” page and apply any items necessary from them. Review for balance considerations.<br>
<a data-href="Balance-Tweak Considerations" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/balance-tweak-considerations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Balance-Tweak Considerations</a><br>
<a data-href="Ideas and Things to Look At" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/ideas-and-things-to-look-at.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ideas and Things to Look At</a>    

<br>Reviewed


<br>6- Read through the whole book page by page and find everything wrong with it. Remove redundancies (like the Delay action), and appl-y proofreading. We should make a point to not find problems where there are none. ✅ 2024-10-13<br>
<a data-href="Alpha Playtest Targets" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/alpha-playtest-targets.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Alpha Playtest Targets</a>    

<br>Reviewed ✅ 2024-10-13


<br><br>Mindfully add new content, finalize design, and community review<br>
<br>1- Potentially add highly balanced and well designed content that fills in gaps. So far, the only items considered for this step are from Tuna’s Expanded Bestiary

<br>1a. Core Crafting Rework (incl. Reforging + Smithing Services)<br>
<a data-href="Content Suggestions" href="projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4/content-suggestions.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Content Suggestions</a>
<br>Reviewed


<br>2- Final design pass - review layout &amp; formatting; add, move, and change images as necessary.

<br>Reviewed


<br>3- Final Community play-testing and review

<br>Reviewed


<br>Misc - Black Book of Lost Knowledge

<br>Profession[Animal Handling] from Black Book
<br>Cannibalism from Black Book


<br><br><br><br>
<br>To Merge:

<br>Standing Stones (From PhB)


]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/the-road-to-v4.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/The Road to v4.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Flavor blurb for the Drain [Characteristic] spell
<br>Flavor blurb for the Cure Disease (Self) spell
<br>Flavor blurb for the Curing Touch spell
<br>Flavor blurb for Monster Hunter talent
<br>Add an “About v4” message after Seht’s intro explaining our specific changes, additions, approach, and overall philosophy. (To be done when the project is in the final stages of pre-release) 
<br><br>
<br>Figure out what the hell is going on with the “Spell Scrolls” Section’s formatting
<br><br>
<br>Modify the "Cast Magic" secondary action to read "Only Reaction spells" rather than "non-attack only”

<br>As part of this, review and discuss which spells we want to be cast as a reaction. Currently this would only be Slowfall and Ward, based on where the reaction keyword currently sits.


<br>Review Chain Lightning (check v3 rules)
<br>Look at the struck-out Grandmaster Spellcasting section of the errata.
<br>Rather than using all stamina giving a point of fatigue, just consider used stamina at 0. I.e. the smart way
<br>Specify that a ranged weapon must be reloaded before it can be shot.

The Reload Action must always be used before attacking with a ranged weapon, even when firing for the first time in combat.


<br>Change the coup de grace rules to read:

The character can make a fatal blow against a helpless target, who is automatically killed as a result. Whether a target is helpless is largely up to the GM, but generally will be unconscious, both restrained and prone, or otherwise incapable of defending themselves. A Coup de Grace can only be attempted if the character is wielding a melee weapon and are in melee range, or wielding a ranged weapon with at least 1 remaining ammunition and are within 1m.<br>
If the target of a Coup de Grace attack is being grappled, they can use the Resist Secondary Action as a reaction to break free before the Coup de Grace resolves. This can be done as a Free Action if the attacker is the character grappling the target.  


<br>To calculate specific DoS values on a crit (only where necessary), you determine your DoS as if you had rolled your maximum successful roll and add your Luck Bonus
<br>Define AoE forms in a grid section
<br>Consider requiring declaring your advantage at time of attack
]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/to-dos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/To Dos.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 05:33:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Version Repository]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Find all prerelease versions, including the latest, here -&gt; <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1G1Xzxuum1mxZu1WezOJjLk4KVfZ7zOwO" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1G1Xzxuum1mxZu1WezOJjLk4KVfZ7zOwO" target="_blank">Prerelease Versions</a><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/uesrpg-3e-v4.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/UESRPG 3e v4.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 06:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[v4.0 Release To-Do List]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Rule Fixes

<br>Review Latch On
<br>Review Endurance + Resistance/Weakness interaction
<br>Hammerblow: rather than saying "or make an all-out attack" it should say "or, if the attack was an all out attack, they can force..."
<br>Fix the lorem ipsum in IoT
<br>determine a diseased trait for lycanthropes, double check that vampires have the trait. Current thought for lycans is -20
<br>Let's make the flyer speed gained from mutate Speed, rather than speed x 2. That's a bit much.
<br>Summon shadow horror has weapon text in the first paragraph.

<br>Could also use some clarity re: unleashing the shadow horror and the following text making it seem like it is bound anyway


<br>With the Vampire lord EA, I think we mean Immune to Normal Weapons
<br>White-Gold Artificer entry cost should not include burning luck, it's inconsistent with the others.
<br>Sload Characteristics are incorrect and have been copy+pasted from maormer
<br>Shield spell effects should say that any damage the target takes, not the caster.
<br>Finish out the special advantages examples in the Combat Style section
<br>Make the Strong Jaws rule more explicit in the intent behind "automatically starts a grapple"

<br>RC
<br>IoT


<br>Aundae + Cyrodilic stat matrices need to be swapped?
<br>Rules for runed on pg 180 should be reflected on page 188
<br>Count Flufficus: "Okay the math is not mathing on dragonscale armors

<br>It's the only material where body is NOT 2x limb price
<br>the suit price just does not match the prices next to it<br>
Current pricing (for partial, but both are screwed up): 3500 limb / 5000 body (18000) - with 5 limbs and 1 body, that should be 22500 instead"


<br>Increase silver weapon material EL to 550?
<br>In Conjure Armor Spell Effect, change

<br>"Adding more than 1 instance of this effect causes the cost of all instances of this effect after the first to be 2 x SL, but only if used in the self form."
<br>to: "Adding more than 1 instance of this effect causes the cost of each instance of this effect after the first to be 5 x SL, but only if used in the self form."


<br>Fix Strong jaws wording for "counter attacks with fang attacks" (should say "against" not "with) on the senche/pahmar. Check other instances of strong jaws as well.
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1353155440036282368" target="_blank">https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1353155440036282368</a>
<br>In the upkeep spell attribute - "cannot be upkept the spell"
<br>BayBerry: Looking over Storm Call, Word 2 contains a misspelling of Becomes. "Duration bcomes 4 rounds."
<br>Add Clarification: In determining wound effects, highest damage type takes precedence. Also, is knock-on effect damage (enchantment damage and the like) added to the base damage against WT or is it resolved individually?
<br>remove "Clothing" from the Clothing &amp; Gear table in chapter 7, as that table doesn't actually contain clothing.
<br>Shadow Key
<br>Arcane Defender requires arcane defender (talent)
<br>Flow of magicka should probably specify that the talent does not apply to spells that do not have spell levels
<br>Look at attack/action types for shadow magic
<br>explain how to combine movement speeds
<br>Pankratosword typo?
<br>Give conjure armor and weapon listed durations of 1 round Bold it
<br>make clearer in the special NPC rules that the only restriction for NPC profiles is the Heroic Action
<br>People tend to miss the base vampirism/lycanthropy rules. Some linked references and/or a reorg to make it clearer is probably in order.
<br>Pronouns
<br>Refine specializations for spell school skill specializations - particularly illusion
<br>Goblin Battleaxe should be 2m reach
<br>Warchief Sledge should be 2H
<br>Instance of "Creation Points" under "Spend XP" heading (pg 50)
<br>Remove "or parried" from beast of steel
<br>Increase Archmage Int by +10 to 60
<br>Dwemer Sphere Mace should be 2m. Spear 2-3m?
<br>Remove Stubborn from dragon, they're immune
<br>Match rules for Deafened to Blinded
<br>Stablize should remove passive wound effects
<br>limit controlled anger
<br>Lycanthropy note: no low XP 
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20250505104123.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20250505104123.png">
<br>Lycanthropy Beast Form AP cost
<br>Pronouns (IoT)
<br>Pronouns (TA)
<br>Shadow Magic effects table still references IoT for Sliver (and shadow horror?
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1372234061690704004" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1372234061690704004" target="_blank">Redundancy?</a>
<br>Instances of "Congruence Rating" instead of "Convergence Rating"
<br>Goblin 2H weapons should have a 2m reach
<br>Spell Attribute changes need to be propagated to IoT
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20250528014845.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20250528014845.png">
<br>Put the bit about spell effects not stacking with themselves into chapter 6
<br>Magic Shield Effect: [Spell Strength] should be SL
<br>Ebony/Stalhrim order in armor tables isn't consistent?
<br>~~Enchanting Fees table should be copied to chapter 6 enchanting``
<br>add necromancy to the optional schools that races can choose as part of character creation?
<br>Feeding should specify that creature cannot be undead
<br>Make the horror result for Mind Break apply until they snap out of it
<br>Add a paragraph talking about having close AND long range options available
<br>movement through enemies - how does it work? Or is this a 4e thing? If it is, maybe just a little advice blurb on options?
<br>"a Reachman may choose to being with the Survival skill"
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20250604101437.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20250604101437.png">
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1379997401036754994" target="_blank">https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1379997401036754994</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1380234583181758475" target="_blank">https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1380234583181758475</a>
<br>Change flavor text of either "Sneak Attack" or "Assassinate"

<br>suggested text from herma: "So many little cracks in armor you can exploit, its just about knowing how to get it in there." 


<br>page 79: armored agility talent - the formula is not clear due to the "rank - 1". Should spell out "minus one" instead
<br>reword the step aside talent? suggested reword: "Successful Evade reactions against attacks of opportunity are free. If the character fails one they must pay 1 AP for it."
<br>inconsistency between Taskmaster and Master of the Hordes?

<br><img alt="Pasted image 20250612153657.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20250612153657.png">


<br>change "caster" to "target" in all shield spells
<br>shield spell effects in the appendix hard code the 50m target range
<br>"Atheltics" typo, page 123 (bestial instinct)
<br>page 122, Perception isn't capitalized under the char bonuses
<br>"without with" in the Diseased trait on page 91
<br>IoT 178 (Dunmer Ancestral Tomb) Damaged (1) piece of partial chitin destroys itself
<br>Copy+paste error between "The Seven Hundred and Fifty Offensive Positions" and "The Eighteen Hundred Offensive Positions"
<br>Left off at <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1384674615737188443" target="_blank">https://discord.com/channels/247154132807450634/998434153303388270/1384674615737188443</a>
<br>Unstoppable might - specify that you cannot dual-wield with a two-handed weapon


<br>v4 Intro section
<br>credits

<br>don't forget credits from supplements
<br>fix sigma's credit ("sigmaphrenic")
<br>Move Dagoth to the designers column


<br>Formatting + Images

<br>art credits


<br>Get someone to update the Compendium/File Repository
<br>Foundry To-dos

<br>Add to the resistances box:

<br>Normal Weapons
<br>Immunities?
<br>Issue with the Elbert Gomberville sheet




]]></description><link>projects/uesrpg/uesrpg-3e-v4/v4.0-release-to-do-list.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/UESRPG/UESRPG 3e v4/v4.0 Release To-Do List.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 22:26:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20250505104123.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20250505104123.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>